<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>swy7</title>
  
  
  <link href="https://swy7.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://swy7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2021-05-11T20:57:32.311Z</updated>
  <id>https://swy7.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>swy7</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>20210512-01 今日翻</title>
    <link href="https://swy7.github.io/2021/05/12/%E7%BF%BB/20210512-01/"/>
    <id>https://swy7.github.io/2021/05/12/%E7%BF%BB/20210512-01/</id>
    <published>2021-05-12T00:00:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-11T20:57:32.311Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<!-- MarkdownTOC --><ul><li><a href="#the-digital-currencies-that-matter">The digital currencies that matter</a></li><li><a href="#permitless-carry-gun-laws-are-misguided-and-should-be-scrapped">Permitless-carry gun laws are misguided and should be scrapped</a></li><li><a href="#warren-buffett-should-step-aside-for-his-chosen-successor">Warren Buffett should step aside for his chosen successor</a></li><li><a href="#somaliland-deserves-international-recognition">Somaliland deserves international recognition</a></li><li><a href="#how-to-make-long-term-climate-pledges-add-up">How to make long-term climate pledges add up</a></li></ul><!-- /MarkdownTOC --><span id="more"></span><p><a id="the-digital-currencies-that-matter"></a></p><h1 id="The-digital-currencies-that-matter"><a href="#The-digital-currencies-that-matter" class="headerlink" title="The digital currencies that matter"></a>The digital currencies that matter</h1><p>Government-run virtual currencies are coming. They are a giant risk that is worth taking<br>来源：2021-05-08 TheEconomist UKedition</p><p>Technological change is upending finance. Bitcoin has gone from being an obsession of <strong>anarchists</strong> to a $1trn asset class that many fund managers insist belongs in any balanced portfolio. Swarms of digital day­-traders have become a force on Wall Street. PayPal has 392m users, a sign that America is catching up with China’s digital­ payments giants. Yet, as our special report explains, the least noticed disruption on the frontier between technology and finance may end up as the most revolutionary: the creation of government digital currencies, which typically aim to let people <strong>deposit</strong> funds directly with a central bank, bypassing conventional lenders.</p><p>These “govcoins” are a new <strong>incarnation</strong> of money. They promise to make finance work better but also to shift power from individuals to the state, alter geopolitics and change how capital is allocated. They are to be treated with optimism, and humility.</p><p>A decade or so ago, amid the <strong>wreckage</strong> of Lehman Brothers,Paul Volcker, a former head of the Federal Reserve, <strong>grumbled</strong> that banking’s last useful innovation was the ATM. Since the crisis, the industry has raised its game. Banks have modernised their creaking it systems. Entrepreneurs have built an experimental world of “decentralised finance”, of which bitcoin is the most famous part and which contains a riot of tokens, databases and <strong>conduits</strong> that interact to varying degrees with traditional finance. Meanwhile, financial “platform” firms now have over 3bn customers who use e-­wallets and payments apps. Alongside PayPal are other specialists such as Ant Group, Grab and Mercado Pago, established firms such as Visa, and Silicon Valley <strong>wannabes</strong> such as Facebook.</p><p>Government or central­-bank digital currencies are the next step but they come with a twist, because they would centralise power in the state rather than spread it through networks or give it to private monopolies. The idea behind them is simple. Instead of holding an account with a retail bank, you would do so direct with a central bank through an interface <strong>resembling</strong> apps such as Alipay or Venmo. Rather than writing cheques or paying online with a card, you could use the central bank’s cheap <strong>plumbing.</strong> And your money would be guaranteed by the full faith of the state, not a fallible bank. Want to buy a pizza or help a broke <strong>sibling</strong>? No need to deal with Citigroup’s call centre or pay Mastercard’s fees: the Bank of England and the Fed are at your service.</p><p>This <strong>metamorphosis</strong> of central banks from the <strong>aristocrats</strong> of finance to its labourers sounds far­fetched, but it is under way. Over 50 monetary authorities, representing the bulk of global GDP, are exploring digital currencies. The Bahamas has issued digital money. China has rolled out its e-­yuan <strong>pilot</strong> to over 500,000 people (see Finance section). The EU wants a virtual euro by 2025, Britain has launched a task­force, and America, the world’s financial <strong>hegemon</strong>, is building a <strong>hypothetical</strong> e-­dollar.</p><p>One motivation for governments and central banks is a fear of losing control. Today central banks harness the banking system to amplify monetary policy. If payments, deposits and loans migrate from banks into privately run digital <strong>realms</strong>, central banks will struggle to manage the economic cycle and inject funds into the system during a crisis. Unsupervised private networks could become a Wild West of fraud and privacy abuses.</p><p>The other motivation is the promise of a better financial system. Ideally money provides a reliable store of value, a stable unit of account and an efficient means of payment. Today’s money gets mixed marks. Uninsured depositors can suffer if banks fail, bitcoin is not widely accepted and credit cards are expensive. Government e-­currencies would score highly, since they are state­-guaranteed and use a cheap, central payments hub. </p><p>As a result, govcoins could cut the operating expenses of the global financial industry, which amount to over $350 a year for every person on Earth. That could make finance accessible for the 1.7bn people who lack bank accounts. Government digital currencies could also expand governments’ toolkits by letting them make instant payments to citizens and cut interest rates below zero. For ordinary users, the appeal of a free, safe, instant, universal means of payment is obvious.</p><p>It is this appeal, though, that creates dangers. Unconstrained, govcoins could fast become a dominant force in finance, particularly if network effects made it hard for people to opt out. They could <strong>destabilise</strong> banks, because if most people and firms <strong>stashed</strong> their cash at the central banks, lenders would have to find other sources of funding with which to back their loans.</p><p>If retail banks were sucked dry of funding, someone else would have to do the lending that fuels business creation. This raises the <strong>queasy</strong> prospect of bureaucrats influencing credit allocation. In a crisis, a digital <strong>stampede</strong> of savers to the central bank could cause bank runs.</p><p>Once <strong>ascendant</strong>, govcoins could become <strong>panopticons</strong> for the state to control citizens: think of instant e-­fines for bad behaviour. They could alter geopolitics, too, by providing a conduit for cross­-border payments and alternatives to the dollar, the world’s reserve currency and a <strong>linchpin</strong> of American influence. The <strong>greenback’s</strong> reign is based partly on America’s open capital markets and property rights, which China cannot rival. But it also relies on old payments systems, <strong>invoicing</strong> conventions and inertia— making it ripe for disruption. Small countries fear that, instead of using local money, people might switch to foreign e­-currencies, causing chaos at home.</p><p>New money, new problems</p><p>Such a vast <strong>spectrum</strong> of opportunities and dangers is <strong>daunting</strong>. It is revealing that China’s autocrats, who value control above all else, are limiting the size of the e-­yuan and <strong>clamping</strong> down on private platforms such as Ant. Open societies should also proceed cautiously by, say, capping digital­-currency accounts. </p><p>Governments and financial firms need to prepare for a long-term shift in how money works, as momentous as the leap to metallic coins or payment cards. That means <strong>beefing up</strong> privacy laws, reforming how central banks are run and preparing retail banks for a more <strong>peripheral</strong> role. State digital currencies are the next great experiment in finance, and they promise to be a lot more <strong>consequential</strong> than the humble ATM.</p><p><a id="permitless-carry-gun-laws-are-misguided-and-should-be-scrapped"></a></p><h1 id="Permitless-carry-gun-laws-are-misguided-and-should-be-scrapped"><a href="#Permitless-carry-gun-laws-are-misguided-and-should-be-scrapped" class="headerlink" title="Permitless-carry gun laws are misguided and should be scrapped"></a>Permitless-carry gun laws are misguided and should be scrapped</h1><p>More states are falling for an extremist take on the Second Amendment<br>来源：2021-05-08 TheEconomist UKedition</p><p>Every american state requires you to have a licence to drive a car, hunt or become a barber. Yet by the end of this year at least 20 states will allow you to carry a handgun in public without a permit. So far in 2021 five have already passed “permitless carry” laws, and five more, including Texas and Louisiana, are considering them. If these became law, around a third of Americans would live in states where it was legal to carry guns around without any need for a licence or training.</p><p>Anyone who considers the 181 mass shootings that have taken place in America since January, or the recent spike in violent crime, would be forgiven for wondering why some states want fewer restrictions on guns, rather than more. The pro-gun lobby, including the National Rifle Association (NRA), argues that having more armed civilians will help boost public safety, making it more likely that “good guys” with guns can <strong>intercept</strong> “bad guys” with guns. With the help of Republican state legislators, they are advancing an interpretation of the Second Amendment which imagines that America’s founders intended no restrictions on guns or gun ownership whatsoever. Backers of permitless carry call it “constitutional carry” to make it seem legitimate and to appear to give it a <strong>pedigree</strong>.</p><p>Do not be fooled. Permitless carry is a radical departure from tradition and should be opposed. One reason is that the gains to gun owners are <strong>trivial</strong>. In most of the states considering permitless carry, it is already possible to be armed with a handgun concealed in public if you have a licence.</p><p>Obtaining a licence is hardly <strong>onerous</strong>, given what guns are capable of. Applicants are often required to do training and to pass a shooting test. Searches help screen out people who should not be trusted with a gun, such as those who have committed violent crimes or who have a history of mental illness.</p><p>Doing away with these conditions is not in the public interest. Just as communities are made safer by drivers being required to pass tests before they can legally operate a car, so it makes sense for people to learn how to use a <strong>lethal</strong> weapon and impose restrictions on when, where and how they can carry guns around. In most places where permitless carry is being considered, police forces have spoken out against it, because it would make their jobs harder and more dangerous.</p><p>The NRA has spent the past 20 years successfully loosening gun laws. The latest wave of <strong>deregulation</strong> was “<strong>shall issue</strong>” requirements for gun licences, giving officials less discretion about when to withhold them. A study of these laws by researchers at Stanford found that they resulted in a 13-15% increase in violent crime in the decade after they came into force. By the same logic, permitless carry would also probably cost lives.</p><p>Permitless carry is also a misreading of history. Romanticising America as a country that intended no restrictions on guns is incorrect. In the 19th century, most Southern states had stricter gun laws than they do today. Even in Wild West settlements like Tombstone, Arizona, newcomers had to leave their guns on the <strong>outskirts</strong> of town or register them with the sheriff. A century ago the NRA backed permitting laws as a way to promote responsible gun ownership and helped draft the country’s first federal gun-control laws in the 1930s. By arguing for permitless carry, it is not faithfully adhering to the past but drifting further towards an extreme.</p><p>America is the world leader in gun-ownership, with about six times the rate of France and Germany, and more than double <strong>war-torn</strong> Yemen, which comes second. The rate of violent gun-deaths is perhaps 100 times higher than in Britain. Most of America’s peers impose stricter laws—even gun-friendly Switzerland and Canada. Because of the near-permanent deadlock in Congress, the federal government will not pass sensible gun reforms. It is up to the states to take responsibility for the welfare of their citizens. Permitless carry will only do them harm. </p><p><a id="warren-buffett-should-step-aside-for-his-chosen-successor"></a></p><h1 id="Warren-Buffett-should-step-aside-for-his-chosen-successor"><a href="#Warren-Buffett-should-step-aside-for-his-chosen-successor" class="headerlink" title="Warren Buffett should step aside for his chosen successor"></a>Warren Buffett should step aside for his chosen successor</h1><p>Berkshire Hathaway needs a leader who will take a fresh look at performance and governance<br>来源：2021-05-08 TheEconomist UKedition</p><p>At 90, warren buffett continues to lead Berkshire Hathaway, wearing the three hats of chief executive, chairman and chief investment officer. For years, the question of whom the feted investor would anoint as his successor to run the giant conglomerate has been the subject of boardroom gossip. The world now knows the answer, though only because of a slip of the tongue by Mr Buffett’s 97-year-old right-hand man, Charlie Munger, at the annual shareholders’ meeting on May 1st. That forced Mr Buffett to confirm that his heir apparent as chief executive is Greg Abel, 58, a trusted lieutenant who runs Berkshire’s non-insurance businesses.</p><p>The cack-handed way in which the succession plan became public fits a bigger pattern. Berkshire is a huge public company, with a stockmarket value of $645bn and an army of devoted retail investors. It is, though, structured and run in much the way it was when Mr Buffett took it over in the 1960s. He has never hidden his reluctance to retire. He once joked that he’ll step down five years after he dies. However, Berkshire needs to make changes if it is to keep up with the times—and that includes having a new person at the top.</p><p>That is not to denigrate Mr Buffett or his achievements. In his 56 years in charge, Berkshire’s total returns have been double those of the s&amp;p 500 index. He can claim to be the greatest value-investor who ever lived. He has instilled an admirable trust-based culture at Berkshire. The dozens of fawning books he has inspired constitute their own genre of business publishing.</p><p>However, cracks have started to appear. One is Berkshire’s financial performance, which has been mediocre over the past decade. Mr Buffett has made some costly mistakes, such as bad bets on airlines and Kraft Heinz, a consumer-goods giant. He has admitted to overpaying for acquisitions, including a big metal-parts-maker that later wrote off $11bn. Were it not for a valuable stake in Apple, the bottom line would have looked limper still. Suspicion is growing that Mr Buffett has lost his magic touch in allocating capital, perhaps because, like other star fund managers, he is too big to outperform the market by much.</p><p>Berkshire’s governance needs rethinking, too. For all the autonomy its divisions enjoy, Mr Buffett still has to sign off on the big decisions. He has special shares with greatly enhanced voting power. The board is stacked with Friends of Warren; five of its 14 members are 89 or over. Berkshire’s failure to write or disclose its policies on investor priorities such as climate risk and diversity irks some shareholders, including big institutions like BlackRock. When investors called Buffett-style governance “unique” they used to mean it as a compliment. No longer.</p><p>The company’s lousy disclosure looks out of step with the times, too. Berkshire offers little beyond mandatory filings and the occasional press release. It does not hold analyst meetings or investor days; it does not even have a functioning investor-relations department. The closest thing to outside scrutiny it tolerates is the three hours of friendly shareholders’ questions, teed up by a genial reporter from CNBC, at the annual conclave.</p><p>The company needs to start dealing with these deficiencies now, or face the increased risk of a drama—such as an attempt by activist investors to break up Berkshire, or a regulatory rumble—when Mr Buffett does eventually leave. There is no need to stoop to the box-ticking corporate conformity that he so loathes, an aversion reflected in his public criticism of the metrics and questionnaires wielded by ESG campaigners.</p><p>Get the job done, Warren<br>New blood and greater openness would be a good start. Naming a successor is a first step. The next should be to replenish the board with outside appointments. Investors must get the information they need to make informed decisions, including analysis of where the firm is creating value, and the tax and other synergies that justify keeping the conglomerate intact.</p><p>The biggest question of all is when Mr Buffett should go. He may want to die at his desk, but the longer he stays, the more he risks becoming a liability. He said at this year’s AGM that bad leaders are the biggest risk companies face. Good leaders who stay too long are not far behind. Mr Buffett has had a wonderful run. But now that the succession is out in the open, it is time to move aside and let Mr Abel fix what isn’t working. </p><p><a id="somaliland-deserves-international-recognition"></a></p><h1 id="Somaliland-deserves-international-recognition"><a href="#Somaliland-deserves-international-recognition" class="headerlink" title="Somaliland deserves international recognition"></a>Somaliland deserves international recognition</h1><p>It is far more functional than Somalia, the state to which it notionally belongs<br>来源：2021-05-08 TheEconomist UKedition</p><p>Somaliland’s first stab at independence lasted less than a week. Pipers of the Royal Highland Fusiliers were ordered to play the new state’s national anthem at a ceremony in Hargeisa, the capital, marking the end of British colonial rule in June 1960. On discovering that it did not have one, the bandmaster cobbled together a medley of local folk tunes, and conducted it with brio. A day later, however, Somaliland’s parliament passed an act of union with Somalia, a former Italian colony to its south, and Somaliland officially was no more.</p><p>It was a catastrophic mistake. Within a decade the new Somali Republic had collapsed. Its president was assassinated by his bodyguards. A Marxist junta seized power, led by Siad Barre, a general-turned-dictator. He abolished democracy and wrecked the economy by nationalising nearly everything except camel herds. He also launched a disastrous war against Ethiopia. When the northerners rebelled, he bombed Hargeisa, killing thousands of civilians. As Somalia disintegrated into clan warfare, Barre refused to negotiate, saying: “When I leave Somalia, I will leave behind buildings but no people.” He was not far off the mark. By the time he fled, in 1991, the country had plunged into chaos from which it has yet to emerge.</p><p>Somaliland unsurprisingly wanted out. Its elders agreed to break away from the rest of Somalia in 1991 at a “Grand Shir”, or gathering of clans, held in a small town in the desert. Since then, Somaliland has become a functioning state in all but name, with 4.5m people on an area bigger than Florida. It has been largely peaceful. It controls its borders and its territory, unlike Somalia’s government, which controls little more than its capital city, and that only thanks to 20,000 foreign peacekeepers. Whereas Somalia has not held a direct election since the 1960s, Somaliland periodically votes for its president and lawmakers, even if polls are marred by attacks on the press and take place less often than they should.</p><p>Yet in the eyes of the world Somaliland remains part of Somalia. For longer than most of its people have been alive, its pleas for recognition as an independent state have been ignored. The world defers on this to the African Union, the continental arbiter. It, in turn, argues that Somaliland can win independence only with the consent of Somalia, which says no.</p><p>The obvious objection to recognising Somaliland is that redrawing maps is perilous. This is especially so in Africa, where borders thoughtlessly imposed in colonial times separate countless clans and ethnic groups from their kin. Untangling this mess would be so tricky that a consensus long ago emerged: leave the map as it is.</p><p>Once you start moving borders or creating new states for this or that group, others will demand their own homelands, too, and blood will surely flow. Witness Africa’s two newest breakaway countries, Eritrea and South Sudan, which have become a gulag state and a war zone. Were Somaliland to win independence, people in other bits of Somalia might try to break away, too, as would ethnic groups in Ethiopia, the regional power.</p><p>For all these reasons, Somaliland’s case will not prevail soon. Yet it deserves a hearing. It is not seeking to redraw borders from scratch, but to revert to old ones. Some 97% of its people supported independence in a referendum in 2001. Scottish and Catalan nationalists can only dream of such unanimity. Most Somalilanders have known nothing but self-rule and would never consent to reintegrate with their bloody, anarchic suzerain.</p><p>Meanwhile, denying them recognition imposes severe human costs. Somalilanders cannot travel freely, since few countries accept Somaliland passports. They are poorer than they should be, since their government does not have the status to make trade deals or borrow directly from the World Bank or the IMF. Statehood would help fix some of these problems.</p><p>Ideally, Somaliland’s separation should be achieved with the agreement of Somalia. For the time being this seems far-fetched. But Somalia should be encouraged to grant a divorce with promises of aid and debt relief from the donors who already bankroll its government and pay for the peacekeepers who prop it up. If, like an abusive spouse, Somalia refuses to let go, Somaliland should not be held hostage. Other countries should recognise it, and international organisations should treat it like a state.</p><p>Were Somaliland to win formal independence again, its road ahead would be hard. But the odds of flourishing would be much better this time. It now has not only a breezy national anthem but also a 30-year record of reasonably successful self-rule. To recognise that is to recognise reality.</p><p><a id="how-to-make-long-term-climate-pledges-add-up"></a></p><h1 id="How-to-make-long-term-climate-pledges-add-up"><a href="#How-to-make-long-term-climate-pledges-add-up" class="headerlink" title="How to make long-term climate pledges add up"></a>How to make long-term climate pledges add up</h1><p>A German court shines a light on the murk of emissions targets<br>来源：2021-05-08 TheEconomist UKedition</p><p>The climate law that the German government passed in 2019 required a cut in greenhouse-gas emissions of 55%, from levels in 1990, by 2030. Climate activists saw this as insufficient. They took the government to court on the basis that, by not treating climate action seriously enough, it was denying basic rights to citizens of the future.</p><p>The court has now rejected the more ambitious aspects of that complaint. But its ruling at the end of last month did nevertheless find fault with the law. Although the target for 2030 was not in itself deemed to be inadequate, the court decided that it does pose a problem in the context of the law’s longer-term aspiration to “net zero” emissions in 2050. The combination of the two pledges seemed to allow governments to impose a greater share of the total burden of decarbonisation on the future. The burden is all the heavier when you consider that the low-hanging apples are usually the first to be picked.</p><p>For justice to be done, the court ruled, there must be intermediate targets. It asked for details of them by the end of 2022. The immediate response, across all parties, was to talk of increasing ambition both in the near term and the longer term: a 65% cut by 2030, net zero by 2045.</p><p>To achieve that would presumably require a quick end to the internal-combustion engine, long a wellspring of national engineering pride—and exports. Germany’s coal phase-out would have to accelerate. And massive infrastructure development would be needed to support the Achilles heel of the country’s renewable-energy infrastructure: its vulnerability to kalte Dunkelflaute, the cold, dark doldrums in which sun and wind abandon the land but the hearth must stay warm.</p><p>Germans—rich, green and technically adept—may find ways to accomplish all this. Or they may not. Over the past decade they have been quite happy to close down their fleet of emissions-sparing nuclear power plants. It would be odd if a long-standing aversion to nuclear power should prove to be the only political objective the country turns out to put ahead of its commitment to climate action.</p><p>However, the court’s reservation also applies well beyond Germany. A near-term goal, expressed as a reduction in emissions with respect to some historical baseline, and a longer-term goal expressed as a date at which they intend to reach net-zero emissions, is increasingly the norm for countries seeking to take the climate seriously. These net-zero goals do not commit a country to a specific level of emissions, but to developing “negative emissions” on a scale that will cover whatever it does end up emitting. This makes what is actually being called for in terms of reduction between 2030 and 2050, or in some cases 2060, impossible to assess. It thus makes the fairness of requiring that effort from future generations impossible to judge.</p><p>This is a gateway to endless fudge. Notional negative emissions are based on forestry, new agricultural practices, rewilding and various technologies that suck carbon from the atmosphere and store it underground. Because they can be invoked to make up any shortfall in emission cuts, some activists are sceptical of including them in targets.</p><p>Blanket doubt is unreasonable. Net-zero thinking makes geophysical and economic sense. Some emissions will surely prove so hard to abate that it will be cheaper to develop technologies to suck an equivalent amount of warming potential out of the air. And if that balance can be achieved globally, the concentration of greenhouse gases in the atmosphere will stabilise and the warming stop. That is why the Paris agreement of 2015 treats net-zero as a second-half-of-the-century goal.</p><p>But net-zero thinking is troublesome, even so. It allows the ultimate scope of emission cuts to remain undefined and sweeps all the uncertainties under a carpet of techno-optimism. To keep governments honest, voters and activists around the world need to echo the German court’s order.</p><p>They should insist that governments show how they will create negative emissions in just and robust ways—so, no afforestation on poor people’s land simply because you can and no double counting or leaky carbon reservoirs. And they must insist on good-faith estimates of the negative emissions governments are banking on. That way they can tell if they are feasible and see what cuts will be needed in five, ten or 15 years’ time.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;!-- MarkdownTOC --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-digital-currencies-that-matter&quot;&gt;The digital currencies that matter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#permitless-carry-gun-laws-are-misguided-and-should-be-scrapped&quot;&gt;Permitless-carry gun laws are misguided and should be scrapped&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#warren-buffett-should-step-aside-for-his-chosen-successor&quot;&gt;Warren Buffett should step aside for his chosen successor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#somaliland-deserves-international-recognition&quot;&gt;Somaliland deserves international recognition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#how-to-make-long-term-climate-pledges-add-up&quot;&gt;How to make long-term climate pledges add up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- /MarkdownTOC --&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
    <category term="2021" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/2021/"/>
    
    <category term="翻" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%BF%BB/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>20210511-02 今日翻</title>
    <link href="https://swy7.github.io/2021/05/11/%E7%BF%BB/20210511-02/"/>
    <id>https://swy7.github.io/2021/05/11/%E7%BF%BB/20210511-02/</id>
    <published>2021-05-11T04:00:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-10T19:36:56.637Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<!-- MarkdownTOC --><ul><li><a href="#what-we-find-when-we-get-lost-in-proust">What We Find When We Get Lost in Proust</a></li><li><a href="#how-long-can-we-live">How Long Can We Live?</a></li><li><a href="#has-an-old-soviet-mystery-at-last-been-solved">Has an Old Soviet Mystery at Last Been Solved?</a></li></ul><!-- /MarkdownTOC --><span id="more"></span><p><a id="what-we-find-when-we-get-lost-in-proust"></a></p><h1 id="What-We-Find-When-We-Get-Lost-in-Proust"><a href="#What-We-Find-When-We-Get-Lost-in-Proust" class="headerlink" title="What We Find When We Get Lost in Proust"></a>What We Find When We Get Lost in Proust</h1><p>来源: <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2021/05/10/what-we-find-when-we-get-lost-in-proust?utm_social-type=owned&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;mbid=social_twitter&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_brand=tny">https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2021/05/10/what-we-find-when-we-get-lost-in-proust?utm_social-type=owned&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;mbid=social_twitter&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_brand=tny</a></p><p>When one finds the bottom of a barrel being energetically scraped, it is proof, at least, that whatever was once floating on the top must have been very delicious indeed. And so, having reached the very bottom of the barrel marked “Marcel Proust,” the scraping continues, even unto the splintered wood. The usual run of a famous author’s remains is more or less set: first the (disillusioning) biography, then the (surprisingly mundane, money-mad) letters, and finally the (painfully naked) diaries, in which erotic obsessions that seem curious and fresh in literary prose look mechanically obsessive in daily record, as with Kenneth Tynan and John Cheever. What comes after is mostly academic commentary.</p><p>But with the biography, the letters, and the journals long in the rearview mirror, the popular secondary works on Proust continue to appear in manic numbers. Anything Proustian, it seems, gets published now. Not long ago, we were given a book made up solely of his desperately polite, querulous letters to his upstairs neighbors in one of his last apartment buildings, on the Boulevard Haussmann, complaining about the noise—and sounding exactly like a classic S. J. Perelman casual. In the past fifteen years or so, certainly since the dawn of the new century, the huge success of Alain de Botton’s “How Proust Can Change Your Life” has been followed by a candid book on Proust’s sex life (by his American biographer, William C. Carter); the memoirs of his Swedish valet (also edited by Carter); a study, by the Auden biographer Richard Davenport-Hines, of Proust’s final days, at the Ritz and the Majestic; Benjamin Taylor’s study of Proust’s life as a distinctly Jewish one; the first fully annotated versions of “Swann’s Way” (both by Carter and by Lydia Davis); Clive James’s long verse commentary “Gate of Lilacs”; and a graphic-novel version of “Swann’s Way,” not to mention an album by the talented Russian-French sisters called the Milstein Duo, “The Vinteuil Sonata,” devoted to the real-life candidates for the musical phrase that entangled Swann’s heart and doomed his life. That’s doubtless not even half the harvest. The books are often illustrated with the intensity of religious tracts. In one, we are given a detailed diagram of the apartment with the cork-lined room where Proust spent his reclusive late years. (The room’s original interior can be found at the Musée Carnavalet, the museum of the history of Paris.) “Lost” works appear. Just last month, Gallimard, in Paris, published “Les Soixante-quinze Feuillets,” an early, more directly autobiographical overture, long thought to have vanished, of themes that he would later develop in depth. And now, in English, arrives a fearsomely slender book, “The Mysterious Correspondent,” nine stories, mostly fragmentary, mostly unpublished, that have only recently been rediscovered, appearing as something between juvenilia and a sketchbook.</p><p>All this work attests to the reputation of the most often attempted, most rarely summited, of all mountainous modern books, Proust’s multivolume “À la Recherche du Temps Perdu,” which, first Englished as “Remembrance of Things Past,” is now routinely more severely Frenchified as “In Search of Lost Time.” (That there are passionate debates about the varying merits of his translators and of these titles is part of the general Proustian effect.) Why some writers get this kind of attention—rooted in encompassing appetite rather than in mere admiration—and some do not is hard to know and interesting to contemplate. Chekhov, born a decade earlier, is a writer of similar stature, and his plays are genuinely popular. But only specialists debate his translators, and there are no books delving into the originals of his characters, or providing recipes for Chekhovian blini, or explaining how Chekhov can change your life, or presenting photographs of his intimates. Proust, by contrast, is a sort of improbable Belle Époque Tolkien, the maker of a world with passports and maps and secret codes, to which many seek entry.</p><p>A writer’s ability to induce this kind of fanaticism—less cult status than cathedral status, where we expect long lines, and hope to be improved by our visit—is still mysterious. Proust, even after he published the first volume of his great work, in 1913, would not have seemed a natural for such a role. He is, after all, the writer who put the long in “longueur”—whose subject is not war and peace, or the making and breaking of a dynasty, or, as with Joyce, the history of literature implanted in an urban day. His terrain is, rather, the strangled loves and pains of a small, fashionable circle, with much of the novel spent with the narrator going back and forth to beach resorts and feeling things, and many more pages, particularly in the middle books, where he simply takes trains, feels jealous, then feels less jealous, then more.</p><p>The peripheral Proust may persist as part of our search for a skeleton key to all the others—a way inside. There are at least six Marcel Prousts to study, and, though we’d like to say that each feeds the others, the truth is that they exist in separate, sometimes baffling strata. There’s the Period Proust, the Toulouse-Lautrec-like painter of the high life of the Belle Époque, who offers an unmatched picture both of riding in the Bois and of visiting the brothels near the Opéra; and the Philosophical Proust, whose thoughts on the nature of time supposedly derived from the ideas of Henri Bergson and are argued to have paralleled those of Einstein. There’s the Psychological Proust, whose analysis of human motives—above all, of love and jealousy—is the real living core of his book; and the “Perverse” Proust (as the eminent scholar Antoine Compagnon refers to him), who was among the first French authors to write quite openly about homosexuality. Then there is the Political Proust, the Jewish writer who diagrammed the fault line that the Dreyfus Affair first cracked in French society, and that the war pulled apart. Finally, there’s the Poetic Proust, the pathétique Proust who writes the sentences and finds the phrases, and whose twilight intensity and violet-tinted charm make his Big Book one of the few that readers urge on friends rather than merely force on students.</p><p>For all the speculative profundity that can be discovered in the vast annotative literature surrounding Proust, ranging from Samuel Beckett’s bleak, inscrutable summary to Roland Barthes’s structural appreciation, Proust is least interesting for his philosophical depth. The profound bits in Proust are the most commonplace, while the commonplace bits—the descriptions, the evocation of place, the characterizations, the jokes, the observations, and, most of all, the love stories—are the most profound. His is the most militant tract of aestheticism ever attempted, and understanding why it has been the most successful at making converts is the key to all the other nested Prousts.</p><p>The son of a half-Jewish Parisian grand-bourgeois family, Proust was known, before the 1913 publication of “Swann’s Way,” as a malicious, amusing, slightly absurd society boy, with a vaguely pathetic literary hobby. He had written some standard-issue aesthetic essays and stories, which no one read, and had translated Ruskin’s study of the Amiens cathedral. (He was an inveterate Anglophile: his favorite novelist was George Eliot, and his favorite novel “The Mill on the Floss.”) A charming society hanger-on, he was admired by his close friends for his literary dedication and the extraordinary flow of his letters—which are effortlessly parenthetical, sliding into digression and back to the main point with the skill of a rally driver dipping in and out of traffic at a hundred miles an hour. None of them, however, thought him much more than a dilettante.</p><p>The newly published stories collected in “The Mysterious Correspondent” feel wispy and inconsequential, but are fascinating as clues to Proust’s limitations, which, before 1913, seemed far more formidable than his talents. The stories were written in the eighteen-nineties, when he was in his twenties, and then locked away in a drawer while he worked on his unpublished novel, “Jean Santeuil,” and then on his masterwork. The title story, at least, was hidden for an obvious reason: it’s a tale of lesbian love. A timid, wealthy woman discovers that the thrilling love note she has received—which sets off a fantasy of making love to a soldier, complete with sword and spurs—was actually written by her closest woman friend. Proust often used lesbian love as a way into writing about homoerotic desire, partly because the female kind was, if not socially acceptable, at least a standard source of aesthetic frisson, and partly because it gave him an acceptable distance from which to write about his own same-sex desires.</p><p>It’s striking how out of focus the stories seem: they have a trancelike rhythm that makes events uneventful, and an absence of narrative push. Reading these lost tales, one recalls that, although none of Proust’s contemporaries doubted his intelligence, they did doubt his ability to turn his literary bent into something solid. In these stories, one sees what worried them: there’s every sign of a natural writer, but no sign at all of an author.</p><p>When the first volume of “In Search of Lost Time” appeared, a year before the Great War, the shock of its excellence was captured in a delicious exchange with André Gide, the magus of the Parisian literary scene. Apologizing for having passed on “Swann’s Way” for his Nouvelle Revue Française, Gide offered an explanation almost more insulting than the original rejection: “For me you were still the man who frequented the houses of Mmes X. and Z., the man who wrote for the Figaro. I thought of you, shall I confess it, as ‘du côté de chez Verdurin’; a snob, a man of the world, and a dilettante—the worst possible thing for our review.” Proust, who had money, had offered to help subsidize the publication, which, Gide fumbles to explain, only made it seem a dubious effort at buying a reputation. (That year, Gide confided in his journal his doubts that any Jewish writer could truly master the “virtues” of the French tradition.)</p><p>Proust responded with the most beautiful fuck-you letter in literary history, suavely pretending that Gide’s belatedly flattering letter made up for all the previous insults: “Had there been no rejection, no repeated rejections by the N.R.F., I should never have had your letter. . . . The joy of receiving your letter infinitely surpasses any I should have had at being published by the N.R.F. . . . How I should like to be able to give someone I loved as much pleasure as you have given me.” Gide, no fool, made a firm offer to publish the rest of the novel, which the Nouvelle Revue did, right through to its completion.</p><p>The exchange underlines several aspects of Proust as a phenomenon. First, Proust landed on his contemporaries with something of the same revelatory shock that he delivers to us. Perhaps only the abrupt celebrity of Karl Ove Knausgaard has had the same effect in our time. What made the metamorphosis? The unimaginably large space between the Proust of “The Mysterious Correspondent” and the Proust of “Swann’s Way” lies in his learning to trust the meandering nature of his own intelligence. He found a voice by hearing his own. The one thing that Proust’s mature literary manner is not is mannered. It was as natural and unimpeded as Mark Twain’s. His mind moved exactly as his sentences do, and his gift was to be able to trace its movements without being halted by other people’s literary rules.</p><p>But the exchange with Gide also reminds us of a less high-minded truth: that Proust was part of the beau monde of the Faubourg Saint-Germain, and that his enthusiasm for the high life—call it snobbery, as Gide did—was unmistakable. Part of the appeal of the novel is the era’s glamour. Swann goes to recover from his jealousies at the still extant swank restaurant Lapérouse; when the narrator realizes that “houses, roads, avenues are as fugitive, alas, as the years,” it is the high season in the Bois de Boulogne, the most exactingly landscaped park in Paris. Proust had conventional Parisian haute-bourgeois tastes of the time, from dinner in the Ritz garden to sexual frolics in the Right Bank brothels. He wanted the Prix Goncourt (got it), the Légion d’Honneur (got it), and membership in the Académie Française (couldn’t get it). Along with everything else he did that was more academically respectable, he offered a picture of a particularly beautiful place and period in the world’s history.</p><p>Proust front-loads his novel with his philosophy of time. One of the oddities is that its most famous incident happens within the first dozen pages, and is, nonetheless, isolated from the rest: the narrator (Proustians haughtily resist identifying him with Proust himself, or referring to him as Marcel, though he obviously is) eats the crumbs of a madeleine dipped in lime-blossom tea and is suddenly thrust back to his childhood at Combray. (The town was based on Illiers, an hour outside Paris, though in later volumes Proust quietly moved Combray much farther north and east, so that it could participate in the battles of the Great War.) His premise is that everything remains inside ourselves, including the past, not just in schematic outline but in its full sensory elaboration. The little smells and sounds are in there along with the big traumas and events. But, as readers may not recall, the memory event isn’t the unbidden association of a sensory clue with a suddenly materializing memory. On the contrary, the event is the result of an effortful process often met with failure:</p><blockquote><p>Will it ultimately reach the clear surface of my consciousness, this memory, this old, dead moment which the magnetism of an identical moment has travelled so far to importune, to disturb, to raise up out of the very depths of my being? I cannot tell. Now I feel nothing; it has stopped, has perhaps sunk back into its darkness, from which who can say whether it will ever rise again? Ten times over I must essay the task, must lean down over the abyss. And each time the cowardice that deters us from every difficult task, every important enterprise, has urged me to leave the thing alone, to drink my tea and to think merely of the worries of today and my hopes for tomorrow, which can be brooded over painlessly.</p></blockquote><p>Proust’s celebrated account of time’s relativity, dancing above or outside experience, though persuasively detailed, is not terribly original. It’s little different from the one that Shakespeare had long before put in Rosalind’s mouth: “Time travels in divers paces with divers persons.” Its apparent likeness to Einstein’s theory of special relativity has been much promoted, recently by the French physicist Thibault Damour, in his book “Once Upon Einstein.” Proust does seem to have become politely aware of Einstein, though rather as a contemporary writer might be of string theory—as a popular metaphor or two drawn from various newspaper writeups. But the similarities are strictly limited. Einstein’s insight was not that “everything is relative” but the opposite: his paradoxes of time are really paradoxes of timekeeping, and are the consequence of his introduction of an absolute, fixed standard—the speed of light. A revival of Sol Invictus worship was as reasonable an aftershock of Einstein’s theories as ideational relativism. In any case, a great novel could be written that intimates and parallels Einstein, and a bad one could be written that intimates and parallels Einstein. Proust’s book makes its own light.</p><p>The Philosophical Proust’s view of time is tied to his larger view of the primacy of mind—in which what we imagine matters more than what we see—and it is this view that shades over, more profitably, into the Psychological Proust. We think that we are living in the world, he insists, when we are living only in our minds. Again, the first volume sets the template, oft repeated later. Charles Swann—the Jewish man-about-town, welcome in every living room high, low, and middle—thinks that he is desperately in love with the courtesan Odette de Crécy; his eventual marriage to Odette gives him the beautiful child Gilberte, the first volume’s heroine, but it diminishes his life. The narrator’s cool analysis of motive (informed by Swann’s retrospective regrets) reveals that Swann has merely projected his obsessions onto Odette. He is in love with the face of one of the Botticelli women on the walls of the Sistine Chapel; he is in love with the fragment of music from the Vinteuil Sonata (probably a melody of Saint-Saëns’s) that he associates with her. He is triangulated by his own intensities.</p><p>Above all, he is in love with his own love, with things made in his own mind, and when ardor cools he is dazed to discover that the great passion of his life had been for a woman he didn’t like at all, a woman “who was not my type.” This, much more than the madeleine memory, is the real Proustian turn. Jealousy, the key emotion in Proust, is self-generated; we go hunting for rumors or images of our beloved entangled with another, to refresh the pain that has become synonymous with love. Our emotions move us right through a sequence of feelings, from the lightest to the darkest and back again, giving the illusion of walking in the park when we are merely once again touring the attic.</p><p>The narrator’s objects of desire and jealousy, like Swann’s, are all women, and it has long been accepted that they are almost all modelled on men. What Proust memorialized as living “in the shadow of young girls in flower” was more like luxuriating in the shadow of young boys on the make. As Carter’s “Proust in Love” details, the novelist, like most wealthy gay men of his time, found lovers extensively among working-class youths: waiters at the Ritz and chauffeurs at resorts. Not exclusively so—Gilberte, the narrator’s first great love as a boy, was modelled on several girls he knew—but Carter shows that Albertine, who dominates the middle volumes, is certainly a transmuted, if composited, version of Proust’s beloved chauffeur, Alfred Agostinelli.</p><p>Proust suffered from a set of gay fact checkers, in the person of other French writers—Jean Cocteau and Gide among them—who scoffed regularly at the transparency of his disguises, pointing out that the narrator’s blithe claim to have made love to fourteen or so girls on the beach was absurd, given the realities of young women’s lives in the period, though it was entirely plausible with working-class boys. (And his intimates <em>were</em> often boys—sixteen and seventeen. We are vastly more tolerant of sexual difference today, but we police age differences far more aggressively.)</p><p>Yet there is nothing humanly unconvincing about Albertine as an invented woman, or about the ring of girls on the beach as girls. That’s partly because Proust, utterly specific about the intricacies of the psyche, is cleverly unspecific about physical types: there are hardly any curvaceous bosoms or rounded bottoms, as in Zola, just an undifferentiated paradise of pure sensation. On the beach, vitality and exuberance are Proust’s hallmarks of attraction: “fine bodies, fine legs, fine hips, wholesome, serene faces,” as he catalogues them. “Blooming cheeks” occur over and over in Proust as a desirable attribute, with a Nabokovian pun in French as in English.</p><p>The anthropology of “sexual inversion” dominates the later volumes, particularly “<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sodom-Gomorrah-Search-Penguin-Classics/dp/0143039318">Sodom and Gomorrah</a>,” with its overheard hip flirt of attraction in the courtyard between the former tailor Jupien and the baron Charlus. Proust’s view of gayness would, by contemporary standards, be considered homophobic: he treats gay men, whom he calls “men-women,” as suffering from a deforming syndrome. Yet, whatever defensive tap dancing past the police is at work here (and Proust was arrested at least once in a male brothel), the portrait of male homosexuality is meant to be intricately humane. The idea of the man-woman is not a derogation of homosexuality but an explanation of its normalcy: people, being people, contain opposites within themselves. Against the old Platonic idea that humans are longing for their missing half, the “Perverse” Proust’s point is that they possess it already. Homosexuality is neither a deliciously archaic transgression, as it was for Wilde’s circle in London, nor a damnable perversion. It just is. We are all double in ourselves, he insisted—a formulation that he took from Montaigne, who he knew was part Jewish and who he may have thought was homosexual.</p><p>There is, however, a tear within the Matrix. As the strangled new stories in “The Mysterious Correspondent” remind us, Proust is often strange on the subject of lesbianism. In the becalmed Albertine volumes—which Proust, as Compagnon reminds us, enlarged late in the game—Proust’s anxiety about Albertine’s possible lesbian loves is, as Carter suggests, an extension of Proust’s anxiety about Agostinelli’s affairs with women. The disdain that Proust shows for lesbian lovers seems the one unresolved spot in his transpositions of desires. His lesbians are actually straight women who might seduce his own male lover, represented as a girl. Proust himself has a hard time keeping all the reflections in focus in this house of mirrors.</p><p>Even Proust’s dabbling in sexual paraphilia is touched by his peculiarly expansive kind of holistic humanism. He is reported, with what truth it is hard to say, to have had a taste for sadistic sexual rituals—in one particularly grotesque account, bringing himself to climax by watching rats forced to fight with one another in his presence. Yet in the pages of his book the dramatized relationship between cruelty and tenderness is so constant that it is no surprise that one might become a mirror image of the other. In Proust, fetishized desires are not seen as intrusions into an otherwise healthy persona but as naturally paired within one. It is entirely Proustian to imagine that the more kindness the more kink, the more appetite for delicacy the more desire for humiliation or fetishized savagery. In the last volume of the novel, Proust has his hyper-refined Baron de Charlus, after paying to be beaten in a brothel, protest that his punisher was not of sufficiently humble origins—not an authentic brute but only a pretend one. The joke isn’t that Charlus is ridiculous in wanting to be beaten by a real villain; the absurdity lies only in how quixotic he becomes in the pursuit of that desire.</p><p>For Proust, there was no hypocrisy in the exquisite aesthete who wants to be roughed up or even in that of the family man who achieves climax by cursing his family (a specific case known to him). Indeed, if one wanted a scientific coördinate for Proust’s vision, one might find it not in Einstein but in James Clerk Maxwell’s theories of electromagnetism, with one sensual field perpetually flipping into its opposite by a fixed law of oscillation. The truth of the battery is, for Proust, the truth of humankind; it must have two poles or it can carry no charge.</p><p>Today, the most present of Prousts is, inevitably, a Political Proust. Proust, being both gay and Jewish, participated in the two dissident cultures that are at the heart of so much modernist art. Benjamin Taylor’s book, in the Yale “Jewish Lives” series, does the best job of narrating Proust’s self-discovery as a Jew, as double-sided as his other understandings, and particularly his surprisingly aggressive role supporting the wrongly prosecuted Captain Alfred Dreyfus. Proust, who, though the son of a Jewish woman, was raised in the Catholic Church, was astonishingly courageous during the <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2009/09/28/trial-of-the-century">Dreyfus Affair</a>. He had no personal incentive to take such an outspoken stand, and he could win no points with the leftist opposition, since he was regarded as a comically marginal figure by the people he admired. (His signature on one Dreyfus petition, proudly offered, wasn’t at first even reprinted in the papers.)</p><p>Taylor insists that this was a genuine act of pure principle. Proust recognized the injustice and found it intolerable. There were assimilated Jews—Theodor Herzl, most famously—who became “single identity” Jews during the Dreyfus Affair. Proust was not one of them. But the word “intellectual,” in our current sense, was invented then, for the Dreyfusards, and that was what he became. He began to think of himself as a republican intellectual, a citizen with a pen and a conscience, as much as the aesthete he had been.</p><p>Though the Great War crushed Proust’s Paris, the Dreyfus Affair is the central exterior act of “In Search of Lost Time.” Just as Swann realizes that the Odette for whom he sacrificed his life is an imaginary creature, so the narrator realizes that the aristocrats of the Faubourg Saint-Germain are his own imaginative projection. The magic that had clung even to the name Guermantes proves to be as illusory as Odette’s Botticelli aura. The Duke de Guermantes’s anti-Semitic rant against the Dreyfusards is not just vile but vulgar, the kind of thing you would expect to read in a cheap tabloid. Proust had always expected his aristocrats to think stupidly; he just didn’t expect so many to behave so shabbily. The result was a revelation like Swann’s: it turns out that they had never really been his type.</p><p>Yet all other Prousts turn back, finally, to the Poetic Proust. We hear him clearly on the Milstein album; in the Saint-Saëns melody, we recognize at once the world Proust has conjured, its violet pangs and waves of emotion. As he wrote in a letter, “The essential purpose of music is to awaken in us the mysterious depths of our soul (which literature, painting, and sculpture cannot express).” The most musical pages of writing that exist in any language are those in the section of “Swann’s Way” called “Place-Names: The Name,” devoted to the romance of the adolescent Marcel and Gilberte, the daughter of Swann and Odette. Coming after the romance of the adults, it recapitulates all of its themes, though in a tenderly comic register:</p><blockquote><p>Doubtless the various reasons which made me so impatient to see her would have appeared less urgent to a grown man. As life goes on, we acquire such adroitness in the cultivation of our pleasures, that we content ourselves with the pleasure we derive from thinking of a woman, as I thought of Gilberte, without troubling ourselves to ascertain whether the image corresponds to the reality. . . . But at the period when I was in love with Gilberte, I still believed that Love did really exist outside ourselves.</p></blockquote><p>The book dispels this illusion of love, only after having first realized it perfectly here. The adolescent romance is, to be sure, very French—the two are young enough to play children’s games in the Champs-Élysées each afternoon, yet old enough to engage in a memorable moment of frottage. But what one recalls from “Place-Names: The Name” is the Mozartian sound through which the miniature love affair of the two children perfectly transposes—as when music we have first heard on flute and piano comes to us freshly revoiced, on an original-instrument recording, by recorder and harpsichord—the adult affair of Odette and Swann. It is a tonal triumph.</p><p>Proust has been called a novelist of manners, meaning a student of mores, of social rituals, but he is also a novelist of manners in another sense, a writer to whom courtesy is of exceptionally, almost supremely, high value. He admired the French aristocrats’ gift for making awkward moments easier—he even inserts into the book abstract details of good manners, like the Princess de Parme’s admiring the narrator’s “American” rubbers, meant for bad weather, which her footmen disdain. (“With those on, you will have nothing to fear even if it starts snowing again and you have a long way to go,” the Princess says. “You’re independent of the weather.”)</p><p>This pattern of French manners, so different from the British upper-class habit of creating maximum awkwardness to display status, is not cosmeticized. The Duchess de Guermantes will soon blow past Swann’s confession that he is dying with her dismissive reply: “You must be joking. . . . Come and have lunch.” But manners matter, still. The most telling of the peripheral Prousts newly on hand might be found in that strange volume of letters to his upstairs neighbors (translated by Davis), where he filters his ornery neurasthenia through the sieve of good manners, constantly sending gifts and praise along with his complaints. “Madame: I had ordered these flowers for you and I am in despair that they are coming on a day when against all expectation I feel so ill that I would like to ask you for silence tomorrow Saturday,” he writes. “Yet as this request is in no way conjoined with the flowers, causing them to lose all their fragrance as disinterested mark of respect and to bristle with nasty thorns, I would like even more not to ask you for this silence.”</p><p>One finds Proust here in pure, and necessarily comic, form. Courtesy is comedy: its elaborate euphemisms work like the slamming doors in a Feydeau farce, italicizing the elaborate network of ways in which we <em>just</em> avoid hurting one another’s feelings. For Proust, manners make humankind tolerable, as the one way to escape our own inevitable egotisms. We fall in love with ourselves, and the only way out is not through others—the standard ethical insistence—but through art, which connects us with others in a kind of psychic network of solipsisms. Part of Proust’s humanism lies in his ability to locate the world exclusively between our ears, without supposing that its residence there is necessarily to be regretted.</p><p>Proust’s still peerless original translator, C. K. Scott Moncrieff, has been mocked, by Nabokov, among others, for making Proust’s titles falsely Shakespearean: “Remembrance of Things Past” instead of the direct “In Search of Lost Time.” And yet this was a felicitous accident of taste, since there is something genuinely Shakespearean in Proust’s ability to extend his sympathy to every corner of his invention, even to people he finds ridiculous (like the Verdurins) or corrupted (like Charlus). They, too, have their story. Perhaps it is the wholeness of his humanism that explains why—despite the novel’s often bleak and disillusioned import—the happiest hours of many readers’ lives, including this one, have been spent reading him. “What a lot of pain there was all the way through,” an Iris Murdoch character muses about Proust. “So how was it that the whole thing could vibrate with such a pure joy?” John Updike, too, coming to Proust at a time of his own Christian doubts, found in him the necessary remedy, the only credible modern religious novelist. There is happiness to be found in his fatalism.</p><p>If Proust, for Updike in the God-haunted nineteen-fifties, was the last Christian poet, we may see him now in more secular terms, as a writer who, perversely, sought serenity not in detachment and self-removal but in attachment and reattachment—a monk within a metropolitan monastery. “Be here now” is the mystic’s insistence. “<em>Don’t</em> be here now” is Proust’s material motto: be there then, again. Enjoy, emote, repeat, remember: there are worse designs for living. </p><p><a id="how-long-can-we-live"></a></p><h1 id="How-Long-Can-We-Live"><a href="#How-Long-Can-We-Live" class="headerlink" title="How Long Can We Live?"></a>How Long Can We Live?</h1><p>来源: <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/28/magazine/human-lifespan.html">https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/28/magazine/human-lifespan.html</a></p><p>In 1990, not long after Jean-Marie Robine and Michel Allard began conducting a nationwide study of French centenarians, one of their software programs spat out an error message. An individual in the study was marked as 115 years old, a number outside the program’s range of acceptable age values. They called their collaborators in Arles, where the subject lived, and asked them to double-check the information they had provided, recalls Allard, who was then the director of the IPSEN Foundation, a nonprofit research organization. Perhaps they made a mistake when transcribing her birth date? Maybe this <a href="https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/10.1089/rej.2019.2298">Jeanne Calment</a> was actually born in 1885, not 1875? No, the collaborators said. We’ve seen her birth certificate. The data is correct.</p><p>Calment was already well known in her hometown. Over the next few years, as rumors of her longevity spread, she became a celebrity. Her birthdays, which had been local holidays for a while, inspired national and, eventually, international news stories. Journalists, doctors and scientists began crowding her nursing-home room, eager to meet <em>la doyenne de l’humanité</em>. Everyone wanted to know her story.</p><p>Calment lived her entire life in the sunburned clay-and-cobble city of Arles in the South of France, where she married a second cousin and moved into a spacious apartment above the store he owned. She never needed to work, instead filling her days with leisurely pursuits: bicycling, painting, roller skating and hunting. She enjoyed a glass of port, a cigarette and some chocolate nearly every day. In town, she was known for her optimism, good humor and wit. (“I’ve never had but one wrinkle,” she once said, “and I’m sitting on it.”)</p><p>By age 88, Calment had outlived her parents, husband, only child, son-in-law and grandson. As she approached her 110th birthday, she was still living alone in her cherished apartment. One day, during a particularly severe winter, the pipes froze. She tried to thaw them with a flame, accidentally igniting the insulating material. Neighbors noticed the smoke and summoned the fire brigade, which rushed her to a hospital. Following the incident, Calment moved into La Maison du Lac, the nursing home situated on the hospital’s campus, where she would live until her death at age 122 in 1997.</p><p>In 1992, as Calment’s fame bloomed, Robine and Allard returned to her file. Clearly, here was someone special — someone who merited a case study. Arles was just an hour’s drive from the village where Robine, a demographer at the French National Institute of Health and Medical Research, lived at the time. He decided to arrange a visit. At La Maison du Lac, he introduced himself to the medical director, Victor Lèbre, and explained that he wanted to interview Calment. Lèbre replied that it was too late; Calment, he said, was completely deaf. But he agreed to let him meet the grande dame anyway. They walked down a long concrete corridor and into a small and spare room.</p><p>“Hello, Madame Calment,” Lèbre said.</p><p>“Good morning, doctor,” she answered without hesitation.</p><p>Lèbre was so shocked that he grabbed Robine by the arm and rushed him down the corridor back to his office, where he interrogated the nurses about Calment’s hearing. Apparently she could hear quite well at times, but experienced periods of near deafness; Lèbre had most likely mistaken one of those interludes for a permanent condition. Upon returning to Calment’s room, Robine saw her properly for the first time. She was sitting by the window in an armchair that dwarfed her shrunken frame. Her eyes, milky with cataracts, could distinguish light from dark, but did not focus on any place in particular. Her plain gray clothes appeared to be several decades old.</p><p>During that first meeting, Robine and Calment mostly exchanged pleasantries and idle chatter. Over the next few years, however, Robine and Allard, in collaboration with several other researchers and archivists, interviewed <a href="https://www.demogr.mpg.de/books/odense/6/09.htm">Calment dozens of times and thoroughly documented her life history,</a> verifying her age and cementing her reputation as <a href="https://academic.oup.com/biomedgerontology/article/74/Supplement_1/S13/5569844?login=true">the oldest person who ever lived. </a>Since then, Calment has become something of an emblem of the ongoing quest to answer one of history’s most controversial questions: What exactly is the limit on the human life span?</p><p>As medical and social advances mitigate diseases of old age and prolong life, the number of exceptionally long-lived people is increasing sharply. <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0047637416302548">The United Nations estimates that there were about 95,000 centenarians in 1990</a> and more than 450,000 in 2015. By 2100, there will be 25 million. Although the proportion of people who live beyond their 110th birthday is far smaller, this once-fabled milestone is also increasingly common in many wealthy nations. The first validated cases of such “supercentenarians” emerged in the 1960s. Since then, their global numbers have multiplied by a factor of at least 10, though no one knows precisely how many there are. In <a href="https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-030-49970-9_10">Japan alone, the population of supercentenarians grew to 146 from 22 between 2005 and 2015,</a> a nearly sevenfold increase.</p><p>Given these statistics, you might expect that the record for longest life span would be increasing, too. Yet nearly a quarter-century after Calment’s death, no one is known to have matched, let alone surpassed, her 122 years. The closest was an American named Sarah Knauss, who died at age 119, two years after Calment. The oldest living person is Kane Tanaka, 118, who resides in Fukuoka, Japan. Very few people make it past 115. (A few researchers have even questioned whether Calment really lived as long as she claimed, though most accept her record as legitimate based on the weight of biographical evidence.)</p><p>As the global population approaches eight billion, and science discovers increasingly promising ways to slow or reverse aging in the lab, the question of human longevity’s potential limits is more urgent than ever. When their work is examined closely, it’s clear that longevity scientists hold a wide range of nuanced perspectives on the future of humanity. Historically, however — and somewhat flippantly, according to many researchers — their outlooks have been divided into two broad camps, which some journalists and researchers call the pessimists and the optimists. Those in the first group view life span as a candle wick that can burn for only so long. They generally think that we are rapidly approaching, or have already reached, a ceiling on life span, and that we will not witness anyone older than Calment anytime soon.</p><p>In contrast, the optimists see life span as a supremely, maybe even infinitely elastic band. They anticipate considerable gains in life expectancy around the world, increasing numbers of extraordinarily long-lived people — and eventually, supercentenarians who outlive Calment, pushing the record to 125, 150, 200 and beyond. Though unresolved, the long-running debate has already inspired a much deeper understanding of what defines and constrains life span — and of the interventions that may one day significantly extend it.</p><p>The theoretical limits on the length of a human life have vexed scientists and philosophers for thousands of years, but for most of history their discussions were largely based on musings and personal observations. In 1825, however, the British actuary <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4360127/">Benjamin Gompertz published a new mathematical model of mortality,</a> which demonstrated that the risk of death increased exponentially with age. Were that risk to continue accelerating throughout life, people would eventually reach a point at which they had essentially no chance of surviving to the next year. In other words, they would hit an effective limit on life span.</p><p>Instead, Gompertz observed that as people entered old age, the risk of death plateaued. “The limit to the possible duration of life is a subject not likely ever to be determined,” he wrote, “even should it exist.” Since then, using new data and more sophisticated mathematics, other scientists around the world have uncovered further evidence of accelerating death rates followed by mortality plateaus not only in humans but also in numerous other species, including <a href="http://longevity-science.org/pdf/Mortality-NAAJ-2011.pdf">rats, mice, shrimp, nematodes, fruit flies and beetles.</a></p><p>In 2016, an especially provocative study in the prestigious research journal Nature strongly implied that the authors had found the limit to the human life span. Jan Vijg, a geneticist at the Albert Einstein College of Medicine, and two colleagues analyzed decades’ worth of mortality data from several countries and concluded that although the highest reported age at death in these countries increased rapidly between the 1970s and 1990s, it had failed to rise since then, stagnating at an average of 114.9 years. Human life span, it seemed, had arrived at its limit. Although some individuals, like Jeanne Calment, might reach staggering ages, they were outliers, not indicators of a continual lengthening of life.</p><p>While a few scientists from the more pessimistic tradition applauded the study, many researchers sternly critiqued its methods, in particular the bold generalization based on what one commentary called a “limited, noisy set of data.” Nearly a dozen rebuttals appeared in Nature and other journals. James Vaupel, the founding director of the Max Planck Institute for Demographic Research and a staunch critic of the idea that the human life span has reached its limit, called the study a travesty and <a href="http://showcase.casw.org/stories/peer-review-post-mortem-how-a-flawed-aging-study-was-published-in-nature/">told the science journalist Hester van Santen</a> that the authors “just shoveled the data into their computer like you’d shovel food into a cow.”</p><p>Robine remembers the furor well. He was one of several peer reviewers whom Nature recruited to evaluate the study by Vijg and his co-authors before publication. The first draft did not satisfy Robine’s standards, because it focused only on the United States and relied on data he considered incomplete. Among other changes, he recommended using the more comprehensive International Database on Longevity, which he and Vaupel developed with colleagues. <a href="http://showcase.casw.org/stories/peer-review-post-mortem-how-a-flawed-aging-study-was-published-in-nature/">Van Santen reported in a peer-review post-mortem</a> that, based on the substantial criticism by Robine and one of the other reviewers, Nature initially declined to publish the study. After Vijg and his co-authors sent Nature a thoroughly revised version, however, Robine conceded that the study was sound enough to publish, though he still disagreed with its conclusions. (Vijg stands by the methodology and conclusions of the study.)</p><p>Two years later, in 2018, the equally prestigious journal Science published a study that completely contradicted the one in Nature. The demographers Elisabetta Barbi of the University of Rome and Kenneth Wachter of the University of California, Berkeley, along with several colleagues, examined the survival trajectories of nearly 4,000 Italians and concluded that, while the risk of death increased exponentially up to age 80, it then slowed and eventually plateaued. Someone alive at 105 had about a 50 percent chance of living to the next year. The same was true at 106, 107, 108 and 109. Their findings, the authors wrote, “strongly suggest that longevity is continuing to increase over time, and that a limit, if any, has not been reached.”</p><p>Many of the disputes over human longevity studies center on the integrity of different data sets and the varying statistical methods researchers use to analyze them. Where one group of scientists perceives a clear trend, another suspects an illusion. Robine finds the debate exciting and essential. “I’m not convinced by my colleagues’ suggesting that life is or is not limited,” he told me. “I think the question is still here. We don’t yet know the best kind of analysis or study design to use to tackle this question. The most important thing to do today is to keep collecting the data.”</p><p>On their own, however, life-span statistics can tell us only so much. Such data have been available for centuries and have clearly not settled the debate. The number of supercentenarians may still be too small to support unequivocal conclusions about mortality rates in extreme old age. But in more recent decades, scientists have made considerable progress toward understanding the evolutionary origins of longevity and the biology of aging. Instead of fixating on human demographics, this research considers all species on the planet and tries to derive general principles about duration of life and timing of death.</p><p>“I’m a little surprised that anyone today would question whether or not there is a limit,” S. Jay Olshansky, an expert on longevity and a professor in the School of Public Health at the University of Illinois at Chicago, told me. “It doesn’t really matter whether there is a plateau of mortality or not in extreme old age. There are so few people that make it up there, and the risk of death at that point is so high, that most people aren’t going to live much beyond the limits we see today.”</p><p>Olshansky, 67, has argued for decades that life span is obviously limited and that the mathematical models of feuding demographers are secondary to the biological realities of aging. He likes to make an analogy to athletics: “Could someone run a two-minute mile? No. The human body is incapable of moving that fast based on anatomical limitations. The same thing applies to human longevity.”</p><p>He is so thoroughly convinced of his position that he has backed it with an investment that may eventually grow to a sizable fortune for him or his heirs. In 2000, Steven Austad, a biologist now at the University of Alabama, Birmingham, told Scientific American, “The first 150-year-old person is probably alive right now.” When Olshansky disagreed, <a href="https://www.nature.com/news/scientists-up-stakes-in-bet-on-whether-humans-will-live-to-150-1.20818#/b1">the two struck up a friendly bet</a>: Each put $150 in an investment fund and signed a contract stipulating that the winner or his descendants would claim the returns in 2150. After the Vijg paper was published, they doubled their contributions. Olshansky originally invested the funds in gold and later in Tesla. He estimates the value will be well over $1 billion when it’s time to collect. “Oh, I am going to win,” Olshansky said when I asked him how he currently feels about the wager. “Ultimately, biology will determine which one of us is right. That’s why I’m so confident.”</p><p>Embedded in the question of the human life span’s limits is a more fundamental enigma: Why do we — why does any organism — get old and die in the first place? As the eminent physicist Richard Feynman put it in a 1964 lecture, “There is nothing in biology yet found that indicates the inevitability of death.”</p><p>Some organisms seem to be living proof of this claim. Scientists recently drilled into sediments deep beneath the seafloor and unearthed microbes that had probably survived “in a metabolically active form” for <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7387439/">more than 100 million years.</a> Pando, a 106-acre clonal colony of genetically identical aspen trees connected by a single root system in Utah, is thought to have sustained itself for as long as <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5498503/">14,000 years and counting.</a></p><p>A few creatures are so ageless that some scientists regard them as biologically immortal. <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3511741/">Hydra,</a> tiny relatives of jellyfish and corals, do not appear to age at all and can regenerate whole new bodies when sliced into pieces. When injured or threatened, a sexually mature <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6893190/">Turritopsis dohrnii,</a> the immortal jellyfish, can revert to its juvenile stage, mature and revert again, potentially forever. Biologically immortal organisms are not impervious to death — they can still perish from predation, lethal injury or infection — but they do not seem to die of their own accord. Theoretically, any organism with a continual supply of energy, a sufficient capacity for self-maintenance and repair and the good fortune to evade all environmental hazards could survive until the end of the universe.</p><p>Why, then, do so many species expire so dependably? Most longevity researchers agree that aging, the set of physical processes of damage and decay that result in death, is not an adaptive trait shaped by natural selection. Rather, aging is a byproduct of selection’s waning power over the course of an organism’s life. Selection acts most strongly on genes and traits that help living creatures survive adolescence and reproduce. In many species, the few individuals who make it to old age are practically invisible to natural selection because they are no longer passing on their genes, nor helping raise their relatives’ progeny.</p><p>As the British biologist Peter Medawar observed in the 1950s, harmful genetic mutations that are not expressed until late in life could accumulate across generations because selection is too weak to remove them, eventually resulting in specieswide aging. The American biologist George C. Williams elaborated on Medawar’s ideas, adding that some genes may be beneficial in youth but detrimental later on, when selection would overlook their disadvantages. Similarly, in the 1970s, the British biologist Thomas Kirkwood proposed that aging was partly due to an evolutionary trade-off between growth and reproduction on the one hand and day-to-day maintenance on the other. Devoting resources to maintenance is advantageous only if an organism is likely to continue surviving and reproducing. For many organisms, external threats are too great and numerous to endure for very long, so there is not much evolutionary pressure to preserve their bodies in old age, resulting in their deterioration.</p><p>But that still leaves the question of why there is such huge variation in life span among species. Biologists think life span is largely determined by a species’ anatomy and lifestyle. Small and highly vulnerable animals tend to reproduce quickly and die not long after, whereas larger animals, and those with sophisticated defenses, usually reproduce later in life and live longer overall. Ground-dwelling birds, for instance, often have shorter life spans than strong-winged, tree-nesting species, which are less susceptible to predators. Naked mole rats, which enjoy the cooperative benefits of tight-knit social groups and the protection of subterranean chambers, live five to 10 times longer than other similarly sized mammals.</p><p>A few species, like stalwart clonal trees with resilient root systems, are so well protected against environmental hazards that they don’t have to prioritize early growth and reproduction over long-term maintenance, allowing them to live an extraordinarily long time. Others, like the immortal jellyfish and hydra, are potentially indefinite, because they have retained primordial powers of rejuvenation that have been relegated to pockets of stem cells in most adult vertebrates.</p><p>Humans have never belonged to the select society of the everlasting. We most likely inherited fairly long life spans from our last common ancestor with chimpanzees, which may have been a large, intelligent, social ape that lived in trees away from ground predators. But we never out-evolved the eventual senescence that is part of being a complex animal with all manner of metabolically costly adaptations and embellishments.</p><p>As the years pass, our chromosomes contract and fracture, genes turn on and off haphazardly, mitochondria break down, proteins unravel or clump together, reserves of regenerative stem cells dwindle, bodily cells stop dividing, bones thin, muscles shrivel, neurons wither, organs become sluggish and dysfunctional, the immune system weakens and self-repair mechanisms fail. There is no programmed death clock ticking away inside us — no precise expiration date hard-wired into our species — but, eventually, the human body just can’t keep going.</p><p>Social advances and improving public health may further increase life expectancy and lift some supercentenarians well beyond Calment’s record. Even the most optimistic longevity scientists admit, however, that at some point these environmentally induced gains will run up against human biology’s limits — unless, that is, we fundamentally alter our biology.</p><p>Many scientists who study aging think that biomedical breakthroughs are the only way to substantially increase the human life span, but some doubt that anyone alive today will witness such radical interventions; a few doubt they are even possible. In any case, longevity scientists agree, significantly elongating life without sustaining well-being is pointless, and enhancing vitality in old age is valuable regardless of gains in maximum life span.</p><p>One of the many obstacles to these goals is the overwhelming complexity of aging in mammals and other vertebrates. Researchers have achieved astonishing results by tweaking the genome of the roundworm C. elegans, extending its life span nearly 10 times — the equivalent of a person’s living 1,000 years. Although scientists have used caloric restriction, genetic engineering and various drugs to stretch life span in more complex species, including fish, rodents and monkeys, the gains have never been as sharp as in roundworms, and the precise mechanisms underlying these changes remain unclear.</p><p>More recently, however, researchers have tested particularly innovative techniques for reversing and postponing some aspects of aging, with tentative but promising results. <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6082705/">James Kirkland, an expert on aging at the Mayo Clinic in Rochester, Minn., has demonstrated </a>with colleagues that certain drug cocktails purge old mice of senescent cells, granting them more than a month of additional healthy living. Their research has already inspired numerous human clinical trials.</p><p>At the same time, at the University of California, Berkeley, the married bioengineers <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5121415/">Irina and Michael Conboy are investigating</a> ways to filter or dilute aged blood in rodents to remove molecules that inhibit healing, which in turn stimulates cellular regeneration and the production of revitalizing compounds.</p><p>In a study published in Nature in December 2020, David Sinclair, a director of the Paul F. Glenn Center for the Biology of Aging Research at Harvard Medical School, along with colleagues, partly restored vision in middle-aged and ailing mice by reprogramming their gene expression. The researchers injected the mice’s eyes with a benign virus carrying genes that revert mature cells to a more supple, stem-cell-like state, which allowed their neurons to regenerate — an ability that mammals usually lose after infancy. “Aging is far more reversible than we thought,” Sinclair told me. “Cells can clean themselves up, they can get rid of old proteins, they can rejuvenate, if you turn on the youthful genes through this reset process.”</p><p>Known for his boyish features and sanguine predictions, Sinclair, 51, and several of his family members (including his dogs) follow versions of his life-prolonging regimen, which has, over the years, included regular exercise, sauna steams and ice baths, a two-meal-a-day mostly vegetarian diet, the diabetes drug metformin (which is purported to have anti-aging properties) and several vitamins and supplements, like the once-hyped but ultimately disappointing red-wine miracle molecule resveratrol. Sinclair has also founded at least 12 biotech companies and serves on the boards of several more, one of which is already pursuing human clinical trials of a gene therapy based on his recent Nature study.</p><p>In <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9nXop2lLDa4">a talk at Google,</a> he envisioned a future in which people receive similar treatments every decade or so to undo the effects of aging throughout the body. “We don’t know how many times you can reset,” he said. “It might be three, it might be 3,000. And if you can reset your body 3,000 times, then things get really interesting. I don’t know if any of you want to live for 1,000 years, but I also don’t know if it’s going to be possible, but these are the questions we have to start thinking about. Because it’s not a question of if — it’s now a question of when.”</p><p>Longevity scientists who favor the idea of living for centuries or longer tend to speak effusively of prosperity and possibility. As they see it, sustaining life and promoting health are intrinsically good and, therefore, so are any medical interventions that accomplish this. Biomedically extended longevity would not only revolutionize general well-being by minimizing or preventing diseases of aging, they say, it would also vastly enrich human experience. It would mean the chance for several fulfilling and diverse careers; the freedom to explore much more of the world; the joy of playing with your great-great-great-grandchildren; the satisfaction of actually sitting in the shade of the tree you planted so long ago. Imagine, some say, how wise our future elders could be. Imagine what the world’s most brilliant minds could accomplish with all that time.</p><p>In sharp contrast, other experts argue that extending life span, even in the name of health, is a doomed pursuit. Perhaps the most common concern is the potential for overpopulation, especially considering humanity’s long history of hoarding and squandering resources and the tremendous socioeconomic inequalities that already divide a world of nearly eight billion. There are still dozens of countries where life expectancy is below 65, primarily because of problems like poverty, famine, limited education, disempowerment of women, poor public health and diseases like malaria and H.I.V./AIDS, which novel and expensive life-extending treatments will do nothing to solve.</p><p>Lingering multitudes of superseniors, some experts add, would stifle new generations and impede social progress. “There is a wisdom to the evolutionary process of letting the older generation disappear,” said Paul Root Wolpe, the director of the Center for Ethics at Emory University, during <a href="https://www.statnews.com/2016/02/04/aging-extending-human-life/">one public debate on life extension.</a> “If the World War I generation and World War II generation and perhaps, you know, the Civil War generation were still alive, do you really think that we would have civil rights in this country? Gay marriage?”</p><p>In her final years at La Maison du Lac, the once-athletic Jeanne Calment was essentially immobile, confined to her bed and wheelchair. Her hearing continued to decline, she was virtually blind and she had trouble speaking. At times, it was not clear that she was fully aware of her surroundings.</p><p>By some accounts, those in charge of Calment’s care failed to shield her from undue commotion and questionable interactions as journalists, tourists and spectators bustled in and out of her room. Following the release of an investigative documentary, the hospital director barred all visitors. The last time Robine saw her was shortly after her 120th birthday. About two years later, in the midst of an especially hot summer, Jeanne Calment died alone in her nursing-home room from unknown causes and was quickly buried. Only a few people were permitted to attend her funeral. Robine and Allard were not among them. Neither was Calment’s family: All her close relatives had been dead for more than three decades.</p><p>“Today, more people are surviving the major diseases of old age and entering a new phase of their life in which they become very weak,” Robine said. “We still don’t know how to avoid frailty.”</p><p>Perhaps the most unpredictable consequence of uncoupling life span from our inherited biology is how it would alter our future psychology. All of human culture evolved with the understanding that earthly life is finite and, in the grand scheme, relatively brief. If we are one day born knowing that we can reasonably expect to live 200 years or longer, will our minds easily accommodate this unparalleled scope of life? Or is our neural architecture, which evolved amid the perils of the Pleistocene, inherently unsuited for such vast horizons?</p><p>Scientists, philosophers and writers have long feared that a surfeit of time would exhaust all meaningful experience, culminating in debilitating levels of melancholy and listlessness. Maybe the desire for all those extra years masks a deeper longing for something unattainable: not for a life that is simply longer, but for one that is long enough to feel utterly perfect and complete.</p><p>In Jorge Luis Borges’s short story “The Immortal,” a Roman military officer stumbles upon a “secret river that purifies men of death.” After drinking from it and spending eons in deep thought, he realizes that death imbues life with value, whereas, for immortals, “Nothing can occur but once, nothing is preciously <em>in peril of being lost</em>.” Determined to find the antidote to everlasting life, he wanders the planet for nearly a millennium. One day, he drinks from a spring of clear water on the Eritrean coast and shortly thereafter scratches the back of his hand on a thorny tree. Startled by an unfamiliar twinge of pain, he searches for a sign of injury. As a drop of blood slowly pools on his skin — proof of his restored mortality — he simply watches, “incredulous, speechless, and in joy.”</p><p><a id="has-an-old-soviet-mystery-at-last-been-solved"></a></p><h1 id="Has-an-Old-Soviet-Mystery-at-Last-Been-Solved"><a href="#Has-an-Old-Soviet-Mystery-at-Last-Been-Solved" class="headerlink" title="Has an Old Soviet Mystery at Last Been Solved?"></a>Has an Old Soviet Mystery at Last Been Solved?</h1><p>The strange fate of a group of skiers in the Ural Mountains has generated endless speculation.</p><p>来源: <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2021/05/17/has-an-old-soviet-mystery-at-last-been-solved">https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2021/05/17/has-an-old-soviet-mystery-at-last-been-solved</a></p><p>Igor Dyatlov was a tinkerer, an inventor, and a devotee of the wilderness. Born in 1936, near Sverdlovsk (now Yekaterinburg), he built radios as a kid and loved camping. When the Soviet Union launched Sputnik, in 1957, he constructed a telescope so that he and his friends could watch the satellite travel across the night sky. By then, he was an engineering student at the city’s Ural Polytechnic Institute. One of the leading technical universities in the country, U.P.I. turned out topflight engineers to work in the nuclear-power and weapons industries, communications, and military engineering. During his years there, Dyatlov led a number of arduous wilderness trips, often using outdoor equipment that he had invented or improved on. It was a time of optimism in the U.S.S.R. Khrushchev’s Thaw had freed many political prisoners from Stalin’s Gulag, economic growth was robust, and the standard of living was rising. The shock that the success of Sputnik delivered to the West further bolstered national confidence. In late 1958, Dyatlov began planning a winter expedition that would exemplify the boldness and vigor of a new Soviet generation: an ambitious sixteen-day cross-country ski trip in the Urals, the north-south mountain range that divides western Russia from Siberia, and thus Europe from Asia.</p><p>He submitted his proposal to the U.P.I. sports club, which readily approved it. Dyatlov’s itinerary lay three hundred and fifty miles north of Sverdlovsk, in the traditional territory of the Mansi, an indigenous people. The Mansi came into contact with Russians around the sixteenth century, when Russia was extending its control over Siberia. Though largely Russified by this time, the Mansi continued to pursue a semi-traditional way of life—hunting, fishing, and reindeer herding. Dyatlov’s group would ski two hundred miles, on a route that no Russian, as far as anyone knew, had taken before. The mountains were gentle and rounded, their barren slopes rising from a vast boreal forest of birch and fir. The challenge wouldn’t be rugged terrain but brutally cold temperatures, deep snow, and high winds.</p><p>Dyatlov recruited his classmate Zina Kolmogorova, and seven other fellow-students and recent graduates. They were among the élite of Soviet youth and all highly experienced winter campers and cross-country skiers. One was Dyatlov’s close friend Georgy Krivonishchenko, who had graduated from U.P.I. two years before and worked as an engineer at the Mayak nuclear complex, in the then secret town of Chelyabinsk-40. Jug-eared, small, and wiry, he told jokes, sang, and played the mandolin. Two other recent graduates were Rustem Slobodin and Nikolay Thibault-Brignoles, of French descent, whose father had been worked nearly to death in one of Stalin’s camps. The other students included Yuri Yudin, Yuri Doroshenko, and Aleksandr Kolevatov. The youngest of the group, at twenty, was Lyuda Dubinina, an economics major, a track athlete, and an ardent Communist, who wore her long blond hair in braids tied with silk ribbons. On a previous wilderness outing, Dubinina had been accidentally shot by a hunter, and survived—quite cheerfully, it was said—a fifty-mile journey back to civilization. A couple of days before the group was due to set off, the U.P.I. administration unexpectedly added a new member, much older than the others and largely unknown to them: Semyon Zolotaryov, a thirty-seven-year-old veteran of the Second World War with an old-fashioned mustache, stainless-steel crowns on his teeth, and tattoos.</p><p>The party left Sverdlovsk by train on January 23rd. Several of them hid under seats to avoid buying tickets. They were in high spirits—so high that on a layover between trains Krivonishchenko was briefly detained by police for playing his mandolin and pretending to panhandle in the train station. We know these details because there was a communal journal, and many of the skiers also kept personal journals. At least five had cameras, and the pictures they took show a lively and strikingly handsome group of young people having the adventure of their lives—skiing, laughing, playing in the snow, and mugging for the camera.</p><p>After two days on trains, the party reached Ivdel, a remote town with a Stalin-era prison camp that, by then, held mostly criminals. From there the group travelled another day by bus, then in the back of a woodcutter’s truck, and finally by ski, guided by a horse-drawn sleigh. They slept in an abandoned logging camp called Second Northern. There Yuri Yudin had a flareup of sciatica that forced him to pull out of the trip. The next day, January 28th, he turned back, while the remaining nine set off toward the mountains. The plan was to end up at the tiny village of Vizhai around February 12th, and telegram the U.P.I. sports club that they had arrived safely. The expected telegram never came.</p><p>At first, the U.P.I. sports club assumed that the group had just been held up; there had been reports of a heavy snowstorm in the mountains. But, after several days passed, families of the group began placing frantic phone calls to the university and to the local bureau of the Communist Party, and, on February 20th, a search was launched. There were several search parties: student volunteers from U.P.I., prison guards from the Ivdel camp, Mansi hunters, local police; the military deployed planes and helicopters. On February 25th, the students found ski tracks, and the next day they discovered the skiers’ tent—above the tree line on a remote mountain that Soviet officials referred to as Height 1079 and that the Mansi called Kholat Syakhl, or Dead Mountain. There was no one inside.</p><p>The tent was partly collapsed and largely buried in snow. After digging it out, the search party saw that the tent appeared to have been deliberately slashed in several places. Yet, inside, everything was neat and orderly. The skiers’ boots, axes, and other equipment were arranged on either side of the door. Food was laid out as if about to be eaten; there was a stack of wood for a heating stove, and clothes, cameras, and journals.</p><p>About a hundred feet downhill, the search party found “very distinct” footprints of eight or nine people, walking (not running) toward the tree line. Almost all the prints were of stockinged feet, some even bare. One person appeared to be wearing a single ski boot. “Some of the prints indicated that the person was either barefoot or in socks because you could see the toes,” a searcher later testified. The party followed the prints downhill for six to seven hundred yards, until they vanished near the tree line.</p><p>The next morning, searchers found the bodies of the mandolin player Krivonishchenko and the student Doroshenko under a tall cedar tree at the edge of the forest. They were lying next to a dead fire, wearing only underwear. Twelve to fifteen feet up the tree were some recently broken branches, and on the trunk bits of skin and torn clothes were found. Later that day, a search party discovered the bodies of Dyatlov and Kolmogorova. Both were farther up the slope, facing in the direction of the tent, their fists tightly clenched. They seemed to have been trying to get back there.</p><p>The four bodies were autopsied, while the search for the others continued. The medical examiner noted a number of bizarre features. Krivonishchenko had blackened fingers and third-degree burns on a shin and a foot. Inside his mouth was a chunk of flesh that he had bitten off his right hand. Doroshenko’s body had burned hair on one side of the head and a charred sock. All the bodies were covered with bruises, abrasions, scratches, and cuts, as was a fifth body, that of the recent graduate Slobodin, which was discovered a few days later. Like Dyatlov and Kolmogorova, Slobodin was on the slope leading back to the tent, with a sock on one foot and a felt bootie on the other; his autopsy noted a minor fracture to his skull.</p><p>By now, a homicide investigation was under way, led by a prosecutor in his mid-thirties named Lev Ivanov. Toxicology tests were done, witness testimony taken, diagrams and maps made of the scene, and evidence gathered and forensically analyzed. The tent and its contents were helicoptered out of the mountains and set up again inside a police station. This led to a key discovery: a seamstress who came to the station to do a uniform fitting happened to notice that the slashes in the tent had been made from the inside.</p><p>Something had happened that induced the skiers to cut their way out of the tent and flee into the night, into a howling blizzard, in twenty-below-zero temperatures, in bare feet or socks. They were not novices to the winter mountains; they would have been acutely aware of the fatal consequences of leaving the tent half dressed in those conditions. This is the central, and apparently inexplicable, mystery of the incident.</p><p>Four bodies remained missing. In early May, when the snow began to melt, a Mansi hunter and his dog came across the remains of a makeshift snow den in the woods two hundred and fifty feet from the cedar tree: a floor of branches laid in a deep hole in the snow. Pieces of tattered clothing were found strewn about: black cotton sweatpants with the right leg cut off, the left half of a woman’s sweater. Another search team arrived and, using avalanche probes around the den, they brought up a piece of flesh. Excavation uncovered the four remaining victims, lying together in a rocky streambed under at least ten feet of snow. The autopsies revealed catastrophic injuries to three of them. Thibault-Brignoles’s skull was fractured so severely that pieces of bone had been driven into the brain. Zolotaryov and Dubinina had crushed chests with multiple broken ribs, and the autopsy report noted a massive hemorrhage in the right ventricle of Dubinina’s heart. The medical examiner said the damage was similar to what is typically seen as the “result of an impact of an automobile moving at high speed.” Yet none of the bodies had external penetrating wounds, though Zolotaryov’s was missing its eyes, and Dubinina’s was missing its eyes, tongue, and part of the upper lip.</p><p>A careful inventory of clothing recovered from the bodies revealed that some of these victims were wearing clothes taken or cut off the bodies of others, and a laboratory found that several items emitted unnaturally high levels of radiation. A radiological expert testified that, because the bodies had been exposed to running water for months, these levels of radiation must originally have been “many times greater.”</p><p>On May 28th, Ivanov abruptly closed the investigation. His role was to determine whether a crime had been committed, not to clarify what had happened, and he concluded that homicide was not a factor. Ivanov ended his report with a non-explanation that has bedevilled Dyatlov researchers ever since: “It should be concluded that the cause of the hikers’ demise was an overwhelming force, which they were not able to overcome.”</p><p>In classic Soviet style, a number of officials who had little to do with the tragedy were either punished or fired, including the director of U.P.I. and the chairman of its sports club, the local Communist Party secretary, the chairmen of two workers’ unions, and a union inspector. The investigative files, photographs, and journals were classified and the area around Dead Mountain was placed off limits to skiers and outdoor enthusiasts for years. The tent was stored but eventually became moldy and had to be thrown out. The saddle in the mountains which the skiers were heading for but never reached was named the Dyatlov Pass.</p><p>The victims’ families were left deeply dissatisfied. Many of them wrote to officials, including Khrushchev, demanding a more thorough investigation. But nothing more was done, and the mysterious deaths of the nine skiers subsided into relative obscurity.</p><p>In 1990, the prosecutor Ivanov, who had retired, published an article in which he claimed that, while compiling his 1959 report, he’d been pressured not to include his views on what happened. The article, titled “The Enigma of the Fireballs,” said that the skiers had been killed by heat rays or balls of fire associated with U.F.O.s. In his original examination of the scene, Ivanov had found trees with unusual burn marks, which “confirmed that some kind of heat ray, say, or a powerful force whose nature is completely unknown (to us, at least) acted selectively on specific objects”—in this case, people. The last photograph in Krivonishchenko’s camera showed flares and streaks of light against a black background.</p><p>By then, the official files had been released and, in the decades since, the case has become one of the most celebrated mysteries of the Soviet era. It has generated dozens of books and documentaries, along with a slew of Web sites and message boards on which Dyatlov obsessives trade scores of theories—the official count of the Russian Prosecutor General’s office lists seventy-five—about what happened. In 2000, relatives and friends of the victims established the Dyatlov Group Memorial Foundation, whose purpose is to honor the memory of the skiers and seek the truth. Its president is Yuri Kuntsevich, who, as a twelve-year-old boy, attended the funerals of some of the victims. He went on to study and teach at U.P.I. (which has since become the Ural State Technical University) and to join its sports club. Now in his mid-seventies, he still leads tours to the Dyatlov Pass. Kuntsevich told me that Russians generally favor one of two theories: the skiers died because they had stumbled into an area where secret weapons were being tested; alternatively, the party was “killed by mercenaries,” probably American spies.</p><p>Kuntsevich insists that the first of these theories is the correct one, and it’s also what the families tend to believe. The idea is that a missile launch of some kind went disastrously wrong, inflicting severe injuries on some of the skiers and forcing the group to flee their tent, at which point they either froze to death or were killed by military observers. Yuri Yudin, whose sciatica compelled him to abandon the trip, likewise maintained that the deaths were not natural. Not long before he died, in 2013, he declared that his teammates had been taken from the tent at gunpoint and murdered. Dubinina, he said, may have had her tongue cut out by the killers because she was the most outspoken of the group.</p><p>Proponents of the weapons-test theory cite claims from people in the region that they had seen flashes of light or moving balls of fire in the direction of the mountains. In 2008, a three-foot-long piece of metal was found in the area; according to the Dyatlov Foundation, which took possession of it, the metal is part of a Soviet ballistic missile. Military tests would explain the radioactivity of recovered clothing. Yevgeny Okishev, Ivanov’s supervisor in the Prosecutor General’s office, gave an interview to a newspaper in 2013, in which he recalled finding it suspicious when he and his colleagues were instructed to test recovered items for radiation. He sent a letter to his superiors asking why radiation was relevant. In response, the Deputy Prosecutor General met with the team. Okishev said that the official dodged questions about weapons testing and ordered them to tell people that the deaths were accidental. “The victims’ parents came to my office, some screamed and called us Fascists for hiding the truth from them,” Okishev recalled. “But the case was closed, and not on our orders.”</p><p>The theory, however, is not consistent with what was found at the site. There was no evidence that other people had been there. Snow does not lie: it would have been close to impossible to erase signs of the people and equipment involved in killing the group and restaging the scene. Besides, why make the staging so elaborate and bizarre? Why scatter the bodies around the landscape, cut off the clothing of some and dress others in it, build a snow den, bury four bodies in ten feet of snow, light a fire, and climb a tree to break branches, leaving skin on the bark? The theory would also suggest that there was a secret weapons base in the area, or that an errant missile had exploded over it. Yet, despite the mass declassification of documents from the Soviet era and the diligent searches of Dyatlov enthusiasts, no such evidence has emerged.</p><p>The K.G.B. theory centers on Zolotaryov, the man who was foisted on the group at the last minute. A book published in Russia claims that he and two other skiers were K.G.B. agents on an assignment to meet with a group of C.I.A. operatives, to furnish them with deliberately misleading information. Samples of clothing contaminated by radioactive isotopes were to be offered as bait; the C.I.A. agents discovered the deception, killed them, and staged the scene. It is certainly possible that Zolotaryov had a K.G.B. link. His service record in the Second World War had holes and inconsistencies, and his sudden inclusion certainly seems suspicious. Still, a K.G.B. connection, even if proved, wouldn’t mean much; many people were low-level informants at the time. And the idea that the C.I.A. would have chosen a place like Dead Mountain for a rendezvous strains credulity.</p><p>Another class of theories considers a variety of natural disasters. An avalanche, perhaps, struck the tent, causing the crushing injuries to three of the victims and forcing the whole group to cut their way out and head to the forest for shelter. But no avalanche debris was found—a ski pole holding up the front of the tent was still standing—and the original investigation determined that the slope was too shallow to generate an avalanche. Besides, the injuries to the three victims found in the streambed were totally incapacitating. They could never have made it there unassisted—it was more than a mile from the tent—but the tracks leading downhill showed no signs of anyone being dragged. There were eight or nine separate sets of footprints, so the fatal injuries must have come after everyone had left the tent. A 2013 best-seller by the filmmaker and writer Donnie Eichar suggests that high winds passing over the mountain created infrasound‚ vibrations below the range of human hearing, and that this induced such terror that the skiers fled. Much about the book is excellent—Eichar conducted many interviews in Russia and travelled to the Dyatlov Pass in winter—but his thesis would require all nine people to have been so terrified of a sound they couldn’t even hear that they ran to certain death, not grabbing their coats or boots, and slashing their way out, when the tent door would have made for a far easier exit.</p><p>Various hypotheses considered in the 1959 inquest have also been raked over: carbon-monoxide poisoning from the heater; sudden madness caused by consuming bad alcohol or hallucinogenic mushrooms that the Mansi sometimes hung on trees to dry; or even murder by the Mansi themselves, if, for instance, the party had strayed onto sacred land. But the autopsies ruled out the first two of these, and when the original investigators interviewed the local Mansi they found them “well disposed toward Russians,” and believable. The Mansi had provided valuable help in the search, and they told the investigators that the area was not sacred; on the contrary, it was considered windy, barren, and worthless.</p><p>By far the most entertaining theory is that the party was attacked by a yeti. The final photograph found in Thibault-Brignoles’s camera has become famous: a dark figure advancing through the snowy forest, hunched and menacing, with no facial features. The Discovery Channel built an entire show, “Russian Yeti: The Killer Lives,” around the image. The skiers actually had been joking about yetis a few hours before they died. A spoof propaganda leaflet was found in the tent. Alongside such items as “Greeting the XXI Congress with increased birthrate among hikers” was the following: “Science: In recent years there has been a heated debate about the existence of the Yeti. Latest evidence indicates that the Yeti lives in the northern Urals, near Mount Otorten.” Still, the photograph, though blurry, pretty clearly shows a member of the group. Similarly, the Krivonishchenko image of streaks of light, which has been used to bolster the U.F.O. and weapons-test theories, is typical of the end of a film roll.</p><p>All the Dyatlov theories share a basic assumption that the full story has not been told. In a place where information has been as tightly controlled as in the former Soviet Union, mistrust of official narratives is natural, and nothing in the record can explain why people would leave a tent undressed, in near-suicidal fashion. For decades, the families and the Dyatlov Group Memorial Foundation pressed for a new investigation; two years ago, elderly relatives of several victims finally succeeded in getting the case reopened.</p><p>A young prosecutor in Yekaterinburg, Andrei Kuryakov, was put in charge. In 2019, he organized a winter expedition to the site. His team took measurements, surveyed, photographed, and conducted a variety of experiments. Using photogrammetry of the pictures taken in 1959, they tried to establish the precise location of the tent. The spot they settled on was several hundred feet from a cairn marking the previously accepted location, on a steeper section of Kholat Syakhl’s slope. Combing through historical data, the investigators determined that weather conditions on the mountain that night were even more extreme than had been thought. The skiers were engulfed in a storm with winds of up to sixty-five miles an hour and temperatures around minus thirty degrees Fahrenheit. As evening fell, they were probably unsure of their precise location.</p><p>From the outset, Kuryakov adopted an intentionally narrow scope, dismissing seventy-two of the seventy-five explanations for what may have happened. “A large class of these seventy-five versions are conspiracy theories alleging that the authorities were somehow involved in the incident,” he said, when announcing the investigation. “We have already proved that this is absolutely false.” This left the investigation with three natural occurrences to consider: an avalanche, a hurricane, and a slab of snow sliding over the tent. Last July, Kuryakov held a televised press conference in which he told his audience that the last of these was the definitive explanation.</p><p>Two photographs taken by the Dyatlov party at around 5 p.m., while they pitched the tent, show that they cut deeply into the snowpack at right angles to the slope, forming a hollow. They had picked a spot where the mountain peak offered some shelter from the strongest winds. Later in the evening, Kuryakov said, a snow slab detached from the slope above and buried most of the tent, pinning down the occupants and possibly causing injuries. Fearing that a full-scale avalanche was imminent, the skiers cut their way out of the downslope side of the tent and fled to a rock ridge a hundred and fifty feet away, which Kuryakov termed a “natural avalanche limiter.” But the big avalanche didn’t come, and, in pitch darkness, they were unable to find their way back to the tent and took shelter in the woods, a mile away. Kuryakov tested this theory by blindfolding a man and a woman and leading them ninety feet downhill from a tent. Asked to find their way back, they quickly went astray. The task would have been even more difficult in a blizzard, with most of the tent buried in snow.</p><p>Analyzing 1959 photographs, many Dyatlov researchers had calculated that the tent was pitched on a slope of some fifteen degrees, which is not steep enough to sustain the movement of snow in cold conditions. The new position of the tent as determined by Kuryakov’s topographical experts was therefore crucial, because the gradient here was between twenty-three and twenty-six degrees, enough for avalanche formation. A paper corroborating much of Kuryakov’s explanation was published in January by two Swiss engineers in the journal Communications Earth &amp; Environment. Creating a mathematical model of the snow structure that night, the researchers showed why the slab didn’t release immediately when the group cut into it, but only hours later: additional loading of snow during the storm was responsible.</p><p>I reviewed the hypothesis with Ethan Greene, the director of the Colorado Avalanche Information Center, who has a Ph.D. in the physics of heat and mass transfer in snow. He suggested that the party’s decision to pitch the tent in the wind shadow of the peak made it likely that they were cutting into a so-called wind slab—an accumulation of hard snow even more dangerous than a typical snow slab. Compacted by the wind, this kind of snow is several times denser than directly deposited snow and, according to Greene, can weigh as much as six hundred and seventy pounds per cubic yard. Furthermore, the clear conditions preceding the storm could have led to the formation of a layer of light, feathery frost, known as surface hoar. When buried in fresh snow during the storm, this layer forms a hazardous stratum that provides poor support to the snow above and often releases, resulting in avalanches. By removing the support on the lower edge of the slab while digging to set their tent, the skiers likely caused it to fracture higher up.</p><p>If the wind slab had simply slid over the tent and halted, without developing into a full-fledged avalanche, the evidence, Greene said, might not be visible twenty-five days later. Even the fissure in the snowpack would probably have been erased by the elements. If a three-foot-thick slab moved over the tent, each skier’s body would have been covered by more than a thousand pounds. The massive weight prevented them from retrieving their boots or warm clothing and forced them to cut their way out of the downslope side of the tent.</p><p>The two Swiss researchers believe that the snow slab probably caused the terrible injuries to three of the skiers found at the snow den, but this remains unlikely, given the distance of those bodies from the tent. Kuryakov’s explanation was more ingenious. The nine skiers retreated downhill, taking shelter under the cedar tree and building a fire. Because the young trees nearby were icy and wet, someone climbed the cedar to break branches higher up—hence the skin and scraps of clothing found on the trunk. The fire they built, in these extreme conditions, was not enough to save them, however. The two most poorly dressed of the group died first. The burned skin on their bodies came from their desperate efforts to seek warmth from the fire. This would suggest that the piece of flesh Krivonishchenko bit from his finger was probably a result of the delirium that overtakes someone who’s dying of hypothermia, or perhaps from an attempt to test for sensation in a frostbitten hand.</p><p>The surviving skiers cut the clothes off their dead comrades and dressed themselves in the remnants. At some point, the group split up. Three skiers, including Dyatlov, tried to return to the tent and soon froze to death as they struggled uphill. The other four, who were better dressed, decided to build a snow den to shelter in overnight. They needed deep snow, which they found in a ravine a couple of hundred feet away. Unfortunately, the spot they picked lay above a stream, a tributary of the Lozva River. The stream, which never freezes, had hollowed out a deep icy tunnel, and the group’s digging caused its roof to collapse, throwing them onto the rocky streambed and burying them in ten to fifteen feet of snow. The pressure of tons of snow forcing them against the rocks caused the traumatic injuries found in this group. The gruesome facial damage—the missing tongue, eyes, and lip—probably resulted from scavenging by small animals and from decomposition.</p><p>Kuryakov’s reconstruction of events made a single plausible narrative out of previously mystifying anomalies. But what of the radiation? This detail, the most enigmatic of all, might be the easiest to explain. For one thing, the mantles used in camp lanterns at the time contained small amounts of the radioactive element thorium. Even more pertinent, the expedition took place less than two years after the world’s third-worst nuclear accident (after Chernobyl and Fukushima), which occurred at the Mayak nuclear complex, south of Sverdlovsk, in September of 1957. A tank of radioactive waste exploded and a radioactive plume some two hundred miles long—later named the East Urals Radioactive Trace—spread northward. Krivonishchenko had worked at the facility and helped with the cleanup, and another skier came from a village in the contaminated zone.</p><p>Kuryakov closed his press conference by declaring, “Formally, this is it. The case is closed.” Given how freighted the case is in Russia, this was too optimistic. For many people, nature alone cannot explain a tragedy of this magnitude; perpetrators must be identified and the state and its dark past invoked. Sure enough, the conclusions were greeted with scorn, especially by the families of the dead. The Dyatlov Group Memorial Foundation sent a letter to the Prosecutor General declaring that, in its view, the skiers’ deaths were caused by “the atmospheric release of a powerful toxic substance” when a secret weapons test went wrong. Natalia Varsegova, a Moscow journalist, who has covered the subject for many years, also rejected Kuryakov’s conclusions. “Two years ago I thought that the prosecutor Andrei Kuryakov really wanted to know the truth,” she wrote to me in an e-mail. “But now I doubt it. I don’t believe in an avalanche.” After the Swiss report came out, she published an article rejecting it as well. “These theoreticians’ conclusions are supported by mathematical calculations, formulas, and diagrams, but the local Mansi, numerous tourists, and organizers of snowmobile tours, who have never seen avalanches on this slope, are unlikely to agree with them.”</p><p>A month after the press conference, Kuryakov was reprimanded for holding it without authorization, and in October he was removed from his post. (The prosecutor’s office has claimed that he resigned, and he did not respond to requests for an interview.) Early this year, he was appointed a deputy minister of natural resources in the Sverdlovsk region, which is a major timber producer. As Kuntsevich wrote to me sarcastically, Kuryakov was shunted off to “felling trees.” Meanwhile, the Prosecutor General declined to be interviewed for this article, and his office has issued no official report. Kuntsevich believes that a report may never be released, even to the families. The foundation is now calling for yet another investigation. Any clarity that Kuryakov’s solution might have brought was quickly occluded amid an atmosphere of murk and mistrust.</p><p>The most appealing aspect of Kuryakov’s scenario is that the Dyatlov party’s actions no longer seem irrational. The snow slab, according to Greene, would probably have made loud cracks and rumbles as it fell across the tent, making an avalanche seem imminent. Kuryakov noted that although the skiers made an error in the placement of their tent, everything they did subsequently was textbook: they conducted an emergency evacuation to ground that would be safe from an avalanche, they took shelter in the woods, they started a fire, they dug a snow cave. Had they been less experienced, they might have remained near the tent, dug it out, and survived. But avalanches are by far the biggest risk in the mountains in winter, and the more experience you have, the more you fear them. The skiers’ expertise doomed them.</p><p>At the end of 1958, as the date of departure approached, Krivonishchenko wrote a letter to Dyatlov firming up various logistical matters, and he enclosed a poem addressing New Year’s greetings to the entire group:</p><blockquote><p>Here’s wishing you<br>Camps pitched on mounts afar,<br>Routes to hike over ranges untamed,</p><p>Packs that, as ever, rest lightly on your backs,<br>And weather that smiles upon your quest. . . .<br>And let your footprints<br>Trace winding tracks across the map of Russia.</p></blockquote><p>Today, the Dyatlov Pass is a popular hiking and tourist destination. Hundreds have visited Height 1079, and followed Dyatlov’s route on foot, snowmobile, or skis. People come from all over the world to see the place where the tent once stood, the streambed where bodies were found, and the cedar tree, its broken branches still visible. Others come to take measurements, photographs, and videos to support their pet theories. The windswept heights of Dead Mountain have become a site of pilgrimage. Long after their deaths, Dyatlov and his friends did indeed leave their footprints across the map of Russia.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;!-- MarkdownTOC --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-we-find-when-we-get-lost-in-proust&quot;&gt;What We Find When We Get Lost in Proust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#how-long-can-we-live&quot;&gt;How Long Can We Live?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#has-an-old-soviet-mystery-at-last-been-solved&quot;&gt;Has an Old Soviet Mystery at Last Been Solved?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- /MarkdownTOC --&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
    <category term="2021" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/2021/"/>
    
    <category term="翻" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%BF%BB/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>20210511-01 今日翻</title>
    <link href="https://swy7.github.io/2021/05/11/%E7%BF%BB/20210511-01/"/>
    <id>https://swy7.github.io/2021/05/11/%E7%BF%BB/20210511-01/</id>
    <published>2021-05-11T00:00:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-09T22:45:18.613Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<!-- MarkdownTOC --><ul><li><a href="#elon-musk%E2%80%99s-golden-age-of-tech-innovation-is-coming">Elon Musk’s Golden Age of Tech Innovation Is Coming</a></li><li><a href="#how-i-learned-to-cycle-like-a-dutchman">How I Learned to Cycle Like a Dutchman</a></li></ul><!-- /MarkdownTOC --><span id="more"></span><p><a id="elon-musk%E2%80%99s-golden-age-of-tech-innovation-is-coming"></a></p><h1 id="Elon-Musk’s-Golden-Age-of-Tech-Innovation-Is-Coming"><a href="#Elon-Musk’s-Golden-Age-of-Tech-Innovation-Is-Coming" class="headerlink" title="Elon Musk’s Golden Age of Tech Innovation Is Coming"></a>Elon Musk’s Golden Age of Tech Innovation Is Coming</h1><p>来源: <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2021-04-28/elon-musk-s-golden-age-of-tech-innovation-is-coming">https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2021-04-28/elon-musk-s-golden-age-of-tech-innovation-is-coming</a></p><p>Elon Musk opined on a podcast last year that “too many smart people go into finance and law.” In these professions, the thinking goes, people tinker around the edges of the economy. Technology, meanwhile, is remaking the economy.</p><p>For the young graduates going after a career in tech rather than pursuing a more traditional path, there’s scarcely been a better time in terms of the potential monetary reward. Joining a young startup could be a ticket to the next Snowflake Inc., Roblox Corp. or Airbnb Inc. — to name a few of the newly-public companies worth tens of billions. And after a series of major technological advancements over the last several months, there’s also a chance to realize that time-honored tech industry cliche: changing the world for the better.</p><p>Take tech companies’ role during the pandemic: E-commerce and food-delivery apps allowed vulnerable people to avoid infection. Videoconferencing and workplace collaboration apps enabled remote work and online schooling, while streaming services and videogames provided in-home entertainment. Most importantly, the rapid development of effective Covid-19 vaccines using new technology like mRNA saved lives and put us on the path to recovery.</p><p>All that’s laid the foundation for further progress. The focus on building digital services to cope with Covid-19 has led to significant advances in key technologies — such as cloud computing, artificial intelligence and semiconductors — that will enable the next wave of innovation. And the maturation of free open-source software tools is a boon for startups looking to develop products rapidly at a lower expense.</p><p>Investors are stepping up as well. According to Crunchbase, nearly $73 billion was invested in growth-stage North American startups during the March quarter, double the prior year. Simply put, there may never have been an easier or more fortuitous time to start a new technology company.</p><p>The tech industry is also going after thorny problems. Earlier this month, Microsoft Corp. bet $20 billion on the potential for artificial intelligence to dramatically improve the workplace with its purchase of Nuance Communications Inc. The software giant is looking to apply the voice-recognition pioneer’s early success in using AI to unburden doctors from tedious administrative paperwork to other industries beyond health care. Fortnite maker Epic Games Inc. raised $1 billion in fresh capital that may bring about something straight out of science fiction novels. The game publisher said the funds will go toward its goal of building the “Metaverse,” where people can play and socialize with one another in virtual worlds. And on Monday, Apple Inc. said it plans to spend tens of billions of dollars on the development of advanced semiconductors and 5G wireless technologies over the next five years.</p><p>Technological progress can have its downsides. There have been ethical hurdles with the use of facial recognition against minority groups, along with negative effects from algorithms that amplify polarizing content on social media. And not all these companies will succeed in their lofty aspirations. But I’m optimistic there will be breakthroughs, and that the potential contributions to society outweigh the costs. With the increasing inflow of talent and large amounts of capital going after such exciting ideas, we may be on the brink of a golden age for innovation. If even just a handful of these new ideas succeed, the future could be brighter than even Elon Musk’s brightest dreams.</p><p><a id="how-i-learned-to-cycle-like-a-dutchman"></a></p><h1 id="How-I-Learned-to-Cycle-Like-a-Dutchman"><a href="#How-I-Learned-to-Cycle-Like-a-Dutchman" class="headerlink" title="How I Learned to Cycle Like a Dutchman"></a>How I Learned to Cycle Like a Dutchman</h1><p>来源: <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/culture/personal-history/how-i-learned-to-cycle-like-a-dutchman?utm_campaign=falcon&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;mbid=social_twitter&amp;utm_social-type=owned&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_brand=tny">https://www.newyorker.com/culture/personal-history/how-i-learned-to-cycle-like-a-dutchman?utm_campaign=falcon&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;mbid=social_twitter&amp;utm_social-type=owned&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_brand=tny</a></p><p>“where are our helmets?” my daughter Harper asked. We were standing outside a cycle shop in the Dutch city of Delft, along with Harper’s older sister, Lyra, and my wife, Alia.</p><p>“We didn’t buy any,” I replied. Along the dark green Wijnhaven canal, confident Dutchmen and Dutchwomen whizzed around, their blond heads exposed to the soft northern sun. “In the Netherlands, only tourists wear helmets.”</p><p>“What if we get in a crash?” Lyra asked.</p><p>“We won’t,” I said. “O.K., now, let’s line up—oop!” A Dutchman in a sleek blue suit, riding a sleek blue bike, was swerving around me from the south. Another rider, approaching from the north, rang her bell to remind me that I was blocking traffic. “Everyone, get on,” I commanded, but nobody did. Small traffic jams were developing on either side of our uncertain foursome. “Let’s maybe walk our bikes to a less busy street,” I said. We wheeled our way across a bridge into the Markt square, where the primary obstacle was an Italian tour group.</p><p>It was April of 2017. We were to live in Delft for three months, and our canalside apartment, on a street named Hippolytusbuurt, was within riding distance of the grocery, the bakery, the girls’ school, the library, the ikea. Back home, in Virginia, our lives had been a blur of traffic, from drop-offs at soccer practice to hectic commutes. While our family was in Holland, Alia and I decided, we would take a break from driving cars. Cycling was the norm in the Netherlands, and fulfilled the dream of every American rider who wished she could rule the road. It was a country with more bikes than people, and we were eager to slip into the two-wheeled flow.</p><p>At the cycle shop, we’d bought used bikes for the adults and new but cheap ones for the kids. In the Dutch style, they weren’t mountain or racing bikes but city cruisers, meant to be ridden perfectly upright, your back as straight as a marching soldier’s. An employee had attached brightly colored milk crates to the back of each bike, so that we could carry baguettes, or whatever. I secured an agreement from the manager that he would buy back the bikes upon our departure, that July. I’d have been satisfied with a handshake, but the manager, being Dutch, had drafted a three-sentence contract, which we both signed in duplicate.</p><p>Alia took out her phone, opened Google Maps, and pointed to a lake just east of the city. “I thought we could ride out here and see what we see,” she said.</p><p>“Can we get a snack?” Harper asked.</p><p>“I am sure we will get a snack.”</p><p>And so we set off, with varying levels of feigned confidence, down the brick streets of Delft, the uneven surface making our wheels jostle. Every few turns of the pedals, I’d ride past a single brick that was painted the elegant blue-and-white of Delftware. As we crossed a canal on a high stone bridge, four boys zoomed past, each with a girlfriend perched sidesaddle atop his back wheel; they were followed, like a punch line, by a girl, pedalling hard, with a boyfriend sitting pertly atop hers.</p><p>We rode past the Oude Kerk, whose steeple, from the fourteenth century, leans at a pitch greater than that of Pisa’s tower. To our right was a wall of narrow three- and four-story apartment buildings, each with a business on the ground floor. To our left was the seven-hundred-year-old Oude Delft canal, its still surface covered with lily pads and floating trash. There was no protective guardrail or fence, not even a curb—just an unnerving, cliff-like drop. I kept imagining myself zooming off the edge, “Thelma &amp; Louise”–style, and into the dark water.</p><p>Alia led the way, with Lyra, then eleven, and Harper, then nine, in the middle, and me covering our rear. “Try to stay to the right,” I called ahead, as faster bikers passed on our left. When a hatchback zipped past us, mere inches from our bikes, Lyra shouted, “That car almost hit me!” After another car came uncomfortably close, she cried, “I don’t like this! Why aren’t we wearing helmets?”</p><p>There’s a gesture I make when I’m biking in the United States that, to me, encapsulates the status cyclists have in this country. Whenever I reach an intersection with a car approaching, I slow down to make sure I won’t be hit, and, even when I have the legal right of way—on a bike path, or when the car has a yield sign—I acknowledge a driver’s stopping with a little half-wave. Thank you for obeying the law and not killing me, I am saying.</p><p>Even in optimistic American municipalities that have demarcated bike lanes on the street or paved a few bike paths, cars come first, and drivers rarely look out for cyclists. Drivers park and then swing their front doors wide; they make right turns without looking behind them; they pull out of parking lots and cut across bike lanes at full speed. Who can blame them? The system was built to maximize drivers’ efficiency, and anything that might slow them down is a glitch.</p><p>For cyclists used to being second-class citizens, watching bikes navigate the Netherlands is revelatory. It’s not just that Dutch train stations all house massive underground bicycle garages, with thousands of bicycles, or fietsen, locked up on tiered racks. It’s not just that every busy street has a handsome bike lane, paved in dark-red brick. It’s that on Dutch streets, bikes rule the road. They take priority in design and traffic flow. Traffic circles are laid out so that cyclists need never stop for cars. Busy intersections often have overpasses or underpasses, so that cyclists never have to slow down.</p><p>Most important, drivers look out for cyclists, cede the right of way, and are rarely surprised by them. After all, nearly all those drivers are cyclists themselves. The eighteen million residents of the Netherlands own, in total, more than twenty-two million bicycles. Dutch kids ride in child seats practically from birth, are on balance bikes by two, and are cycling unaided by four. Old people continue to cycle, too: when pedalling gets too difficult, they switch to battery-assisted e-bikes, which now outsell standard adult bikes in the Netherlands.</p><p>When you’re biking on a Dutch street, the person next to you in a Renault Clio is driving today only because she broke her arm or has to cart furniture home from the store. Most days, she’d be biking next to you, unprotected from cars except by custom, respect, and the forethought that comes from being able to think like a cyclist. In the Netherlands, drivers don’t turn right without checking their blind spots. They don’t park in bike lanes, not even just for a minute, to drop something off. And no Dutch cyclist ever half-waves at a driver for making a required stop—they assume that drivers will see them and obey the law.</p><p>Even if something goes wrong, a biker will still likely emerge unscathed. Dutch transportation designers strive to create what Wim Bot, an official in the Dutch cyclist’s union, calls “forgiving infrastructure”—systems that allow users to make errors without causing a crash. Studies have demonstrated that when a car hits a cyclist at speeds in excess of thirty kilometres per hour the cyclist is not likely to survive. Therefore, Bot told me, “thirty kilometres is the maximum speed in every living area in the Netherlands.” This consistent speed limit means that “it’s safe to have shared space between users of different forms of mobility.” Even though nobody wears bike helmets in the Netherlands, the fatality rate there is six times smaller than that of the United States.</p><p>I learned these statistics soon after arriving in Delft, but I couldn’t quite make myself believe them. I kept stopping for cars and, yes, half-waving at intersections, even as the gesture began to feel obsequious. I couldn’t shake my American cycling deference. Meanwhile, impatient Dutch riders stacked up behind me, screeching to a halt on their worn brakes when I slowed unexpectedly—and, in their view, unnecessarily. Once, as I cautiously picked my way through a roundabout, I was passed on the left by an exasperated preschool teacher pedalling a kind of bike bus—eight kids lined up ahead of her, in rows of two. Their little unhelmeted heads turned to watch me as they went by.</p><p>On busy modern streets with bike lanes, my family’s tentativeness was annoying but not catastrophic. But in the old city center, with its narrow brick streets, steep canal bridges, and crowds of pedestrians, we kept causing accidents. The girls failed to get out of the way of an oncoming university student, sending him, careening and cursing, into an alley. In front of our apartment, Lyra mounted her bike, wobbled, and collided with another cyclist, an elderly Dutchman. They both toppled slowly onto the bricks. Lyra looked outraged at first, then terrified when she saw how old the other party was, wool scarf and all. All four of us apologized over and over; the gentleman silently helped Lyra up, brushed himself off, and rode away.</p><p>But we kept at it. Harper and Lyra rode to school every day, three and a half kilometres each way. The first time that they had to make the journey on a cold, wet morning, their faces sagged when we held out their raincoats. It wasn’t as if we were punishing them or anything; we didn’t have a car! When they begged us to bike with them, Alia asked, “Why would we do that? We don’t want to get wet.”</p><p>“We don’t, either,” the girls protested.</p><p>“Oh, well!” Alia said, brightly.</p><p>After a few round trips, they mostly mastered their daily ride. But I struggled to navigate complicated traffic situations in the old city. Keeping track of all the other bikes, cars, mopeds, and pedestrians—all moving in different directions, at different speeds—seemed to exceed my processing power.</p><p>Why were the Dutch so much more comfortable on a street that I saw as filled with dangers? As with so many aspects of their society, it seemed to depend on subsuming the needs of the individual to the needs of the community. “If you are not able to anticipate what other people will do, you will have lots of small accidents, or near accidents,” Bot told me, in a café down the street from our apartment. “You must be communicating with your eyes to the other riders in the street. Your decisions must be based on what is best for the flow of traffic, not what is best for your trip in particular.”</p><p>Bot went on, “Think of it this way. Car drivers behave like a bunch of geese. They have the same distance from each other and fly at the same speed, and move almost in military formation.” He put down his tea and made a series of regimented gestures with his hands. Then he moved them around together, in an elegant dance. “Cyclists move like a swarm of sparrows,” he said. “There are thousands of them moving in chaos, but there are no collisions. They turn a little bit; they change their speed. You must do the same.”</p><p>Angela van der Kloof, a cycling expert and project leader with the Delft mobility consultancy Mobycon, told me, “From a young age in the Netherlands, we’re trained to take note of others. Not by a teacher but by the way we do things. I think we are very much used to physical negotiation.” Dutch people live in small houses, ride on crowded trains, and generally jostle against one another—the Netherlands has the sixteenth-highest population density in the world. Navigating complicated traffic situations, calmly and systematically, came naturally to our neighbors.</p><p>I had assumed that Dutch people’s adeptness at biking was the result of generations of incessant cycling. In fact, after the Second World War, the Netherlands had, like the U.S., become dominated by cars. Cycling paths were overtaken by roads, and neighborhoods in Amsterdam were razed to make room for highways. Between 1950 and 1970, the number of cars in the country exploded from about a hundred thousand to nearly two and a half million. During that same period, bike use plummeted; in Amsterdam, the percentage of trips made by bike fell from eighty to twenty.</p><p>With cars came carnage. In 1971 alone, thirty-three hundred people—including more than four hundred children—were killed on Dutch roads. A number of organizations, including a group named Stop de Kindermoord, or Stop the Child Murder, began agitating to take the streets back from automobiles. In one memorable protest, sixty riders on Dutch cargo bikes, or bakfiets, converged on Amsterdam’s city center at rush hour and pedalled as slowly as possible, in order to drive drivers crazy. As Pete Jordan chronicles in his book “In the City of Bikes,” from 2013, two drivers intentionally struck protesters with their cars, and fights broke out. “To contain the conflict, riot police arrived in armored vans, and regular police arrived on motorcycles with sidecars,” he writes. “The demonstrators actually welcomed the presence of the police, since the additional vehicles helped to ensnarl traffic.”</p><p>While some of the activist organizations were led by young men, Stop de Kindermoord was the project of mothers, many of whom wished to use cycles in their daily life but felt that car traffic made doing so unsafe. “Women’s mobility and men’s mobility typically are different,” van der Kloof, the cycling expert, said. “Women have shorter trips, multiple trips, oftentimes accompanied by children. That’s why I think especially women were so interested in this.” As groups such as Stop de Kindermoord gained in prominence, local municipalities began experimenting with restricting cars on certain days or in certain areas. In the late seventies, the global energy crisis offered further justification for emphasizing cycling over driving.</p><p>Cycling activists successfully ran for office, and citizens pressured officials in Dutch cities to scrap plans for expanding automobile access. In Delft, a major bridge into town from the south had been built, and planners had approved the construction of a multilane road that would carve through the old city, all the way to the Markt square. “Just in time, those plans were abandoned,” Wim Bot said. Only the bridge remains. Instead, Delft was made more inhospitable to cars; these days, a driver can battle his way toward the center of the old city, creeping through narrow one-way streets and swarms of cyclists and pedestrians. But it is impossible to drive all the way from one side of Delft to the other: to cross the city, you must ride.</p><p>I did my best. I couldn’t be lean and blond, but I could bike as if I were. I could ride tall in the saddle, with the self-possession of a Dutchman with sharp, visible cheekbones. “The road was built for me, too,” I told myself, repeating it like a mantra.</p><p>After I picked a vector and owned it, made strong directional choices at intersections, and stopped riding in fear, I fit into the flow of Dutch traffic much better. Making eye contact with other riders and pedestrians, each of us using the other’s feedback to negotiate those individual interactions, solved encounters that previously would have paralyzed me.</p><p>I also stopped slowing down when cars approached, although I never quite got over the fear that this oncoming driver would be the one who didn’t see me. My mantra faltered. “In North America, if you want to bike, it’s like playing tennis,” van der Kloof mused. “You need a racquet, a ball, the right clothing, and a tennis court. Talking about biking, you need a bike, you need the right gear, and you need a bike lane.” But, as a Dutch person, she continued, she had never questioned her right to claim her share of public space. “In the Netherlands, we think of it as our space,” she said.</p><p>By the end of our stay in Holland, cycling had become something we did with the ease I’d dreamed of. Once, in a light rain, I biked ten kilometres to the Hague, with my phone strapped to my handlebars displaying Google Maps and five thousand dollars’ worth of my employer’s computer equipment in my basket. In a country where I’d once seen a guy riding one-handed while carrying a used television set in the other hand, I felt, at this moment, like I fit in.</p><p>Since returning home, I’ve made a conscious decision to ride differently on American streets. I pedal like a Dutchman: confidently, with no helmet, and taking up my fair share of the street. I’ve spent many an afternoon trundling along the quieter parts of my suburban neighborhood, a couple of cars lining up behind me as I approach an intersection. I enjoy playing big on the road, and making drivers recognize that I belong in that space just as much as they do. (If I’m lucky, none of them will hit me.)</p><p>I think a lot about the ride that I took with the girls to their school in Delft, on the last day before summer break. We biked out of the old city, past the train station and through the most magnificent traffic circle I’ve ever seen: a gigantic roundabout, at the Delflandplein, that capably handles bicycles, cars, express buses, and the tram to The Hague. It’s a masterpiece of boring urban design. Even though thousands of cars and bikes pass through the roundabout every day, there were zero crashes reported there between 2014 and 2017.</p><p>It was a beautiful, warm day, and we cruised confidently through the circle, my children in the lead. We had the right of way around the circle’s entire circumference. Cars waited patiently, reminded to be cautious by little painted triangles on the pavement and by their own roles as cyclists. As we completed the arc, we felt fleetingly assimilated—part of a smoothly operating machine that offers safety and satisfaction to each one of its cogs. We were fietsers.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;!-- MarkdownTOC --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#elon-musk%E2%80%99s-golden-age-of-tech-innovation-is-coming&quot;&gt;Elon Musk’s Golden Age of Tech Innovation Is Coming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#how-i-learned-to-cycle-like-a-dutchman&quot;&gt;How I Learned to Cycle Like a Dutchman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- /MarkdownTOC --&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
    <category term="2021" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/2021/"/>
    
    <category term="翻" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%BF%BB/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>20210510 今日翻</title>
    <link href="https://swy7.github.io/2021/05/10/%E7%BF%BB/20210510/"/>
    <id>https://swy7.github.io/2021/05/10/%E7%BF%BB/20210510/</id>
    <published>2021-05-09T19:17:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-10T06:46:23.150Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<!-- MarkdownTOC --><ul><li><a href="#the-small-worlds-of-%E2%80%9Cabout-endlessness%E2%80%9D">The Small Worlds of “About Endlessness”</a></li><li><a href="#acts-of-kindness-prevent-a-downward-spiral-from-solitude-to-loneliness">Acts of kindness prevent a downward spiral from solitude to loneliness</a></li><li><a href="#can-we-escape-from-information-overload">Can we escape from information overload?</a></li><li><a href="#solitude-has-always-been-both-a-blessing-and-a-curse">Solitude has always been both a blessing and a curse</a></li><li><a href="#why-j-m-barrie-created-peter-pan">Why J. M. Barrie Created Peter Pan</a></li></ul><!-- /MarkdownTOC --><span id="more"></span><p><a id="the-small-worlds-of-%E2%80%9Cabout-endlessness%E2%80%9D"></a></p><h1 id="The-Small-Worlds-of-“About-Endlessness”"><a href="#The-Small-Worlds-of-“About-Endlessness”" class="headerlink" title="The Small Worlds of “About Endlessness”"></a>The Small Worlds of “About Endlessness”</h1><p>来源: <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2021/05/10/the-small-worlds-of-about-endlessness?mbid=social_twitter&amp;utm_social-type=owned&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_brand=tny&amp;utm_source=twitter">https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2021/05/10/the-small-worlds-of-about-endlessness?mbid=social_twitter&amp;utm_social-type=owned&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_brand=tny&amp;utm_source=twitter</a></p><p>A man sits alone at a table, in a restaurant, reading a newspaper. Beside him is a white-jacketed waiter, holding a bottle of red wine. The man tastes a little of the wine and nods. The waiter starts to pour and fails to stop. The wine brims over the top of the glass, like water in a fountain, and spreads across the tablecloth. The waiter mops at the spill with his napkin, to no avail. He could be a murderer, trying to wipe away his crime. Not a word is spoken. In voice-over, though, a nameless woman says, “I saw a man with his mind elsewhere.”</p><p> voice-over:画外音 mind elsewhere：心不在焉</p><p>That is a scene from “About Endlessness,” the latest—and, according to a rumor that one hopes will prove unfounded, the final—film from the Swedish director Roy Andersson. By my count, there are thirty-three such scenes; what worked for Beethoven, in the Diabelli Variations, is good enough for Andersson. He has referred to the movie as “a collection of short, short poems about existence,” like an eager bardic youth pressing his first, slim volume upon us, and “About Endlessness,” defying its own title, clocks in at a sprightly seventy-six minutes. Yet Andersson himself is now seventy-eight, and most of his characters proceed with painful caution, as if they were approaching a dental appointment or walking a pirate’s plank. Many of them prefer to stay still, waiting for God knows what.</p><p>Things were not always thus in Andersson’s created world. His début feature, “A Swedish Love Story” (1970), tracing the progress of an adolescent relationship, was governed by a modest social realism. Its charm brought the director a measure of success, which he then erased with the wholesale failure of “Giliap” (1975). At this point, he paused for thought, and his next full-length movie, “Songs from the Second Floor,” did not appear until the turn of the millennium. That’s a hell of a pause.</p><p>Andersson was far from idle during the hiatus. He made hundreds of commercials, which were lauded by <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-desk/the-immortal-world-of-ingmar-bergman">Ingmar Bergman</a>, no less, and which demonstrated the refining of an austerely funny style. Given Andersson’s predilection for misadventure, it’s no surprise that he was hired to promote an insurance company. His presence can be felt in stories that take twenty seconds to tell. When a green car, for example, stops at the side of a road, and the driver gets out, walking around to the hood but leaving his door open, it is only natural that a passing truck will shear the door off, like a falcon ripping the wing from a dove. Note, again, the lack of speech; neither shouting nor cursing, the innocent man merely stares at the small disaster as if he had seen it coming. Note, too, the unexplained set of antlers strapped to the roof of his car. As the silent comedians knew, and as insurance agents tend to forget, experience can overshoot the strange.</p><p>Andersson returned to feature films in rigorous command of his art. Since then, each of his movies has been made up of miniature fables, some of them as curt as commercials. His angle of vision has been singular and fixed—literally so, with a camera that refuses to budge. Most of his characters are played by ordinary folk whom Andersson spotted around town and invited to perform, however fleetingly, onscreen. Many of them have whitened faces, as if they’d been dusted with flour. Are we meant to think of Marcel Marceau, perhaps, or of Harry Langdon, whose milky and babyish features made him a star of the nineteen-twenties? Or could the dust be ash, akin to the penitential mark that some Christians wear on their brows on Ash Wednesday? The prevailing air is one of befuddled sorriness, and the epigraph to “Songs from the Second Floor” is a line from the Peruvian poet César Vallejo: “Beloved be the ones who sit down.” Only Andersson, the doyen of inaction movies, could offer beatitudes to the ineffectual and the zonked.</p><p>“Songs from the Second Floor,” “You, the Living” (2007), and “A Pigeon Sat on a Branch Reflecting on Existence” (2014) are informally known as the “Living” trilogy—as opposed to the Corleone saga, say, which is known as the “Shooting, Garroting, and Poisoned Cannoli” trilogy. To some extent, “About Endlessness” departs from the trilogy, not least in the voice-over, which, as if rebuffing the rhapsodies in the Book of Revelation (“And I saw a new heaven and a new earth”), remarks without judgment on cruelty and tedium alike: “I saw a man begging for his life,” or, “I saw a woman who had problems with her shoe.”</p><p>In other respects, the new film keeps up the sad work. As before, we get a sequence of tableaux vivants in lieu of a plot. Inspect them closely, and loose links emerge. A man who gets blanked in broad daylight by an old schoolmate, near the start of the movie, returns more than an hour later, standing in his kitchen and <em>still</em> griping about the guy. We also have a recurring guest appearance by a priest, who has mislaid his faith. He is seen dragging a huge cross along a street, to shouts of “Crucify!” from a jeering mob; swigging Communion wine in the vestry while his parishioners kneel at the altar rail; and confessing to a doctor that he doubts the existence of God. “What’s there to believe in, then?” the priest asks. The doctor’s reply is unimprovable. “Damned if I know,” he says.</p><p>There is a fine documentary about Andersson, titled “Being a Human Person” (2020). It is directed by Fred Scott, and centers on the making of “About Endlessness.” Here we see Andersson as the lord of his domain—his production studios, on an unassuming street in Stockholm. The figure he cuts is that of a homely Dumbledore, mostly in jeans and checked shirt, moving gingerly, patiently deploying his magic, and frequently melting into laughter. At one point, production lurches to a halt as Andersson enters rehab. (Behind him, in the words of a loyal colleague, lie “thirty years of heavy drinking.”) Flashbacks to his earlier self show a lithe young fellow whom we barely recognize.</p><p>For the crafting of every tableau, within the studios, a set is designed, constructed, and, after use, destroyed. No external filming takes place; even the grandest episodes, such as a defeated army trudging across a snowscape, are fashioned indoors. Panels of board, bearing architectural details, are hung between the camera and the backdrop in order to feed the illusion of deep perspective. You may not realize, as a woman alights from a train—gazing around her, expecting to be greeted—that the train is not the real thing, pulling out of a real station, but a model, drawn along the tracks by a length of twine, which is wrapped around the spinning bit of a regular household drill. Simple.</p><p>Not that Andersson is averse to digital sleights of hand. Twice in the new movie, we watch a couple floating through the sky and clutching each other tight. As Scott’s documentary makes plain, they were filmed against a green screen. No less important than the technical trick, though, is the echo of Chagall—specifically, of his painting “Over the Town,” in which he and his wife, likewise, are aloft. The difference is that, whereas Chagall soars over Vitebsk, precisely recalled from his childhood, what lies beneath the drifters in “About Endlessness” is the city of Cologne, ravaged by wartime bombing. Moreover, while the painting glows with accents of blue, green, and red, Andersson’s palette, as so often, is limited to washed-out duns and grays.</p><p>Is there a downside to this visual manner, forthright and coherent as it is? At the risk of heresy, I’d suggest that the light with which so much of Andersson’s work is suffused—pale, sifted, and flattening—can sometimes verge on monotony and sink the soul. (Compare the sharp and crystalline atmosphere that Bergman, his fellow-Swede, conjured up when he ventured out of doors, especially in his bracing early films.) The constant near-avoidance of despair is a delicate trade, and Andersson’s sense of direction is not unerring. I wasn’t entirely swayed by the sudden arrival of Adolf Hitler in “About Endlessness,” even if the Führer is at his wits’ end, or, in Andersson’s previous film, by the running gag about two salesmen, one of them permanently on the brink of tears, who were dead set on hawking joke toys—vampire teeth, “laugh bags,” and so on. In truth, the mixing of the mournful and the clownish is a stale trope. Didn’t <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/culture/richard-brody/charlie-chaplins-scandalous-life-and-boundless-artistry">Chaplin</a>’s “Limelight” (1952) lay it to rest?</p><p>Yet Andersson has earned our lasting gratitude. Few living directors beget work that carries so clear and so immediate a signature. There is nothing unfinished about his fragments, and no one else could have summoned the precarious beauty of the moment, in “About Endlessness,” at which the patrons of a bar regard the snow falling softly outside, to the sound of “Silent Night,” and one of them exclaims, in lonely joy, “Isn’t it fantastic?” Indeed. You could argue that a little of this goes a long way, but that’s the point. An Andersson movie is a gallery of littles, each of them going a very long way. The new film ends with another green car by the roadside—broken down, in the middle of nowhere. Once more, the driver doesn’t complain; why rage against the gods? Instead, in his abandonment, he listens to the birdsong all around. Overhead, into the painted yonder, a skein of geese glides by. Hopelessness, like endlessness, can be the bringer of peace.</p><p><a id="acts-of-kindness-prevent-a-downward-spiral-from-solitude-to-loneliness"></a></p><h1 id="Acts-of-kindness-prevent-a-downward-spiral-from-solitude-to-loneliness"><a href="#Acts-of-kindness-prevent-a-downward-spiral-from-solitude-to-loneliness" class="headerlink" title="Acts of kindness prevent a downward spiral from solitude to loneliness"></a>Acts of kindness prevent a downward spiral from solitude to loneliness</h1><p>LONELINESS IS BAD for your health—certainly as bad as being obese, and possibly as bad as being a moderate smoker. So, in these days of plague, when enforced solitude is the order of the day in many places, how to stop solitude turning into loneliness is a pressing medical question.</p><p>One part of the answer is to try to understand the physiology of the change. And that has, for the past few years, been the objective of Steven Cole of the University of California, Los Angeles. Dr Cole began his work with a study he published in 2015, in collaboration with John Cacioppo of the University of Chicago. The pair led a team of psychologists, neuroscientists and immunologists who found that the pattern in people’s blood of immune cells called myeloid cells is notably different in those who score as “very lonely” on loneliness tests compared with those who do not.</p><p>Lonely people have unusually low numbers of a type of myeloid cell that generates what are known as interferon responses, which hamper viral replication. This makes them particularly vulnerable to viral infections. They also have an abundance of a second type of myeloid cell, one that promotes the activity of genes which drive inflammation—and it has been known for years that those who feel lonely experience more inflammation than those who do not.</p><p>These correlations are intriguing, but do not explain which comes first, the loneliness or the myeloid response. Dr Cole and Dr Cacioppo addressed that question by repeatedly measuring perceptions of social isolation in individual volunteers, while simultaneously tracking, from blood samples, their gene-expression patterns and other changes in their physiology. They found that, initially, volunteers’ feelings of isolation coincided with an increase in their inflammation genes’ activity and a concomitant increase in the circulation of immature immune cells, called monocytes, that are involved in inflammation—and which are also known to travel into the brain and promote anxiety. They noted, too, increased levels in the brain of signalling molecules associated with both inflammation and behaviours such as social withdrawal, feelings of suspicion towards the outside world and a tendency to act more defensively by making decisions that involve few risks. That, of course, promotes further feelings of loneliness. Which, in turn, trigger a further myeloid response. And so on.</p><p>It seems, therefore, that though loneliness starts with solitude, it can quickly take on a physiological life of its own. Dr Cole thus worries that the enforced isolation, brought about by current circumstances, of those who are already living alone may create in many people a state of chronic loneliness that is difficult to escape from when things start returning to normal.</p><p>Dealing with this will not be a simple matter of allowing people to socialise once again. Because the myeloid feedback loop makes those affected more defensive and suspicious, the mere presence of others is not enough to restore the status quo. Something else is needed, too.</p><p>In search of that something Dr Cole carried out—this time in collaboration with Sonja Lyubomirsky, a psychologist at the University of California, Riverside—a series of experiments that encouraged healthy people to direct simple acts of kindness towards their fellow creatures: things like running an errand for an elderly neighbour or helping a colleague with a computer problem. Participants had their blood drawn in order to examine their myeloid responses. Those directed to show kindness to others on a weekly basis had precisely the opposite gene-expression activity to that previously seen in the lonely by Dr Cole and Dr Cacioppo.</p><p>Dr Lyubomirsky now picked up the baton. In collaboration with Dr Cole and with Megan Fritz, a colleague at Riverside, she repeated the study, but with a twist. Instead of looking only at participants’ myeloid responses, she also asked them specific questions about loneliness.</p><p>As she and her colleagues reported to this year’s conference of the Society for Personality and Social Psychology, held in New Orleans in February, they found that in the case of loneliness, the saying about it being more blessed to give than to receive is true. Asking lonely people to perform acts of kindness to others significantly reduced the offerer’s feelings of loneliness, as well as the myeloid response that drives inflammation. Also, and perhaps portentously given the meeting’s timing, Dr Fritz and Dr Lyubomirsky reported the preliminary results of a second study. This compared the effect on a lonely person’s feelings of acts of kindness he or she performed face to face with those performed online: donating money to a gofundme effort, for example, or writing a thank-you note to a friend.</p><p>The study’s results suggest that online kindness has the same beneficial effect as the face-to-face variety. And that could help to address Dr Cole’s fears of a post-covid loneliness epidemic. No doubt (though this was beyond the scope of these studies) merely having contact with others while staying in isolation is beneficial to those at risk of loneliness. But asking lonely people to use those means to commit random acts of kindness to others might go beyond this, and be just what the doctor ordered.</p><p><a id="can-we-escape-from-information-overload"></a></p><h1 id="Can-we-escape-from-information-overload"><a href="#Can-we-escape-from-information-overload" class="headerlink" title="Can we escape from information overload?"></a>Can we escape from information overload?</h1><p>We live in an age of infinite scrolling and endless interruptions. So what happens when you switch off the lights? Tom Lamont finds out One day in December 2016 a 37-year-old British artist named Sam Winston equipped himself with a step-ladder, a pair of scissors, several rolls of black-out cloth and a huge supply of duct tape, and set about a project he had been considering for some time. Slight and bearded, with large grey-blue eyes, Winston had moved to London from Devon in the late 1990s. He supported himself through his 20s and 30s by teaching, doing illustrations for magazines and selling larger, freer-form artworks, many of them pencil-drawn, to collectors and museums. He had just collaborated on a children’s book with author Oliver Jeffers, and done his part to propel “Child of Books” up the bestseller lists. Grateful as he was for commercial success, Winston found he disliked corporate publishing. All the emails! He saw himself as a lead-smudged idealist, an artist-hermit at heart. He’d been troubled by nervous energy and stress since he was young, was an intermittent insomniac, had difficulty filtering noise and distractions in public spaces, and was someone who – like so many of us – increasingly relied on his phone and computer. So Winston decided to hole up for a few days. No screens. No sun. No visual stimulation of any kind. He was going to spend some time alone in the dark.</p><p>It took him hours, climbing up and down the ladder in his studio, to cover every last aperture and pinprick of inbound light. The studio, in a converted factory in east London, has large tenement windows and a sloped roof inlaid with skylights that were especially tricky to seal. By Winston’s conservative estimate he used 200 metres of duct tape before he was fully satisfied that here, at last, was darkness. He would sit in it, drawing with pencil and paper, doing yoga, snacking a bit, waiting to see if the dark had any sort of palliative effect.</p><p>The world in the 21st century is no more richly textured or exotic to touch than it used to be. It smells about the same and there are no new flavours. Not since the coming of factories, then aeroplanes, domestic appliances and motorways has there been a serious uptick in sound pollution. Yet the spill of information and distraction that comes at us by eye has grown and grown ceaselessly for two decades, without any sign of a halt or plateau. DM! Breaking-news! Inbox (1)! This is a time of the scrolling, bottomless visual, when bus stops and the curved walls of Tube platforms play video adverts and grandma’s face swims onto a smartphone to say hi. People watch Oscar-nominated movies while standing in queues, their devices held at waist height. A Netflix executive can quip, semi-seriously, that he covets the hours we sleep (hours in which we do not, currently, stream Netflix shows). Apple has put an extra screen on our wrists and Google retains quiet hope that we will eventually wear a screen inside our specs. Big news lands in 140 characters or less, ideally with a startling picture or piece of video, else it doesn’t register as big news.</p><p>Our brains tend to lean on the visual, heavily prioritising sight over the other four senses. Ever since we climbed on to two feet as a species, taking our noses farther from the aroma-rich savannah floor, we have been wired to be seeing creatures and for better or worse we usually experience the what’s-next-what’s-next of this world through our peepers. As an artist, Sam Winston was often on the lookout for topsy-turvy projects – weird, sidelong ways to unmoor familiar habits or nudge his work in new directions. He wanted to know what would happen, to him and to his work, if he hid away from the ocular blitz for a while.</p><p>Now, working and sleeping in his blacked-out studio, he began to notice new things. Without sunlight as a guide, the day’s rhythms came via aural clues he had been only dimly aware of before: the cessation of London’s air traffic overnight, or the sound of idling vehicles as they took fractionally longer to move off from traffic lights during rush hour. When he brewed cups of rooibos in a rote-remembered action at his tea station he noticed that he could hear the difference between hot and cold liquids as he poured them. He began to see, he later told me, “how intelligent our senses are. And how we just drown them in the tsunami.”</p><p>Winston found that he was productive in the dark, too, drawing until his pencils were nubs and creating a series of huge sketches – broad-stroked in places or crowded with overlapping sentences in his crabby handwriting – that would later become part of an exhibition at the Southbank Centre in London. Between drawing jags he had vivid daydreams, even hallucinations, “as if my brain was a digital radio left on search, constantly searching for an available channel”.</p><p>Winston’s older brother had died, suddenly, the year before, and bereavement was another prompt for him to hole away in the dark. He had expected to use his time under seal to have profound thoughts about love and loss, to feel gratitude towards his girlfriend, a fellow artist, and his parents back in Devon. Instead a very different figure stalked the darkened landscape of Winston’s mind – one who was suited, lardy and omnipresent in the news after his recent election as president of the United States. Winston considered himself only a moderate news junkie, bombarded but not an addict. Yet here was Donald Trump, cavorting around his studio. It was as if, Winston felt, the news was something he’d over-indulged in, even overdosed on, a damaging substance that only now, in cold-turkey conditions, could swirl up out of him and be evacuated.</p><p>Winston emerged from the blacked-out studio before his food stocks ran out, around lunchtime on a Saturday. He’d been in there for six or seven days. The sun hurt his eyes. For a long time Winston watched train after train go by on the tracks outside his studio, relishing the everyday sights he’d been starved of, and at the same time trying to settle his insides. What he presumed to be a sudden dump of daylight-induced hormones made him feel faint. The next time he retreated into the dark, Winston resolved, he would try to come out after sunset for a gentler transition. Intrigued by the experiment, and suspecting there were greater depths he could go to, he had already decided there would be a next time.</p><p>Through 2017 and 2018 he made plans. He Googled bits and pieces of research. A pioneering experiment on sensory deprivation had been done at the University of Manitoba in Canada in the 1950s, during which hundreds of people were asked to remain alone in a sealed dark room for as long as they could bear. About a third of the subjects quit within days. At most they were in there a fortnight. If he went into the dark again, Winston wondered, could he manage a month? He Googled some more, and went shopping online, ordering more black-out cloth, more duct tape.</p><p>Information overload was a term coined in the mid-1960s by Bertram Gross, an American social scientist. In 1970 a writer called Alvin Toffler, who was known at the time as a dependable futurist – someone who prognosticated for a living – popularised the idea of information overload as part of a set of bleak predictions about eventual human dependence on technology. (Good call, Alvin.) Information overload can occur in man or machine, wrote another set of academics in a 1977 study, “when the amount of input to a system exceeds its processing capacity”. Then came VHS, home computers, the internet, mobile phones, mobile-phones-with-the-internet – and waves of anxiety that we might be reaching the limits of our capacity.</p><p>A study in 2011 found that on a typical day Americans were taking in five times as much information as they had done 25 years earlier – and this was before most people had bought smartphones. In 2019 a study by academics in Germany, Ireland and Denmark identified that humans’ attention span is shrinking, probably because of digital intrusion, but was manifesting itself both “online and offline”.</p><p>By that time an organisation called the Information Overload Research Group had done a study which estimated that hundreds of billions of dollars were being shucked away from the American economy every year, in miscellaneous productivity costs, by an overload of data. The group had been co-founded in 2007 by a computer engineer-turned-consultant, Nathan Zeldes, who had once been asked by Intel, a computer-chip maker, to reduce the burden of email imposed on its workers. By the end of 2019 Zeldes was ready to sound a note of defeat. “I’d love to give you a magic potion that would restore your attention span to that of your grandparents,” he wrote in a blog, “but I can’t. After over a decade of smartphone use and social media, the harm is probably irreversible.” He advised people to take up a hobby.</p><p>In an age of overload it can feel as though technology has rather chanced its luck. Pushed too much, too far, bone-deep. Even before coronavirus spread across the world, parts of the culture had started to tack towards isolation and deprivation as desirable lifestyle signifiers, hot-this-year, as if some time spent alone and without a device was the new season’s outfit, the next Cronut, another twerk.</p><p>Before a pandemic limited the appeal of wallowing in someone else’s tepid water, flotation-tank centres were opening all over London. In the Czech Republic there are spas that sell clients a week in the dark in shuttered, serviced suites. “Social distancing is underrated,” Edward Snowden tweeted, deadpan, in March 2020: a corona-joke, but one that will have spoken to the tech bros of Silicon Valley, for whom retreats were the treat of choice.</p><p>Recently, I saw that a person called Celine in San Francisco had tweeted to her 2,500-odd followers about the difficulty of “trying to date SF guys in between their week-long meditation retreats, Tahoe weekends, month-long remote work sessions…” About 4,000 people tapped to endorse the sentiment, launching Celine onto an exponential number of strangers’ screens, including my own. The default sound for any new tweet is a whistle, somewhere between a neighbourly “yoo-hoo” and a dog-walker’s call to heel.</p><p>Hilda Burke, a British psychotherapist who has written about smartphone addiction, told me that part of the problem in this age of overload is the yoo-hooing insistence with which each new parcel of information seeks our attention. Speakers chime. Pixelated columns shuffle urgently or icons bounce, as if to signal that here is the fire. Our twitch response to urgency is triggered, in bad faith.</p><p>When Celine’s tweet whistled onto my phone one idle Friday I couldn’t understand why I found it mildly stressful to read. Was it that it made me feel old? That I already had enough to think about? Eventually I realised that, for me, every tweet is a bit stressful. Every trifling, whistling update that comes at us, Burke said, “is like a sheep dressed in wolf’s clothing. The body springs to attention, ready to run or fight, and for nothing that’s worth it. This is confusing.”</p><p>In Sam Winston’s case the epiphany moment came when he realised just how much he was enjoying his hangovers after a night out. He lolled on the sofa. He didn’t feel “targeted by Twitter, Instagram, Facebook, all these services with algorithms that are intentionally designed to be as sexy and juicy and distracting as possible, to fire my synapses as often as they could. What’s that truism? ‘Protect me from what I want.’” He realised that he had a weird urge to be on something like a cruise ship for a month: “To experience a clear stop to it.”</p><p>During the summer of 2018 Winston worked to secure a location for his planned month in the dark. An acquaintance agreed to lend him a one-room guesthouse in the Lake District, asking only that, once the property had been thoroughly blacked-out with cloth and tape, Winston sign a waiver taking the blame for any catastrophe. He bought cupboard stores, frozen pies, an apocalypse-supply of bottled water. He arranged for a group of trusted people to call in by phone and make the occasional visit to check that, as one friend put it, “he wasn’t going full Norman Bates in there”.</p><p>Winston decided on a few more ground rules. He would do four weeks, going in on Monday at the start of October and coming out on a Sunday at the end. This would amount to 672 hours in seclusion. He would take voice notes on a Dictaphone and record less literal impressions in a series of pencil drawings.</p><p>In keeping with the maverick spirit of the effort he did not look deeply into the health risks. He did a bit of reading about melatonin and serotonin, hormones that are produced in the brain by the pea-sized pineal gland and which help the body to regulate its sleep-wake cycle. Winston figured he’d end up rather starved of serotonin, which is usually secreted during daylight hours and helps us to feel alert, but that he’d get an absolute bonanza of melatonin, a soporific. He didn’t consult a doctor, though he did quiz a Specsavers employee during a routine appointment. She said she didn’t know what to tell him.</p><p>Winston couldn’t resist a final tweet before he locked himself away: “No reception. No screen time. Drawing in darkness. See you in Nov.” On the last day of September he took a sunset walk in the fields surrounding the property, staring at hills and cows and in general trying to enjoy this last conventional use of his eyeballs. Then he went indoors and went to bed, killing the lights for the next 28 days.</p><p>He could handle the pitch-black mornings, having tried a shorter version of this experiment before. So when Winston awoke and got over the momentary panic – that, no, he had not lost his vision overnight – it was easy and agreeable to drift back into a dark-drugged second sleep. When he did get out of bed, feeling his way to the kitchenette and the fridge, breakfast took longer than usual to prepare and consume. All this contributed to a certain time-slippage. Even in those first few days he imagined he was up and under way on some morning activity, drawing at his work table, or doing yoga stretches on the carpet, only to receive a check-in call from his girlfriend, who let him know he was a few hours behind. Without a precise sense of time he surrendered again to the vaguer, lulling rhythms of something-like-morning, something-like-afternoon, something-like-evening, something-like-night.</p><p>It was quieter in the country guesthouse than it had been in the city studio. Winston’s ears had to tune in to more distant aural clues. Before long he realised he could tell the difference between day and night from the density of traffic noise on an A-road half a mile away. He went through other transitional stages he had experienced before, such as that weird prominence of news and current events as his psyche cleared its titbits and cookies, “the accumulated songs, the little thought eddies, a kaleidoscope of stuff”, as Winston remarked in a Dictaphone note on day five. A day later he recorded another note: “I’ve discovered it doesn’t matter which way you walk in the dark, forward or backwards, it makes no difference. Either way you can’t see anything. Quite good, walking backwards.”</p><p>With his vision suppressed, his other four senses were getting a chance to step up and show their stuff. It has long been accepted that people who can’t see may experience other sensory gains. With advancements in brain-scanning technology in the 1990s and 2000s, academics began to test our anecdotal understanding with empirical research. Their findings suggested that non-visual sensory enhancement happens quickly in the dark. Even 30 or 45 minutes after the lights plink off, our fingertips thrill with greater responsiveness and we seem to become markedly better at determining the direction of travel of sound. Research in this area is ongoing, and it excites scientists who specialise in the senses because it suggests the brain is more adaptable – more “plastic” in their terminology – than was previously thought.</p><p>Charles Spence of Oxford University’s department of experimental psychology talks about brain plasticity as if he’s a property magnate. “When the body is plunged into darkness”, he told me, “this huge visual part of the brain is no longer doing the stuff it normally does. That’s a lot of spare real estate and what you find is that, surprisingly quickly, the real estate is retooled or repurposed.” The other senses simply take it over. That the non-visual senses should commandeer brain space so quickly – within an hour, according to some studies – excites specialists such as Spence because it suggests that we are using latent connections instead of growing new ones, which would take longer to form. By turning off the lights, in other words, we aren’t necessarily enhancing the other senses, we’re just more inclined to heed what these other senses are already saying.</p><p>As he entered his second week in the dark, Winston spent ages running his fingers over common objects, the edges of things, surfaces, entertained and distracted by the minute textural details he could discern. He had been drawing in the dark. Now, whenever he picked up a pencil, he was sure he could intuit the density of a pencil’s lead from its vibrations on paper as well as “the acoustics of it, its energy across the page”. Certain tactile experiences came with exciting visual impressions. Washing was especially thrilling – “showers were Alton Towers” – as every drop of water seemed to conjure a corresponding drop of colour in Winston’s mind. When his girlfriend called him from a London bus, he found that he relished the humdrum noises in the background, the sound of commuters, the beeps. “It was like having a whole tv mini-series to think about afterwards.”</p><p>The refining of his other senses led to compromises and frustrations too. Winston could no longer get to sleep on sheets that had been washed in supermarket detergent because he found the fragrance so strong it made him gag. Foods he’d always liked turned disagreeable, particularly processed ones. There was an unforgettable afternoon with a McCoy. Winston was convinced he could now track the progress of the crisp’s saturated fat down his oesophagus. One day, troubled by indigestion, his brain conjured a frightening image of himself with a distended, bloated stomach. He started to eat less after that. Exercising, crying, masturbating less. As Winston prickled with a richer sort of sensory awareness, these basic physical activities wound down because he found them too dramatic, too weird, too much. He had come into the dark to escape, but this didn’t feel like much of one.</p><p>By the start of the third week, soggy with melatonin, Winston was spending more and more time on the sofa. He sunk in to memories. Daydreamed. Hallucinated. He saw landscapes drift past, mostly coastlines, shimmering seas. His hallucinations could be workaday and he found that his mind itched to redraw the guesthouse around him, plastered beige walls there, tiled kitchenette there…Then, after something as prosaic as that, he would see a cloud-filled sky. A star field.</p><p>If the bodily effects of the retreat were strange (psychedelic showers, the snake-like digestion of a crisp), then these were foothill experiences compared with the mental effects. In the aftermath Winston would have trouble putting the experiences into words and we would have long conversations trying to map where exactly he went in his head, trying to differentiate between day-time hallucinations and night-time dreams, sometimes falling back on the Dictaphone notes Winston had recorded in the dark.</p><p>He was amazed at the obscurity and reach of the memories that came to the fore, “these weird little air bubbles from the past that went ‘pop’.” As with Trump, the people who turned up to join him – sometimes hallucinated, sometimes felt only as spectral presences – were rarely those he expected. When he was 17, Winston had been a bit crap toward his first girlfriend. He hadn’t thought about her in decades and now she strode back in (hiya!) to join him in the black-out. It took Winston four or five days, wringing his hands, picking back through long-ago instances of infelicity, laziness, casual teenaged callousness, to retrieve a useful memory: she’d once written him a letter he hadn’t answered. “She was the first person who ever wrote to me and said, ‘I love you.’ And I turned around and said, ‘Whatevs, I’m over, doing this with somebody else.’ I missed it at the time, the intimacy and the tenderness of the moment. So there I am, 20 years later, in the dark – realising how incredibly selfish I’d been.”</p><p>The spectral girlfriend shimmered away. Afterwards, Winston found himself revisiting and replaying all kinds of bygone squabbles and misunderstandings. Pleasant moments too. He thought about his girlfriend a lot. He wondered why he had never asked her to marry him. He found he could wallow, a little more inquisitively, a little more sympathetically, in overwhelming emotional events that had rushed by at the time.</p><p>This was not always a good thing. Winston thought a lot about his brother, Ben, who had died. “Just fell over. He was 40. He had a wife and a young daughter. He was in the middle of his life. It wasn’t fucking fair.” When someone dies on you like that, Winston said, “there’s a rational bit of you that knows they’re dead. And there’s this irrational bit where you feel a bit like a bloodhound. You’re sniffing around going ‘Sorry, where have they gone?’” In the dark, with no morning or afternoon, the real and the imagined had vaguer edges and Winston started sniffing around more deliberately. “I had some experiences that were pretty far out to sea. A part of me thought, you know, ‘I’m gonna go and find Ben.’” This didn’t happen. There was no spiritual encounter, no satisfying reunion for Winston. Instead, during his scarier reveries on the guesthouse sofa, he started to doubt what he called “the binary here and not-here of death”. Winston even wondered once or twice if he’d died himself. He worried he might be going mad.</p><p>“When you turn off perception by going into darkness,” Charles Spence told me, “mental imagery has nothing to compete with. It becomes the most intense thing there is. Hence you start to see hallucinations, people confusing reality with their mental imagery, the mental image for the real.” A friend of Winston, Martin Aylward, who’d tried a week-long dark retreat himself, warned how noisy the experience could be. “Even if you spend a little time with yourself,” Aylward said, “you’ll notice how a voice chatters away in your head – the blah-blah-blah of the inner monologue. In the dark that can start to be extremely loud, extremely tiresome. And relentless.”</p><p>There had been moments, listening to Winston’s tales from the dark, that I wondered if we might all follow his lead and spend our own month under seal. In a fluorescent world, especially in these tense, locked-down times, mightn’t darkness be a sort of readily available cure-all? A potent, inexhaustible form of bedroom pharma?</p><p>Winston went into the dark for a month in a bid to escape the digital bell-chimes, the bouncing icons, the bulletins and info-blasts – our exhausting daily scroll. “But when you go into the dark for a long time,” Winston admitted to me, recently, “you’re not going into a void. You’re going into yourself. And good luck finding blissful empty quiet there.” There was nothing to compete with the loud, incessant inner monologue or drown it out. I wondered, then, whether we’d created and refined all our sparkly informational distractions because on some level we knew the relentlessness of the subconscious had the real power to overload.</p><p>By the start of the fourth week Winston had started to lose track of how much sleep he was getting. He was having dreams of such dazzling, 3D intensity that even months later it was hard for him to call them dreams. One morning towards the end, Winston woke up and recorded a raspy, panicked Dictaphone note: “Day 19… There was a bizarre little event. The Queen came to visit, and I was naked, and she was here already.” Around this time a friend drove to the guesthouse to look in on Winston. He answered the door in a blindfold, looking pale and gaunt. Talking slowly, maybe at two-thirds speed, he said he hadn’t been expecting anyone until the afternoon. “But it’s 5pm,” the friend said.</p><p>The real world, the one with garishly delineated mornings and afternoons, was creeping back to claim him. His girlfriend was due to arrive at the guesthouse a couple of days before the end, to help Winston adjust to human company again and ease the outward transition. He recorded a voice note: “So this is day, I think, 26? 27? She arrives in a couple of hours. Everything’s sped up. Everything’s got quite rush-y. Like, shit, I need to wipe down the surfaces or make the bed. None of it big. But it [still feels like] coming out of hyperspace.”</p><p>On day 28, just before dusk, his girlfriend helped him out of the guesthouse, leading him in a blindfold to the garden. Winston was gently hysterical, cackling and clapping, kneeling to touch the ground under his feet, stroking the bark of a tree and muttering, “Who made this?” When he gingerly removed his blindfold and used his sight for the first time in 672 hours he had to bow his head against the minimal glare. He stared at the horizon for a long time, and later explained what was going through his head: “the whole system rebooting…Like you’re being born, but this time with an adult head on…I remember I felt really innocent. Like those astronauts who look back on Earth and wonder how a war could ever happen, how we could all get so confused. [There was] a sense of the impending loss of that. I knew that before long I’d be back on the Central line, thinking that some stranger was an idiot for standing in the wrong place in the carriage.”</p><p>Before he lost that thinning sense of innocence, Winston wanted to capitalise on his experience. He dragged his girlfriend off on a walk and proposed to her. She said yes. Over the month away he’d lost weight and his pallid, almost puce-coloured skin had turned a raw burnished pink in the outdoor breeze. As long as she’d known Winston his eyes had been an unremarkable blue-grey. Now, when he removed his blindfold, she gasped. She rushed to take a picture. His eyes, after 28 days without anything to feast on, had turned a vivid baby blue.</p><p>Shortly afterwards, Winston put the quirky photograph of his brightened eyes on Twitter, for his followers to see. He logged in, uploaded the JPEG, appended a pert little message and pressed send, digital chores that signalled as surely as anything that he was back in the world.</p><p>One afternoon in January this year I met Winston by Regent’s Canal in east London. He had just taught an art class nearby and was due back at his studio, where admin awaited him. More than a year had passed since the end of his monkish retreat and his eyes had returned to their regular blue-grey. Winston was carrying a large satchel, over-stuffed with cardboard tubes and when I asked what was in them he said it was his students’ work. That afternoon he had led a class in which he encouraged them to put on blindfolds to draw.</p><p>He had become an advocate for making art in the dark. Winston’s retreat had left him with conflicting feelings, but he was convinced of one thing: that a blast of darkness, taken in moderation, was a powerful creative tool. The boiled-down pitch he’d been making to other artists was that by depriving yourself of visual stimulus, the mind had to leave its comfortable grooves. Originality resulted. He was pleased with the large swirling pencil drawings that he’d made in the dark and had plans to exhibit them at the Barbican in London and the National Centre for Writing in Norwich. Winston had commissioned poets and novelists to undertake dark retreats, and been satisfied to hear from them that the freeing effects of dark-working carried over into other forms of creativity.</p><p>On his computer there were tons of emails that needed answering about the dual shows. Inbox (200), Inbox (300). One of the most time-consuming tasks, Winston admitted, had been his efforts to persuade curators in London and Norwich to construct enclosed black-out spaces, so that visitors could try immersion in the dark themselves. An hour or two at most, Winston suggested. Not 672.</p><p>He said he wouldn’t recommend what he’d done to any-one. A year on, Winston had finally found his bearings again but it took him months, maybe six, to get his equilibrium back. For a long time he couldn’t stop noticing every little inbound impression. In a city as loud and smelly as London that was too much to tolerate. After the retreat he often felt glum, almost bereaved, because, for all its terrors, the dark could be addictive. He pined for another immersion. This disturbed him.</p><p>Back at the studio we met his girlfriend. As usual, to record our conversations, I laid my iPhone on the table, beside a fail-safe iPad. Behind us, the studio computer flicked to a screensaver, hiding email software that teemed with to-dos. Unwilling to face these, Winston fooled about with a cardboard tube instead, using it as a loud hailer to pester his girlfriend. “Why haven’t we got married yet?” he boomed.</p><p>She smiled and said: “I don’t know,” throwing Winston an ambiguous look that I took to mean, “Because you’re the kind of person who might vanish on a black-out jag at any moment.” Winston sighed. Things had seemed simpler with the lights off. “I wanted to know, ‘How did we all get so confused?’ Because I couldn’t see the confusion. Now I can’t see the simplicity.”</p><p>He sat at the computer. Typed a bit. He was restless. Did I want to try it, Winston asked, the dark? The sun was setting outside the tenement windows. We could sneak in a couple of hours before I had to go home, he reckoned. Excited as a boy getting out his stickers, Winston grabbed two blindfolds from a hook and started shoving furniture to the walls. His girlfriend excused herself. I agreed to try and do some writing while Winston meditated and snoozed on the sofa nearby. The poet George Szirtes had been so uneasy about the coming dark, Winston recalled, that he needed his hand held. Don Paterson, another poet, had admitted that what truly terrified him was the prospect of his own uninterrupted company. “I’ll just be over here,” Winston said to me. There was a click and the lights went off.</p><p>From the sound of the sofa’s miniature rustlings, I tried to visualise the positions Winston shifted through. Then I listened to the creaks of the building’s heating system and the more distant trains. Taking up a pencil I started to make the scratchy beginnings on this story (what would eventually become paragraph three). After half an hour, surely no more, I heard Winston stir. He removed his blindfold and checked the time. Two hours had passed. With some reluctance, I pulled myself out of a middle-place of pale colours, crisp sound and slower, sedate thought. I said goodbye to Winston and headed for the nearby station. An electronic message board above the platform said the next train was 15 minutes away: unacceptable. I texted home to complain about this. The board rotated through station names, security warnings, bromides about respectful travel. A man beside me watched the new Scorsese on his upturned phone.</p><p><a id="solitude-has-always-been-both-a-blessing-and-a-curse"></a></p><h1 id="Solitude-has-always-been-both-a-blessing-and-a-curse"><a href="#Solitude-has-always-been-both-a-blessing-and-a-curse" class="headerlink" title="Solitude has always been both a blessing and a curse"></a>Solitude has always been both a blessing and a curse</h1><p>IN HIS “POLITICS” Aristotle argued that, thanks to the gift of language, man is destined to be a social and therefore a political animal. Yet the human instinct to socialise has always been balanced by an urge to withdraw into solitude. A few hermits make their lives in isolation, but many ordinary folk believe society is only tolerable if punctuated by frequent spells on their own. “There are many modern thinkers who emphasise the individual’s dependency upon society,” John Cowper Powys, a British writer and advocate of solitude, observed. “It is, on the contrary, only the cultivation of interior solitude, among crowded lives, that makes society endurable.”</p><p>Historians are for the most part solitary creatures themselves—the sort of people who, at school, preferred reading to team sports and, as adults, desperately try to avoid committees in order to spend more time in the library. All the same, they generally focus on gregarious activities, whether politicians on manoeuvres or the masses on the march. Bucking that trend, a couple of fascinating books on social isolation have appeared in time for the lockdown. Fay Bound Alberti has tried her hand at a history of loneliness. David Vincent focuses on loneliness’s rather more interesting sibling, solitude. Both concentrate on late modern Britain, Ms Alberti because she argues, somewhat unpersuasively, that loneliness is a recent phenomenon, the product of industrialisation and secularisation; Mr Vincent because he has spent a lifetime studying the country’s modern social history. What Aristotle called the “bird which flies alone” is finally getting his due.</p><p>Medieval Christendom saw some extraordinary feats of solitude. In the late third century St Anthony spent years in the desert with only scorpions and beasts for company. St Jerome tried a similar feat but took a large library with him. St Simeon Stylites upped the ante by sitting on top of a pillar in order to be closer to heaven. (“The progress of an ulcer in his thigh might shorten, but it could not disturb, this celestial life,” Edward Gibbon wrote in a wonderful description of the saint, “and the patient Hermit expired, without descending from his column.”) Monasteries were refuges from the world that combined communal living with hours of solo prayer. Thomas Merton, a modern advocate of monasticism, claimed that “man’s loneliness is in fact the loneliness of God.”</p><p>The 18th and 19th centuries saw this cult of solitude reinvented in secular forms. Enlightenment philosophers argued that the key to a civilised life lay in mixing sociability and solitude in just the right doses: immerse yourself too deeply in urban life and you might become neurotic, but retreat for too long to the country and you might degenerate into a bearded barbarian. The Romantics thought the best way to create great art was to surround yourself with nature. John Clare began one poem: “O thou soothing Solitude/From the vain and from the rude”. William Wordsworth wandered “lonely as a cloud”. By taking long walks in remote places, such as the Lake District or the Alps, you could become what Robert Louis Stevenson later called “a pipe for any wind to play upon”.</p><p>The Romantics set off a lasting fashion for grappling with nature in the raw. In Britain intellectuals showed that scaling mountains and hiking long distances could connote brains as well as brawn (Leslie Stephen and G.M. Trevelyan thought nothing of walking from Cambridge to London for dinner). In America the march of civilisation generated a compensatory fascination with the wilderness. Henry David Thoreau retreated to Walden Pond. As a young man Teddy Roosevelt reinvented himself as a western cowboy by travelling around the Dakotas. As president he created National Parks to let ordinary Americans escape from the pressure of civilisation to a natural world of soaring peaks and wild animals. Many of the iconic images of 19th-century America capture a sense of solitude—the “lonesome cowboy” on cattle drives or the haunting sound of the train whistle in the middle of nowhere.</p><p>Lost in the crowd</p><p>As Mr Vincent says, industrial society brought a spate of solitary hobbies within reach by boosting living standards and enlarging personal space. Women with a little time on their hands took up pastimes that had once been necessities, such as cooking, dressmaking and embroidery. Men tried pigeon-breeding and stamp-collecting. People of both sexes took on jigsaw puzzles and, from the 1920s, crosswords. The cult of solitude also encouraged less healthy habits. Charles Kingsley, a subscriber to “muscular Christianity”, regarded tobacco as the ideal accompaniment to the solitary life—“a lone man’s companion, a bachelor’s friend, a hungry man’s food, a sad man’s cordial, a wakeful man’s sleep, and a chilly man’s fire”. Arthur Conan Doyle’s Sherlock Holmes preferred an opium pipe to ignite his solitary reveries.</p><p>Healthy or otherwise, these hobbies united a nation that was divided by class. Britain’s allotment movement meant that, by 1910, half a million working-class men could enjoy the pleasures of gardening. Such activities also married sociability with solitude. Smokers shared their solitary vice in dedicated rooms in clubs and pubs. Angling encouraged people to collaborate on being alone. “We may club together as against others, but by the water we divide,” Morley Roberts wrote in 1932. “When I fish I am the universe.”</p><p>Yet the more civilisation has advanced, the further people have had to go to achieve that sensation. Starting with Joshua Slocum in 1895, solo yachtsmen sailed around the world, sometimes cutting themselves off from all outside help. Robin Knox-Johnston, for example, didn’t talk to anyone for five months. Mountaineers competed with each other to slip the knot of civilisation. In 2017 Alex Honnold climbed El Capitan in Yosemite with neither companions nor crampons. These extraordinary battles against nature were inspired by the belief that the best way to explore body and soul is to strip the self to its essence. “It is here, in the immense desert of the Southern Ocean,” Bernard Moitessier wrote, “that I feel most strongly how much man is both atom and god.”</p><p>And the more sophisticated civilisation has become, the more people have been willing to use its fruits to escape the enforced sociability that has mostly been humanity’s lot. In 1900 just 5% of households comprised one person. Today a quarter do in America, along with a third in Britain and perhaps half in Sweden. Sometimes the solo life is a choice: people use their money to dump an unsatisfactory partner. Sometimes it is a tragedy: in Britain a million older people say they routinely suffer from loneliness. Most feel unable to admit their plight to friends and relatives.</p><p>This points to the paradox at the heart of solitude, which, as Mr Vincent says, can be both a blessing and a curse. Loneliness and solitude are not the same: you can feel lonely in a crowd—indeed loneliness is at its darkest when you are surrounded by people having fun—but they overlap. Unwanted solitude can lead to the most miserable sort of loneliness. “I’d like to meet,” C.S. Lewis wrote to a friend after his wife died, “for I am—Oh God that I were not—very free now. One doesn’t realise in early life that the price of freedom is loneliness. To be happy is to be tied.”</p><p>Even voluntary solitude can foster mental illness. In the early modern period John Evelyn warned that solitude “creates witches”. Samuel-Auguste Tissot feared it led to masturbation and all that masturbation entails, “melancholy, sighing, tears, palpitations, suffocations and faintings”. The first great book devoted to solitude, by George III’s personal doctor, Johann Georg Zimmerman, was titled “Solitude Considered with Respect to its Dangerous Influence Upon the Mind and Heart” (1791). Joseph Conrad condemns his character Nostromo to die of solitude, “the enemy known but to few on this Earth, and whom only the simplest of us are fit to withstand”.</p><p>Given its power to break the spirit, loneliness has inevitably been used as a punishment. Pentonville, Britain’s first model prison built on Utilitarian principles, confined all prisoners in solitary cells, though it dropped the face masks that, in Jeremy Bentham’s original design, they were supposed to wear to stop them communicating during meals. The most extreme use of solitary confinement was in a wing of a state prison in Auburn, New York, where inmates were confined in total solitude, with no exercise and no human contact of any kind. Gustave de Beaumont and Alexis de Tocqueville were appalled when they visited the place in 1833: “In order to reform them they have been submitted to complete isolation; but this absolute solitude, if nothing interrupt it, is beyond the strength of man; it destroys the criminal without intermission and without pity; it does not reform, it kills.”</p><p>Ms Alberti notes that anxiety over involuntary loneliness has become a big political issue, particularly in northern European and Anglo-Saxon countries, where the breakdown of the family has gone furthest. In 2016 the BBC released a television documentary on “the age of loneliness”. In 2017 Vivek Murthy, America’s former surgeon general, declared an “epidemic of loneliness”. In 2018 Theresa May appointed Britain’s first “minister for loneliness”, declaring that “up to a fifth of UK adults feel lonely most or all of the time.”</p><p>Life in the quiet carriage</p><p>The history of solitude is thus partly a history of extremes—of people who have willingly sat on top of pillars for decades and of prison reformers who aim to use loneliness to break men’s souls. But it is also a history of the quest for balance.</p><p>The healthiest form of solitude is a flexible kind that combines it with sociability as necessary. Modern technology has made it both easier and harder to get the balance right. On the one hand, it has introduced what Mr Vincent calls “networked solitude”. Just as St Jerome squatted in his cave surrounded by his library, so modern hermits can sit in their flats gorging on downloaded books and films or chatting with friends across the world. On the other hand, it has made it more difficult to enjoy the benefits of solitude. Distraction is always one click away. And the same technology that allows the solitary individual to engage remotely with society also allows society to engage remotely—and sometimes secretly—with the individual. Giant companies watch over you whether you are alone or in a crowd.</p><p>There is also something disturbing about the way the boundaries between solitude and sociability are blurring. Visit a gym and you see sweaty solipsists performing private workouts in public. On a train many of your fellow passengers will be insulated by headphones. Those ubiquitous devices are double-edged: they can fill your head with babble or, thanks to noise-cancelling, leave you in Trappist silence. As the two categories mingle, so the quest for balance becomes more intense. Popular modern fads offer a reacquaintance with the virtues of solitude: mindfulness provides access to peace and silence; some of the most popular pastimes in Silicon Valley, the source of so much noise and distraction, are hiking, yoga and meditation.</p><p>The lockdown has put the question of solitude at the heart of politics. Social distancing has been a tragedy for those living and, in some cases, dying alone. But for others it has proved a strange blessing. Overworked people have been able to take a break from the treadmill of commuting. Many have picked up long-abandoned hobbies, such as tending the garden or playing bridge. Solitude is both one of mankind’s greatest blessings and greatest curses—and thanks to a virus that has been carried across the world by human sociability, more people than ever are getting the chance to experience both. </p><p><a id="why-j-m-barrie-created-peter-pan"></a></p><h1 id="Why-J-M-Barrie-Created-Peter-Pan"><a href="#Why-J-M-Barrie-Created-Peter-Pan" class="headerlink" title="Why J. M. Barrie Created Peter Pan"></a>Why J. M. Barrie Created Peter Pan</h1><p>Almost a hundred years ago, at half past eight on the evening of December 27, 1904, the curtain went up at the Duke of York’s Theatre, in London, to reveal, among other things, a man dressed as a dog. The man was an actor named Arthur Lupino, suffering for his art in a shaggy costume, and the dog was called Nana. Most plays enjoy a fitful life, at best, but we can be fairly sure that this winter grown men will once again drop on all fours and work up a canine sweat, while grown women will crop their hair, pull on green tights, and turn into temporary boys. The play is “Peter Pan,” and, like its eponymous hero, it gives freakishly little sign of growing old.</p><p>The author was J. M. Barrie: Jimmy to some of his friends, and, in his later pomp, Sir James. He was short and slight, with bags under his eyes and a pale, protuberant brow, like a clever schoolboy who has stayed up late reading books under the bedclothes. He had a heavy mustache and a pipe smoker’s percussive cough. Of humble origins, he grew rich, yet his choice of overcoat remained several sizes too large, as if he were wearing a father’s hand-me-down. Both in face and in body—and, it became apparent, in the lineaments of his soul—Barrie seemed ill-suited to adult life, and those neat, child-friendly features sank all too readily into the caved-in sadness of old age.</p><p>Up to his death, in 1937, Barrie, as a result of his novels and plays, was one of the most famous men of his day; when Chaplin, on a trip to London in 1921, was asked whom he most wanted to meet, the answer was J. M. Barrie. Not even Barrie’s ardent admirers, however, would have described him as a matinée idol, and he would have been wryly flattered to find himself reincarnated, for the centenary of “Peter Pan,” in the beauteous person of Johnny Depp. A new film, entitled “Finding Neverland,” tells the story—or a decorated version of the story—of J. M. Barrie and the circumstances under which Peter Pan leaped into existence. Depp resembles Barrie in no way, except in his slenderness of form. We get a passable, soft stab at a Scottish burr but no mustache; we see more of the sweet side of Barrie than the insidious flip side; and the harshest coughing in the film comes not from Depp but from Kate Winslet, who plays Barrie’s friend Sylvia Llewellyn Davies.</p><p>Sylvia was one of a number of strong, rather Shakespearean female figures who ringed the life of Barrie—a dominance that began, unsurprisingly, with his mother. She was Margaret Ogilvy, a stonemason’s daughter who hailed from a particularly hard outcrop of the Presbyterian Church. James was born in 1860, the son of Margaret and a weaver named Alexander Barrie, in the Scottish town of Kirriemuir, and, until the age of six, he played in the shadow of his gifted and handsome older brother, David. Then, in the winter of 1867, David was killed; he was hit by a fellow ice-skater, fell, and cracked his skull. Margaret took to her bed under the onslaught of grief, and young James was dispatched to offer comfort:</p><blockquote><p>The room was dark, and when I heard the door shut and no sound come from the bed I was afraid, and I stood still. I suppose I was breathing hard, or perhaps I was crying, for after a time I heard a listless voice that had never been listless before say, “Is that you?” I think the tone hurt me, for I made no answer, and then the voice said more anxiously “Is that you?” again. I thought it was the dead boy she was speaking to, and I said in a little lonely voice, “No, it’s no’ him, it’s just me.” Then I heard a cry, and my mother turned in bed, and though it was dark I knew that she was holding out her arms.</p></blockquote><p>From here on, James worshipped his dead brother with a devotion that carried the taint of jealousy. Once, he even entered his mother’s presence wearing a suit of David’s clothes. The residue of the calamity, as it eventually seeped into Barrie’s art, was the conviction that a perfect child who dies on the eve of his fourteenth birthday will be spared the degradation of growing up, and that the death will be outshone by the thought of the perfection—so blindingly, perhaps, that the boy will seem scarcely to have passed away at all.</p><p>We think of Barrie as one of the chief explorers—or, in a gloomier light, invaders—of childhood. Yet the childhood that gripped him most tightly was not his own but that of other people; it is almost as if his own did not exist. The souls around him were like books, ripe for perusal, and he preferred their opening chapters. Hence “Margaret Ogilvy” (1896), which in part is a memoir of his mother’s youth. One of Barrie’s biographers, Denis Mackail, calls it “that distressingly human and inhuman book,” presumably because it demonstrates, even more than “Peter Pan,” the weird twinning of Barrie’s gifts—an almost telepathic self-spiriting into the emotions of others, and a professional shamelessness about baring them in public. Listen to his proud recital of Margaret Ogilvy’s deprivations: “She was eight when her mother’s death made her mistress of the house and mother to her little brother, and from that time she scrubbed and mended and baked and sewed.” At once we see that image skipping the generations, from mother to son, and from the son to the Wendy of “Peter Pan,” who was obliged, when she flew to Neverland and found a host of unclaimed children, to become a mother before her time.</p><p>The Barrie family—James was one of ten children, two of whom died in infancy—was ardently ambitious for its sons, the tool of that ambition was education, and Barrie duly studied at Dumfries Academy and at Edinburgh University. He emerged timid but industrious, and plowed a path into local and then national journalism. He moved to London, and, in 1887, produced his first novel, which bore the title “Better Dead.” Within a few years, thanks largely to some sharp, rosy fictions set in Scotland and to “The Little Minister,” a quaint tale of a minister who falls in love with a Gypsy, he had acquired not just a solid readership but a serious reputation; all of a sudden, we find him in correspondence with Thomas Hardy and Robert Louis Stevenson. He started writing for the theatre, kicking off with a parody of Ibsen, and indulging in the traditional sport of losing his heart to the leading ladies. His most acute biographer, Andrew Birkin—whose “J. M. Barrie and the Lost Boys” has been granted a timely reissue (Yale; $18.95)—digs up some astounding entries from Barrie’s private notebooks. Some are composed in the third person, as jottings toward a possible novel:</p><blockquote><p>—Greatest horror—dream I am married—wake up shrieking.<br>—Even while proposing, the thought of how it wd <em>read</em> go thro’ him.<br>—He never has contact with a woman—If he had this might have made him exult less in making women love him.</p></blockquote><p>In 1894, ignoring these self-cautions, Barrie married an actress named Mary Ansell, bestowing upon her, by way of a wedding present, a St. Bernard dog. The saga of Barrie is full of long-sufferers, the longest being Barrie himself, but nobody could follow its course and not spare a wealth of pity for Mary. Her husband loved many women, but the evidence suggests that the actual making of love lay outside his interests, or beyond his grasp. The creator of “Peter Pan” never had a child of his own. To us, the bewildering thing (and to Mary, surely the roughest insult) was that Barrie, far from burying his secret incapacities, dug them up like a pirate uncovering a treasure chest: “Grizel, I seem to be different from all other men; there seems to be some curse upon me… . You are the only woman I ever wanted to love, but apparently I can’t.” That comes from “Tommy and Grizel,” the tale of a devastated marriage which was published six years into Barrie’s own. At one point, the narrator says of Tommy, the fruitless husband, “He was a boy who could not grow up,” adding, of Grizel, “He gave her all his affection, but his passion, like an outlaw, had ever to hunt alone.” So where did the distinguished author like to hunt?</p><p>The answer is specific: Kensington Gardens, the broad, half-empty stretch of greenery next to Hyde Park. Here, in 1898, Barrie met a pair of boys, George and Jack Llewellyn Davies, aged five and four, who walked there with their nurse. They were amused by the small Scotsman with the enormous dog. Barrie talked with children, rather than at or down to them, and the meetings with George and Jack became drawn into the rhythm of their days. To our panicked eyes, such a relationship would be unthinkable—or, if thought about, nipped in the bud. We assume that a strange man, nearing forty, in a public place can offer only one thing to children still in knickerbockers, and that is harm. We would call the police, or, at least, call our children away. If we discovered the man to be a celebrity, we might call our lawyers, or, if we were feeling spiteful, the newspapers. And, if we were later to read what he wrote about our children, in an account so lightly ornamented as hardly to count as fiction, we might not be responsible for our actions:</p><blockquote><p>I returned to David, and asked him in a low voice whether he would give me a kiss. He shook his head about six times, and I was in despair. Then the smile came, and I knew that he was teasing me only. He now nodded his head about six times.<br>That was the prettiest of all his exploits.</p></blockquote><p>The tone of this, written in 1902, grates nastily on modern ears. Ever since “Lolita,” we have realized that one of the pleasures of the child-seeker is not merely to play games with the victim but to pretend that the victim is complicit in that game, or even pulling the strings; thus is the burden of guilt shifted smoothly away from the raptor. Did readers of 1902 feel nothing of the sort, or are we the guilty party, unable to conjure a time when playfulness was its own reward, rather than an alibi or a ruse? The passage comes from “The Little White Bird,” Barrie’s half-disguised novel about George Llewellyn Davies. In the book, George becomes David—note the name of Barrie’s dead brother—and is befriended by the bachelor narrator, who pretends to have a son of his own. This son, he then declares, has died (somewhere around here, the sheer weirdness of Barrie starts to multiply out of control), and he uses the nonexistent death to ingratiate himself further with David’s parents. He is especially pleased that David’s mother, Mary—note the name of Barrie’s wife—is “culpably obtuse to my sinister design,” the design being “to burrow under Mary’s influence with the boy, expose her to him in all his vagaries, take him utterly from her and make him mine.” Ladies and gentlemen of the jury, you may retire to consider your verdict.</p><p>Yet the stubborn fact remains: J. M. Barrie was innocent. He no more sought sex from children than he did from women. Andrew Birkin, who knows more about Barrie than anybody else (the last Llewellyn Davies boy, Nico, having died in 1980), has arrived at the balanced conclusion that the author of “Peter Pan” was “a lover of childhood, but was not in any sexual sense the paedophile that some claim him to have been.” His sinister design, it turns out, was not to corrupt boys with the murk of adult desire but to slough off any corruptions of his own, rejoin the unadulterated—the very word shows up the impurities in grownup life—and shrink once more, as best he could, into boyhood. This plan of Barrie’s may have been creepy and pathetic, but it was not a crime, and, as weaknesses go, it may be the most widespread in the world, haunting every harassed male who lies awake and tells himself how much simpler everything was as a kid.</p><p>At the heart of “The Little White Bird” is a story that the narrator slowly invents not only for David’s entertainment but with David’s help. It is about a boy named Peter Pan, who lives in Kensington Gardens. The first name is a direct allusion to the fact that George Llewellyn Davies now had another brother, Peter, born in 1897. There would be two more: Michael, born in 1900, and Nicholas (or Nico), born in 1903; a sisterless five in all, rather than the four of “Finding Neverland.” The film also opts for Peter Llewellyn Davies as the focus of Barrie’s attention—a not unnatural choice, given his name, but the wrong one, for it was really the whole gang of them whom Barrie loved. If he had a favorite, it was Michael, but, as the notorious preface to “Peter Pan”—dedicated “To the Five”—explains, “I always knew that I made Peter by rubbing the five of you violently together, as savages with two sticks produce a flame…. That is all he is, the spark I got from you.”</p><p>The course of the flame is a tricky one to trace, and what matters is that in Peter Pan Barrie achieved the rarest alchemy of all, the one that no writer can plan or predict: he invented a myth. The idea of Peter seems to have been flying around forever, a constant of humanity, and all that Barrie had to do was reach up and pluck the boy out of the air. After his first appearance, in “The Little White Bird,” Peter outgrew the nest; the passages about him were revised and republished, with illustrations of delicate grotesquerie by Arthur Rackham, under the title “Peter Pan in Kensington Gardens,” in 1906. In the meantime, the play, after its London début, was triumphantly staged in New York in the winter of 1905. The novel we now think of as “Peter Pan” is actually called “Peter and Wendy,” and it first saw the light in 1911. It is worth emphasizing that much of this material is close to unreadable—sometimes because it is sappy with sentiment but mostly because it is just too gnarled and knotted for current taste (increasing one’s reverence for Rackham, who saw its warpings at once), let alone for that of our children. What on earth will they make, for instance, of the opening pages of the novel, in which Mr. and Mrs. Darling, Wendy’s parents, are seen deciding whether they can afford to have more babies—literally adding up the doctors’ fees for the infant diseases (“measles one five, German measles half a guinea”) that they will be called upon to nurse?</p><p>Barrie would remonstrate severely on this point. He would claim that children cleave naturally to the misshapen and the morbid; like Roald Dahl, he admired the heartlessness and cunning of the young far more than he did their good behavior, and, for every mention of skipping fairies in “Peter Pan,” there will be some dashed-off sketch of alarming and sanguinary malice. Look between the cracks of the play, in the stage directions, and you will find his prose hardening and cooling into casual sadism, as in this line about Tootles, one of the pirate boys in Neverland:</p><blockquote><p>He has been in fewer adventures than any of them because the big things constantly happen while he has stepped round the corner; he will go off, for instance, in some quiet hour to gather firewood, and then when he returns the others will be sweeping up the blood.</p></blockquote><p>The most unfeeling child of all, needless to say, is Peter Pan himself. He flits through the play and the novels, and he has flitted through a century of stage productions and movies, and one result of those flittings is that we regard him as airy and innocuous. In truth, he is mean and green, a mini-monster of capering egotism; could there be any more dazzling proof of self-regard than a boy who first shows up in pursuit of his own shadow? In the early versions of the play, there is no Captain Hook, because there is no need for him; Peter supplies all the cruelty that is required. As “Peter Pan in Kensington Gardens” makes clear, our hero escaped from his parents as a baby and, after much prevarication, decided to forsake them for the unwithering plea-sure gardens of Kensington. He would fly back like a bird to watch his sleeping mother, but, once the decision was made, his way was barred—“When we reach the window it is Lock-out Time. The iron bars are up for life.” Such is Peter’s tragedy, but only because it was also his choice, and we should recall the terrifying title that Barrie appended to an early draft of the story: “The Boy Who Hated Mothers.”</p><p>And what of the real mother? Sylvia Llewellyn Davies first met Barrie at a dinner party in 1897; as the evening progressed, she realized that he was the man who wiggled his eyebrows at her children in the park. This revelation seems to have charmed rather than offended her; Barrie and she would be intimate friends for the rest of her life. Kate Winslet, who plays Sylvia in “Finding Neverland,” is ideal for the role, because she radiates that peculiar ease which starts to appear in photographs toward the end of the nineteenth century—no longer prim and straitened but open-faced, trusting, educated, and not without flickers of fire. In short, Sylvia (the daughter of a fast-witted literary clan, the du Mauriers) was altogether more modern than her husband, Arthur—scholar, lawyer, and stiff. Yet he, too, adored his boys, and it may be unfair of “Finding Neverland” to elide him, for streamlining purposes, from the scene; by the time that Johnny Depp meets Kate Winslet, she is already a widow, whereas Arthur was very much alive when Barrie first entered the consciousness—and, little by little, the home—of the Llewellyn Davies family. Soon, he was staying for tea, and then to wish the boys good night, and before long the Llewellyn Davieses were invited down to the Barries’ house in the country for idyllic vacations. He began as Mr. Barrie the author, and grew into Uncle Jim. It was all too much for Barrie’s wife, who, in the end, sought understandable consolation in the arms of another man; Barrie, in turn, sought a divorce, which was granted in 1909.</p><p>“Finding Neverland” is a weepie, and some viewers will mock it on that score, but it needs to be defended. First, because these days a good weepie is hard to find. And, second, because there is so much to weep about—far more, in fact, than you would gather from the film, which closes decorously after the death of Sylvia. (If you want a more accurate and leisurely testament, you could go online and order the DVD of “J. M. Barrie and the Lost Boys”—a wonderful TV drama, written by Andrew Birkin and running to four and a half hours, that the BBC produced in 1978, with Ian Holm providing the definitive Barrie.) From the moment that Barrie met George and Jack, and started to ponder the means by which they might be rendered immortal, the story becomes a dismal catalogue of mortality:</p><p>1907—Arthur Llewellyn Davies dies from cancer of the jaw.</p><p>1910—Sylvia dies of lung cancer. The five boys are orphaned; Barrie is made their guardian.</p><p>1915—George is killed in the First World War, fighting with his regiment in Flanders.</p><p>1921—Michael, an undergraduate at Oxford, is drowned while swimming with a friend. The two bodies, when recovered, are found clinging together.</p><p>All of this was enough to wreck Barrie, or, at least, to throw intolerable shadows over the remainder of his life. Few of his works, aside from “Peter Pan” and his desert-island comedy of class conflict, “The Admirable Crichton,” are remembered now, yet in 1922 he was invested with the Order of Merit, the grandest of British honors. He died in 1937, and we should be thankful that he didn’t live to be a hundred, and so to witness the terrible final act. On April 5, 1960, Peter Llewellyn Davies, by then an esteemed publisher, threw himself under a subway train in London. We should not presume to read a mind in torment, but we may note in passing that, if he had lived another month, he would have reached the centenary of Barrie’s birth and thus, one imagines, a fresh flurry of interest in “Peter Pan”—“that terrible masterpiece,” in the words of Peter Llewellyn Davies. His numerous comments on the genesis of the work, as quoted in Janet Dunbar’s 1970 biography of Barrie, are judicious, amused, and apparently unperturbed. But the effect of “Peter Pan” was like that of those iron bars on the hero’s family home; it is a kind of prison drama played onstage as a slice of festive cheer, and it locked the Llewellyn Davies boys into the garden of pre-puberty as surely as Pan himself is locked out from his mother’s embrace.</p><p>Does that make Barrie the bringer of mischance, after all? Peter “is never touched by any one in the play,” a stage direction in “Peter Pan” reads, and Barrie never touched his young charges—as Peter Llewellyn Davies confirmed—with anything more than affection. Once Arthur and Sylvia had died, Barrie, in loco parentis, fulfilled his duties with diligence and pride. But the damage, unwitting as it was, had been done long before, not by Barrie the middle-aged man but by Barrie the successful author; in making the Five the tinder for Peter Pan, he treated them as ideal spirits made flesh, and no child should be freighted with such an embarrassing burden. Their innocence was imperilled from the moment that it became prime-quality material for his elaborate public fantasies, and there may never have been a more desperate or acquisitive dedication than the one at the start of “Peter Pan in Kensington Gardens”: “To Sylvia and Arthur Llewellyn Davies and their boys (my boys).”</p><p>Barrie was a wounded creature, from his earliest youth, and his probing of that wound is what makes “Peter Pan” so enduringly painful to read. Toward the end of the novel, an immutable Peter drops in to find the adult Wendy, now a mother herself, as if he were the ghost of David Barrie, still cold from that skating accident, alighting beside Margaret Ogilvy. The tensions are bald and excruciating:</p><blockquote><p>He was a little boy, and she was grown up. She huddled by the fire not daring to move, helpless and guilty, a big woman.<br>“Hullo, Wendy,” he said, not noticing any difference, for he was thinking chiefly of himself; and in the dim light her white dress might have been the nightgown in which he had seen her first.<br>“Hullo, Peter,” she replied faintly, squeezing herself as small as possible. Something inside of her was crying, “Woman, woman, let go of me.”</p></blockquote><p>Is this really the stuff of classic children’s fiction? Do people still read “Peter Pan,” or has Peter shrunk to a brand by now, a chirping Disney figure wrenched from the unsettling landscapes where he originally appeared? If so, he demands restitution, for he sprang from the mind of an oddball, and he is not alone. Consider Lewis Carroll, Edward Lear, and J. M. Barrie: the stammerer with the camera, the wandering epileptic, and the coughing frequenter of playgrounds. The great dreamers of English children’s literature were not, as it happens, dreamy types at all but exacting, even pedantic, in the dramatizing of their fathomless unhappiness. If their characters are pricked by a helpless urge to travel—down a rabbit hole, to sea in a sieve, second star to the right and straight on till morning—it is because there is always something, a drab existence or a dreadful past, that begs to be fled. Open a page of “Harry Potter,” by contrast, and you know that it was written by a clever, funny woman of sound mind, with a keen commercial eye and a Barrie-like love of the fizzing narratives for which children naturally thirst; but there is nothing smarting beneath, no ominous beat of the heartsick. Harry will grow up, and we think it only proper that he should; but will he continue to taunt and haunt us, a hundred years from now, like the boy who never did?</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;!-- MarkdownTOC --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-small-worlds-of-%E2%80%9Cabout-endlessness%E2%80%9D&quot;&gt;The Small Worlds of “About Endlessness”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#acts-of-kindness-prevent-a-downward-spiral-from-solitude-to-loneliness&quot;&gt;Acts of kindness prevent a downward spiral from solitude to loneliness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#can-we-escape-from-information-overload&quot;&gt;Can we escape from information overload?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#solitude-has-always-been-both-a-blessing-and-a-curse&quot;&gt;Solitude has always been both a blessing and a curse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#why-j-m-barrie-created-peter-pan&quot;&gt;Why J. M. Barrie Created Peter Pan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- /MarkdownTOC --&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
    <category term="2021" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/2021/"/>
    
    <category term="翻" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%BF%BB/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>意识到</title>
    <link href="https://swy7.github.io/2021/04/21/%E6%9D%82/%E6%84%8F%E8%AF%86%E5%88%B0/"/>
    <id>https://swy7.github.io/2021/04/21/%E6%9D%82/%E6%84%8F%E8%AF%86%E5%88%B0/</id>
    <published>2021-04-21T11:36:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-09T21:39:01.522Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>看到微博上一个采访，关于上海人大附中学生的英语水平。让我想起那个恍惚的早晨，走在考试的路上，在来来往往的人群中，或许于他们而言这是个普通甚至厌倦的早晨，我却紧张的要死，脑袋发嗡。因为悦于享乐而未复习，我很是抱怨，但耳机里的歌继续放着，给我些许平静，让我这个情绪矛盾体走向考场，不知怎的我的思维渐散，想到人群平静人像中有我、有你、有他，大事小事就在这普通的表象下奔涌向前，所有人像一块地皮上的草，远看相同，近看不同，却有相同的土壤，土壤下的根彼此相连。而这种客观的视角瞬间被我抓了回来，<span id="more"></span>从相同转到不同，负气的想着我与他们何干。那时的感觉不了了之，我也再没写过，以至现在与这条微博才联系起来，我与他们何干，我的事于别人可能不是事，我的坎于别人可能从不会遇到。</p><p>这样说多少是种自责与自卑，因别人的优秀而让我羞耻。19年12月的事，现在过去了一年半，按当时情绪写法写下去定是骂的自己狗血淋头。我胆怯的要命。害怕充满了我与环境，我连迈开腿都不敢，我的思想明确的感到被禁锢，做出浪费时间这种十恶不赦的事。</p><p>我未去倾诉，自负的认为周边的人全是疲于奔命，谈何理想。于是远离家庭，远离朋友，奔向书籍电影与音乐，我想成为它们中的一员，想从事这方面的工作，去当作家，当编剧，当导演。从理科到文科的跨度之大，在我这几年的阅读与观影中才显现出来，文学素养与电影品味是需要时间打磨的。我很想去询问那些作家和导演，在第一部作品出来前自己是如何坚持的，生活是如何供给的。我知道我没有机会去询问，像导演李安那待业的七年怎么过的，杨德昌三十岁之前怎么过的，村上春树在看棒球赛前有没有在夜里或其他独自一人的时间里犹豫过未来的去向，再加上在微博中看到的下面这些。</p><p>作家在成名之前都做过什么：</p><p>库尔特·冯古内特——4s店销售员<br>斯蒂芬·金——学校保安<br>菲茨杰拉德——广告公司文案<br>肯·克西——精神病院看门<br>查尔斯·狄更斯——鞋厂流水线小工<br>马克·吐温——印刷厂排字工<br>玛格丽特·米切尔——记者<br>威廉·福克纳——大学邮政局局长<br>哈珀·李——航空公司售票员<br>阿加莎·克里斯蒂——护士<br>杰克·伦敦——小偷、水手<br>玛格丽特·阿特伍德——咖啡店收银员</p><p>或许可以给我一些安慰，26岁还有时间。</p><p>我从喜爱的人物回溯他们的过去，寻找与我相同的点给予我启发，然而有些事实让人冷却，像是那三位的家庭都属于中产家庭，父母是知识分子，从小就有良好的习惯与环境，而我农民阶级，留守儿童，家庭争端，混杂处于我的起始，以致到了大学未意识到自强而去随波逐流，与千万个在普通大学鬼混的学生一样浪费时间，等到社会，各个问题一一出现，有些果自己已食。反抗与挣扎出现在工作中的前半段，到中期与现在竟出现躺平任嘲的现象，是的我正处于这样的低谷，时时嘲讽道还有比现在更失败的时间点吗，随着自己的堕落，答案竟还是这句话，还有比现在更失败的时间点吗？</p><p>未去求人，所以也只能追溯过去，父亲的家暴与自身的无奈，母亲的不解与无知与善良，两人的婚姻从离婚到复婚，爷爷奶奶的管教到严教朋友，弟弟因管教失衡而早早辍学，亲戚因父母不在家释放的排挤，乡村老师在自身短见下的体罚与教育，家庭在社会的阶级，个人对女性的看法竟有些恋母（这让我很长时间批判与痛斥自己），个人在成长中性格的转变。种种这些都未养成我与人倾诉沟通的能力，以致到到大学到社会离后还是影响着我。高中与其他人一样顶多就是韩寒郭敬明还有一些书摊的短文小书，高考选专业没有参考和意见，16年进了大学学的工科自动化，不喜欢本专业，赖的环境松弛与自我放逐，未把这一大事放在心头。享乐与逃避之余大四前读的文学书不超过五本，在大四闲的无聊才去接触文学。看的比较多的还是电影，在电影中才找到我寂静的小岛，大学的历程整体是苦恼与逃避的。到了工作这种情绪简直就是无缝连接，从制造业换到计算机还是未找到自己热爱的，简直就是In the middle of nowhere，现在找到了却出现了胆怯真是挺讽刺的。</p><p>在这种回顾中前半期因埋怨家庭而忽视了自我的能动性，到了中期与现在可以客观的评价过去。也许因为时间与空间的拉长，也许这样的心路历程是必需的。《真探》中的宁静祷文：上帝赐予我宁静去接受我无法改变的，赐予我勇气去改变我所能改变的，并赐予我智慧去分辨它们的不同。到后来看到的：宽恕他人就是宽恕自己。还有其他书籍看到的句子给我安慰与启示。但问题是我的理想在现实找不到出口（这种文章严格不算），下一步该怎么走成了我心头大问。大到我又采用以前的方法去逃避，但总会在各个时间段浮现：洗澡，睡觉前，阅读，观影，发呆。明知道逃不过去，还假借勇气去逃避，简直是我这几年的生活最大的隐喻。即使是在写这篇文章后我都未给出答案。三年未回家，家人的说道才知道头发白了好多，就像前几次理发前看着镜子里的自己，莫名的冒出一句话：变老了。</p><p>变老了</p><p>是的，如果单听这句话从一个26岁的人说出口，你一定觉得</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;看到微博上一个采访，关于上海人大附中学生的英语水平。让我想起那个恍惚的早晨，走在考试的路上，在来来往往的人群中，或许于他们而言这是个普通甚至厌倦的早晨，我却紧张的要死，脑袋发嗡。因为悦于享乐而未复习，我很是抱怨，但耳机里的歌继续放着，给我些许平静，让我这个情绪矛盾体走向考场，不知怎的我的思维渐散，想到人群平静人像中有我、有你、有他，大事小事就在这普通的表象下奔涌向前，所有人像一块地皮上的草，远看相同，近看不同，却有相同的土壤，土壤下的根彼此相连。而这种客观的视角瞬间被我抓了回来，</summary>
    
    
    
    
    <category term="杂" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/%E6%9D%82/"/>
    
    <category term="2021" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/2021/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>20200604 今日翻</title>
    <link href="https://swy7.github.io/2020/06/04/%E7%BF%BB/20200604/"/>
    <id>https://swy7.github.io/2020/06/04/%E7%BF%BB/20200604/</id>
    <published>2020-06-03T17:06:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-10T05:28:36.409Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Michel Piccoli(who died on May 12, at the age of ninety-four) stars in Manoel de Oliveira’s luminous drama, from 2001, as Gilbert, a Paris-based actor whose wife, daughter, and son in-law die in a car accident, leaving him to raise his young grandson. Gilbert’s grief nonetheless propels him into the thick of life, and he starts paying heightened aesthetic attention to his surroundings. Oliveira films Gilbert and the city with puckish delight and graceful precision that capture the actor’s refined sensibility—and his poignant awareness that he may be seeing things for the last time. Yet, when Gilbert is offered the plum role of Buck Mulligan in an adaptation of “Ulysses” by an American director (John Malkovich), the performer must decide whether he’s ready to trade his new life of seeing for the chance to be seen again. Oliveira, a nvonagenarian when he made the film, conveys the hidden rapture of daily life—and the power of images to preserve it. In French and English.—R.B. (Streaming on Milestone Films.)</p><span id="more"></span><p>Michel Piccoli(于5月12日去世，享年94岁)自2001年起在Manoel de Oliveira执导的这部光芒熠熠的戏剧中饰演Gilbert。这位巴黎演员的妻子、女儿和女婿在一场车祸中丧生，留下他抚养年幼的孙子。尽管如此，吉尔伯特的悲伤把他推向了人生的充实，他开始对周围的环境产生了更高的审美关注。Oliveira以顽皮的喜悦和优雅的精准捕捉了这位演员精致的敏感，以及他可能是最后一次看东西的凄凉意识。然而，当一位美国导演John Malkovich邀请Gilbert在改编的《尤利西斯》(Ulysses)中饰演Buck Mulligan这一令人满意的角色时，他必须决定是否准备好用他的新生活来换取重见天日的机会。当Oliveira制作这部电影时，他已经九十多岁了，他传达了日常生活中隐藏的狂喜–以及影像的力量来保存它。有法语和英语版本，R.B.（在Milestone Films上播放）。</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Michel Piccoli(who died on May 12, at the age of ninety-four) stars in Manoel de Oliveira’s luminous drama, from 2001, as Gilbert, a Paris-based actor whose wife, daughter, and son in-law die in a car accident, leaving him to raise his young grandson. Gilbert’s grief nonetheless propels him into the thick of life, and he starts paying heightened aesthetic attention to his surroundings. Oliveira films Gilbert and the city with puckish delight and graceful precision that capture the actor’s refined sensibility—and his poignant awareness that he may be seeing things for the last time. Yet, when Gilbert is offered the plum role of Buck Mulligan in an adaptation of “Ulysses” by an American director (John Malkovich), the performer must decide whether he’s ready to trade his new life of seeing for the chance to be seen again. Oliveira, a nvonagenarian when he made the film, conveys the hidden rapture of daily life—and the power of images to preserve it. In French and English.—R.B. (Streaming on Milestone Films.)&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
    <category term="2020" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/2020/"/>
    
    <category term="翻" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%BF%BB/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>THE MAIL The New Yorker-2020-06-01</title>
    <link href="https://swy7.github.io/2020/05/31/%E7%BF%BB/THE%20MAIL%20The%20New%20Yorker-2020-06-01/"/>
    <id>https://swy7.github.io/2020/05/31/%E7%BF%BB/THE%20MAIL%20The%20New%20Yorker-2020-06-01/</id>
    <published>2020-05-31T14:34:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-09T21:23:11.551Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>JUST THE TICKET</p><p>I thoroughly enjoyed Anthony Lane’s ode to night trains(“Because the Night,” May 11th).I had the pleasure of riding the Venice Simplon-Orient-Express from Istanbul to Paris last summer, and thus feel compelled to contest Lane’s clever swipe at the types of passenger many believe to be on board this luxurious locomotive. I had a twin cabin; though expensive, it did not have the thirty-seven-thousand-dollar ticket price of the Cabin Suite. And, happily, my conversations consisted of topics much more interesting than the “same anecdote, from the same retired fund manager, all the way across a continent.” Far from being loathsome fat cat financiers, many passengers had saved for years to take this trip of a lifetime, just as I did. They ran the gamut from two longtime friends from Australia to a retired oncologist and his seriously ill wife; a woman who worked on the 9/11 victim-compensation fund; and a young man and his mother, to whom he’d given the trip for her fiftieth birthday. It was an incredible experience, and I look forward to more sleeping-car trips in the future.</p><span id="more"></span><p>我非常喜欢安东尼·莱恩(Anthony Lane)对夜间列车的颂歌(《因为夜晚》[Because the night]， 5月11日)。去年夏天，我有幸乘坐了从伊斯坦布尔到巴黎的威尼斯辛普朗-东方快车(Venice Simplon-Orient-Express)，因此我觉得有必要对莱恩巧妙的抨击乘客类型进行反驳，大多认为是这辆豪华列车上的乘客。我有一个双人舱;虽然很贵，但它不像客舱套间那样要三万七千美元的票价。幸运的是，我的谈话内容远比“ 整个大陆上同一个退休基金经理讲的同一件轶事”有趣得多。许多乘客根本不是令人讨厌的有钱的金融家，而是像我一样，为了这次一生难忘的旅行而存了多年的钱。乘客各式各样，从两位来自澳大利亚的老朋友到一位退休的肿瘤医生和他身患重病的妻子;一位在911受害者赔偿基金工作的女性;还有一个年轻人和他的母亲，他把这趟旅行作为她50岁生日的礼物送给了她。这是一次不可思议的经历，我期待着未来有更多的卧铺之旅。</p><p>Janet Paist New York City</p><p>Lane’s love letter to the night train was enchanting. I’ve crossed the United States twice and the Canadian border once on Amtrak,seated each time. It’s a lot like camping: sleeping in uncomfortable positions, preparing instant noodles by moonlight, and approximating a shower using a water bottle and a sink. Night-train journeys both whet our appetite for adventure and develop our sense of scale. The trip from New York to San Francisco once took more than a year and required you to winch your wagon down the granite slopes of the Sierras. How miraculous is it that, today, you can travel cross-country relatively efficiently, but still stick your head out the window and let the desert wind whip your hair, or watch the moon rise over the snowy Rocky Mountains from the sightseeing car? For the planet’s sake, those of us lucky enough to have the means to travel don’t just need to find greener substitutes for flying; we need to once again allow cross-continental journeys to be full of grandeur. During these homebound times,Lane’s piece offered an important reminder about the power of travel, as well as a wonderful escape back into the wider world.</p><p>莱恩写给夜班火车的情书很迷人。我曾两次穿越美国，一次坐Amtrak穿越加拿大边境，每次都是坐着。这很像野营:以不舒服的姿势睡觉，在月光下准备方便面，用水瓶和水槽洗澡。夜间火车旅行既刺激了我们的冒险欲望，又培养了我们的感知范围。从纽约到旧金山的旅程曾经需要花了一年多的时间，需要你用绞车将马车从山脉的花岗岩山坡拉下。今天，你可以相对高效地进行越野旅行，但仍然把头v伸出窗外，让沙漠的风吹动你的头发，或者从观光车上看着月亮从落基山脉的雪山上升起，这是多么不可思议啊!看在地球的份上，我们这些有能力旅行的人，不只是要寻找更环保的交通工具来代替飞行，我们需要再次让跨洲旅行充满了宏伟的气势。在这个无法出门的时间里，莱恩的文章提醒了人们旅行的力量，同时也让我们回到了更广阔的世界。</p><p>Sophia Kakarala B1rooklyn, N.Y</p><p>UNTIL THE SHOOTING STOPS I read Jill Lepore’s analysis of the violence at Kent State,Jackson State, and elsewhere with interest and emotion (Books, May 4th). In 1970, for a journalism course at Berkeley, I wrote a paper comparing the media coverage, in regional papers and national magazines, of the incidents at Kent State and Jackson State and in Augusta, Georgia. I found, among other things, that the San Francisco Examiner gave more than three times as many column inches to Kent State, where four white students were killed, as it did to Augusta and Jackson State, where, collectively, eight black people were killed. The students at Kent State had their biographies outlined all over the press, but, in a story about the Augusta and Jackson State shootings in Time’s May 25th issue, the six men killed in Augusta weren’t even named. In summary, I wrote that “the whites were mourned, the blacks merely mentioned,”and concluded that “in America, it seems, we will not grant equality even to the dead.” As Lepore writes, we will go on not only suffering but suffering unequally “until the shooting stops.” </p><p>在《直到枪声停止》（UNTIL THE SHOOTING STOPS）一书中，我读了吉尔-莱波尔（Jill Lepore）对肯特州立大学、杰克逊州立大学和其他地方的暴力事件的分析，并感慨万千（Books，5月4日）。1970年，我在伯克利大学的一门新闻学课程中，写了一篇论文，比较了地区性报纸和全国性杂志对肯特州立大学、杰克逊州立大学和佐治亚州奥古斯塔事件的媒体报道。我发现，《旧金山问卷者》给肯特州立大学的专栏篇幅是给奥古斯塔和杰克逊州立大学的三倍多，肯特州立大学有四名白人学生被杀，而奥古斯塔和杰克逊州立大学总共有八名黑人学生被杀。肯特州立大学的学生们的传记被刊登在了各大报刊上，但在《时代》杂志5月25日刊登的一篇关于奥古斯塔和杰克逊州立大学枪击事件的报道中，在奥古斯塔被枪杀的六名男子甚至连名字都没有提到。总之，我写道，“白人受到哀悼，黑人只是被提到”，并得出结论，“在美国，似乎我们甚至不会赋予死者平等权利。”正如勒波雷所写，我们不仅会继续受苦，而且会不平等地受苦，“直到枪声停止”。</p><p>Nancy Roberts Healdsburg, Calif</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;JUST THE TICKET&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thoroughly enjoyed Anthony Lane’s ode to night trains(“Because the Night,” May 11th).I had the pleasure of riding the Venice Simplon-Orient-Express from Istanbul to Paris last summer, and thus feel compelled to contest Lane’s clever swipe at the types of passenger many believe to be on board this luxurious locomotive. I had a twin cabin; though expensive, it did not have the thirty-seven-thousand-dollar ticket price of the Cabin Suite. And, happily, my conversations consisted of topics much more interesting than the “same anecdote, from the same retired fund manager, all the way across a continent.” Far from being loathsome fat cat financiers, many passengers had saved for years to take this trip of a lifetime, just as I did. They ran the gamut from two longtime friends from Australia to a retired oncologist and his seriously ill wife; a woman who worked on the 9/11 victim-compensation fund; and a young man and his mother, to whom he’d given the trip for her fiftieth birthday. It was an incredible experience, and I look forward to more sleeping-car trips in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
    <category term="2020" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/2020/"/>
    
    <category term="翻" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%BF%BB/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Has covid-19 killed globalisation?</title>
    <link href="https://swy7.github.io/2020/05/18/%E7%BF%BB/Has%20covid-19%20killed%20globalisation/"/>
    <id>https://swy7.github.io/2020/05/18/%E7%BF%BB/Has%20covid-19%20killed%20globalisation/</id>
    <published>2020-05-18T01:18:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-09T21:23:02.360Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>EVEN BEFORE the pandemic, globalisation was in trouble. The open system of trade that had dominated the world economy for decades had been damaged by the financial crash and the Sino-American trade war. Now it is reeling from its third body-blow in a dozen years as lockdowns have sealed borders and disrupted commerce (see ). The number of passengers at Heathrow has dropped by 97% year-on-year; Mexican car exports fell by 90% in April; 21% of transpacific container-sailings in May have been cancelled. As economies reopen, activity will recover, but don’t expect a quick return to a carefree world of unfettered movement and free trade. The pandemic will politicise travel and migration and entrench a bias towards self-reliance. This inward-looking lurch will enfeeble the recovery, leave the economy vulnerable and spread geopolitical instability.</p><span id="more"></span><p>甚至在大流行之前，全球化就陷入了困境。几十年来主导世界经济的开放贸易体系已经被金融危机和中美贸易战破坏。现在，由于封锁了边境，扰乱了商业，它正遭受着十多年来的第三次沉重打击。希思罗机场的乘客数量同比下降了97%;4月份墨西哥汽车出口下降了90%;五月份，21%的跨太平洋集装箱航班被取消。随着经济重新开放，经济活动将会复苏，但不要指望会很快回到自由流动和自由贸易的无忧无虑的世界。大流行将使旅行和移民政治化，并使人们更加倾向于自力更生。这种向内倾斜将削弱复苏，使经济脆弱，并蔓延地缘政治不稳定。</p><p>The world has had several epochs of integration, but the trading system that emerged in the 1990s went further than ever before. China became the world’s factory and borders opened to people, goods, capital and information (see ). After Lehman Brothers collapsed in 2008 most banks and some multinational firms pulled back. Trade and foreign investment stagnated relative to GDP, a process this newspaper later called slowbalisation. Then came President Donald Trump’s trade wars, which mixed worries about blue-collar jobs and China’s autocratic capitalism with a broader agenda of chauvinism and contempt for alliances. At the moment when the virus first started to spread in Wuhan last year, America’s tariff rate on imports was back to its highest level since 1993 and both America and China had begun to decouple their technology industries.</p><p>世界已经经历了几个一体化的时代，但上世纪90年代出现的贸易体系比以往任何时候都走得更远。它成为了世界工厂，向人们、商品、资本和信息开放了边界。2008年雷曼兄弟破产后，大多数银行和一些跨国公司都撤出了市场。贸易和外国投资相对于国内生产总值(GDP)停滞不前，本报后来将这一过程称为“缓慢平衡”(slowbalisation)。然后是唐纳德·特朗普(Donald Trump)总统的贸易战，这场贸易战既有对蓝领工作和中国专制资本主义的担忧，也有更广泛的沙文主义和对联盟的蔑视。当病毒去年开始在武汉传播的时候，美国的进口关税回到了1993年以来的最高水平，美国和中国已经开始脱钩他们的技术产业。</p><p>Since January a new wave of disruption has spread westward from Asia. Factory, shop and office closures have caused demand to tumble and prevented suppliers from reaching customers. The damage is not universal. Food is still getting through, Apple insists it can still make iPhones and China’s exports have held up so far, buoyed by sales of medical gear. But the overall effect is savage. World goods trade may shrink by 10-30% this year. In the first ten days of May exports from South Korea, a trade powerhouse, fell by 46% year-on-year, probably the worst decline since records began in 1967.</p><p>自1月份以来，一波新的破坏浪潮从亚洲向西蔓延。工厂、商店和办公室的关闭导致需求暴跌，并使供应商无法接触到客户。这种损害并不是普遍的。食品仍在运输途中，苹果坚称仍有能力生产iphone，而中国的出口在医疗设备销售的推动下迄今保持稳定。但总体效果是残酷的。今年，世界货物贸易可能缩水10-30%。五月的前十天，韩国这个贸易大国的出口同比下降46%，这可能是自1967年有记录以来最严重的下降。</p><p>The underlying anarchy of global governance is being exposed. France and Britain have squabbled over quarantine rules, China is threatening Australia with punitive tariffs for demanding an investigation into the virus’s origins and the White House remains on the warpath about trade. Despite some instances of co-operation during the pandemic, such as the Federal Reserve’s loans to other central banks, America has been reluctant to act as the world’s leader. Chaos and division at home have damaged its prestige. China’s secrecy and bullying have confirmed that it is unwilling—and unfit—to pick up the mantle. Around the world, public opinion is shifting away from globalisation. People have been disturbed to find that their health depends on a brawl to import protective equipment and on the migrant workers who work in care homes and harvest crops.</p><p>全球治理的无政府状态正在暴露出来。法国和英国在检疫规则问题上争吵不休，法国和英国在检疫规则上发生了争执，中国威胁要对澳大利亚征收惩罚性关税，因为澳大利亚要求对病毒的来源进行调查，而白宫仍在为贸易问题争吵不休。尽管在疫情发生期间出现了一些合作的情况，比如美联储向其他央行提供贷款，但美国一直不愿意充当世界的领导者。国内的混乱和分裂破坏了美国的威信。中国的秘密和欺凌证实了它不愿意也不适合拿起衣钵。在全球范围内，公众舆论正在远离全球化。人们不安地发现，他们的健康取决于进口防护用品的争斗，以及在养老院工作和收割庄稼的农民工。</p><p>This is just the start. Although the flow of information is largely free outside China, the movement of people, goods and capital is not. Consider people first. The Trump administration is proposing to curtail immigration further, arguing that jobs should go to Americans instead. Other countries are likely to follow. Travel is restricted, limiting the scope to find work, inspect plants and drum up orders. Some 90% of people live in countries with largely closed borders. Many governments will open up only to countries with similar health protocols: one such “travel bubble” is mooted to include Australia and New Zealand and, perhaps, Taiwan and Singapore (see ). The industry is signalling that the disruption to travel will be lasting. Airbus has cut production by a third and Emirates, a symbol of globalisation, expects no recovery until 2022.</p><p>这仅仅是个开始。尽管信息在中国境外的流动基本上是自由的，但人员、商品和资本的流动却不是。首先考虑的人。特朗普政府正提议进一步限制移民，辩称工作岗位应该由美国人获得。其他国家可能也会效仿。旅行受到限制，限制了寻找工作、检查工厂和招揽订单的范围。大约90%的人生活在边境基本封闭的国家。许多政府将只对拥有类似健康协议的国家开放:一个类似的“旅游泡沫”正在酝酿中，其中包括澳大利亚和新西兰，也许还有台湾和新加坡(见)。该行业发出的信号表明，旅游中断将是持久的。空客已经削减了三分之一的产量，而全球化的象征阿联酋航空预计在2022年之前都不会恢复生产。</p><p>Trade will suffer as countries abandon the idea that firms and goods are treated equally regardless of where they come from. Governments and central banks are asking taxpayers to underwrite national firms through their stimulus packages, creating a huge and ongoing incentive to favour them. And the push to bring supply chains back home in the name of resilience is accelerating. On May 12th Narendra Modi, India’s prime minister, told the nation that a new era of economic self-reliance has begun. Japan’s covid-19 stimulus includes subsidies for firms that repatriate factories; European Union officials talk of “strategic autonomy” and are creating a fund to buy stakes in firms. America is urging Intel to build plants at home. Digital trade is thriving but its scale is still modest. The sales abroad of Amazon, Apple, Facebook and Microsoft are equivalent to just 1.3% of world exports.</p><p>贸易将会受到影响，因为各国放弃了企业和商品无论来自哪里都受到平等对待的想法。政府和中央银行正在要求纳税人通过他们的经济刺激计划为国有企业提供担保，这就产生了一种巨大且持续的支持他们的动机。以恢复力为名将供应链带回国内的努力正在加速。5月12日，印度总理纳伦德拉·莫迪(Narendra Modi)向全国宣布，一个经济自力更生的新时代已经开始。日本的covid-19刺激计划包括为将工厂迁回日本的公司提供补贴;欧盟官员谈到了“战略自主权”，并正在创建一个基金来购买公司的股份。美国正敦促英特尔在国内建厂。数字贸易正在蓬勃发展，但其规模仍然不大。亚马逊(Amazon)、苹果(Apple)、Facebook和微软(Microsoft)的海外销售额仅占全球出口额的1.3%。</p><p>The flow of capital is also suffering, as long-term investment sinks. Chinese venture-capital investment in America dropped to $400m in the first quarter of this year, 60% below its level two years ago. Multinational firms may cut their cross-border investment by a third this year. America has just instructed its main federal pension fund to stop buying Chinese shares, and so far this year countries representing 59% of world GDP have tightened their rules on foreign investment. As governments try to pay down their new debts by taxing firms and investors, some countries may be tempted to further restrict the flow of capital across borders.</p><p>随着长期投资的减少，资本流动也受到了影响。今年第一季度，中国在美国的风险投资降至4亿美元，比两年前的水平低了60%。跨国公司今年可能会减少三分之一的跨国投资。美国刚刚指示其主要的联邦养老基金停止购买中国股票，今年到目前为止，占世界GDP 59%的国家已经收紧了对外国投资的规定。当政府试图通过向企业和投资者征税来偿还新债务时，一些国家可能会忍不住进一步限制资本跨境流动。</p><p>It’s lonely out there</p><p>Don’t be fooled that a trading system with an unstable web of national controls will be more humane or safer. Poorer countries will find it harder to catch up and, in the rich world, life will be more expensive and less free. The way to make supply chains more resilient is not to domesticate them, which concentrates risk and forfeits economies of scale, but to diversify them. Moreover, a fractured world will make solving global problems harder, including finding a vaccine and securing an economic recovery.</p><p>外面很寂寞</p><p>不要以为一个由不稳定的国家控制网络组成的贸易体系会更人性化或更安全。贫穷的国家将会发现很难赶上，而在富裕的国家，生活将会更昂贵，更不自由。使供应链更具弹性的方法不是将其驯化，而是使其多样化，因为驯化将集中风险并丧失规模经济。此外，一个分裂的世界将使解决全球性问题更加困难，包括寻找疫苗和确保经济复苏。</p><p>Tragically, this logic is no longer fashionable. Those three body-blows have so wounded the open system of trade that the powerful arguments in its favour are being neglected. Wave goodbye to the greatest era of globalisation—and worry about what is going to take its place</p><p>可悲的是，这种逻辑已不再流行。这三次沉重的打击对开放的贸易体系造成了如此严重的伤害，以至于支持开放贸易体系的有力论据被忽视了。向全球化最伟大的时代挥手告别，并为即将取代它的时代而担忧</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;EVEN BEFORE the pandemic, globalisation was in trouble. The open system of trade that had dominated the world economy for decades had been damaged by the financial crash and the Sino-American trade war. Now it is reeling from its third body-blow in a dozen years as lockdowns have sealed borders and disrupted commerce (see ). The number of passengers at Heathrow has dropped by 97% year-on-year; Mexican car exports fell by 90% in April; 21% of transpacific container-sailings in May have been cancelled. As economies reopen, activity will recover, but don’t expect a quick return to a carefree world of unfettered movement and free trade. The pandemic will politicise travel and migration and entrench a bias towards self-reliance. This inward-looking lurch will enfeeble the recovery, leave the economy vulnerable and spread geopolitical instability.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
    <category term="2020" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/2020/"/>
    
    <category term="翻" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%BF%BB/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>no</title>
    <link href="https://swy7.github.io/2020/01/01/%E7%9F%A5/no/"/>
    <id>https://swy7.github.io/2020/01/01/%E7%9F%A5/no/</id>
    <published>2019-12-31T16:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-09T21:22:18.257Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>no</p><span id="more"></span>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;no&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
    <category term="2020" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/2020/"/>
    
    <category term="知" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%9F%A5/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>生于教育（一）</title>
    <link href="https://swy7.github.io/2019/12/27/%E7%BF%BB/%E7%94%9F%E4%BA%8E%E6%95%99%E8%82%B2%EF%BC%88%E4%B8%80%EF%BC%89/"/>
    <id>https://swy7.github.io/2019/12/27/%E7%BF%BB/%E7%94%9F%E4%BA%8E%E6%95%99%E8%82%B2%EF%BC%88%E4%B8%80%EF%BC%89/</id>
    <published>2019-12-27T11:21:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-09T21:23:24.486Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>我印象最深的记忆并不真实。而是一些我想象出来的事，这使得往后记起时像是发生过一样。这种记忆在我五到六岁之间形成，来自于父亲说的一个详细的故事，其中伴随着枪声与喊叫声，我和我的兄弟姐妹每个人变成了自己的电影角色。当我和家人一起蜷缩在厨房，关掉灯，躲避着房屋周围联邦人员，矿井的蟋蟀声，是我能听到的。一个女人伸手去拿水，月光照亮她的轮廓。枪声如同鞭声，她应声而倒。在我的记忆里，这个女人是我的母亲，怀中还抱有孩子。</p><span id="more"></span><p>这个孩子怎么都说不通，我是七个孩子中最小的，就像我说的，其实这些都没有发生过。</p><p>父亲讲这个故事后的一年，晚上全家聚在一起听他朗读圣经中的一节，关于以马内利的预言。他坐在芥末色沙发上，腿上放着一本打开的圣经。母亲坐在他的旁边。剩下的我们零散的坐在棕色的地毯上。</p><p>“他将会得到奶油和蜂蜜”，在搬运一天后的疲惫中，父亲拖着低沉，单调的语气读着。“这使得他弃恶择善。”</p><p>一阵沉重的沉默。我们静静地坐在那里。</p><p>父亲并不高，但足以震慑这个家。他的周围有一种神谕的庄严气氛。他的手又糙又厚，这是一生艰苦工作人的手，这手正紧抓着《圣经》。</p><p>他大声读着这一章两遍，三遍，四遍。每一次的重复他的声音变得越高。他的眼睛刚刚还因疲劳而肿起来，现在却睁得大大的，机警起来了。这里有一个神圣的教义，他说。他会向主询问。</p><p>第二天早上，爸爸把冰箱里的牛奶、酸奶和奶酪都清理了。当天晚上，他回家的时候，卡车里装满了50加仑的蜂蜜。</p><p>当我的兄弟把白桶搬进了地下室时，爸爸笑着说，“圣经没有说黄油还是蜂蜜，哪个是邪恶的，你们若问，主必告诉你们。”</p><p>当父亲对奶奶念诗，她当着他的面笑了。“我钱包里有些硬币，”她说。“你最好拿去。他们将是你所有的感觉。</p><p>奶奶有一张瘦削、棱角分明的脸，她那细长的脖子和手指上挂着一簇簇数不尽的银饰和绿松石做的人造印度首饰。因为她住在我们的山下，靠近公路，所以我们叫她山下奶奶。为了把奶奶和外婆区别开来，我们称外婆为镇上奶奶，因为外婆住在往南15英里的这个县唯一的一个镇上，在这里只有一个红绿灯和一家杂货店。</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;我印象最深的记忆并不真实。而是一些我想象出来的事，这使得往后记起时像是发生过一样。这种记忆在我五到六岁之间形成，来自于父亲说的一个详细的故事，其中伴随着枪声与喊叫声，我和我的兄弟姐妹每个人变成了自己的电影角色。当我和家人一起蜷缩在厨房，关掉灯，躲避着房屋周围联邦人员，矿井的蟋蟀声，是我能听到的。一个女人伸手去拿水，月光照亮她的轮廓。枪声如同鞭声，她应声而倒。在我的记忆里，这个女人是我的母亲，怀中还抱有孩子。&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
    <category term="2020" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/2020/"/>
    
    <category term="翻" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%BF%BB/"/>
    
    <category term="生于教育" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%94%9F%E4%BA%8E%E6%95%99%E8%82%B2/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>生于教育（序）</title>
    <link href="https://swy7.github.io/2019/12/27/%E7%BF%BB/%E7%94%9F%E4%BA%8E%E6%95%99%E8%82%B2%EF%BC%88%E5%BA%8F%EF%BC%89/"/>
    <id>https://swy7.github.io/2019/12/27/%E7%BF%BB/%E7%94%9F%E4%BA%8E%E6%95%99%E8%82%B2%EF%BC%88%E5%BA%8F%EF%BC%89/</id>
    <published>2019-12-27T03:11:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-09T21:23:34.229Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>我正站在谷仓旁的废弃红色火车上。风声大作，吹乱我的头发，将凉意送进领口。山边的风更大些，像是山峰在呼吸。往下的山谷则安静平和。与此同时，我家的农场跳起舞来：随着每一阵风吹来，巨大的针叶树缓慢摇摆，灌木丛跟着颤栗、弯腰。在我身后，缓缓向上的山坡绵延到山脚下。如果我抬起头，便可看见黑暗形态的印第安公主.</p><span id="more"></span><p>山坡上长满了野生小麦。若把针叶树与灌木丛看作独奏者，那这麦田便是芭蕾舞团，每个麦秆随着其他部分爆发出一阵阵的运动，在大风吹着金色的麦穗下，百万个芭蕾舞者此起彼伏地弯下腰。麦田凹陷的形状只存在片刻，像是人们看到风一样。</p><p>转向我家山坡上的房子，我看到不同的运动，高大的影子在气流中僵硬移动。我的兄弟们醒了，在测天气。我想象母亲在火炉边正翻着麦麸煎饼。父亲弓着背站在后门，系着钢头靴，把长满老茧的手穿进焊接手套里。下面的高速公路上，校车不停地驶过。</p><p>我只有7岁，但我明白，让我家与众不同是“我们不去上学”这个事实，而不是其他的事。</p><p>我爸担心政府会强迫我们去学校，但事实上并不会，因为政府根本不知道我们。七个孩子中有四个没有出生证明。因为在家里出生并未见过医生与护士，我们没有医疗档案。因为从未踏入进教室，我们没有学校档案。当我9岁时，我将得到一份延期的出生证明，但在此时，根据爱达荷州和联邦政府的说法，我是不存在。</p><p>当然我是存在的。我从小就为可憎的日子作准备，看着太阳下山，看着月亮如染血般下落。夏天，我把桃子装进瓶，冬天，则作食物供应。当这个世界走向尽头，我家依在，不受任何影响。</p><p>我学习于山的韵律，这种韵律的变化不是基本规律，而是一种循环。太阳在每天的早晨中升起，划过山谷，在山峰的背后落下。冬天的雪在春季融化。我们的生活是一个循环，一天的循环，一季的循环。我相信我家是这永恒模式中的一部分，在某种意义，我们是永恒的。但永恒只属于这座山。</p><p>我父亲曾经讲过一个关于这个山峰的故事。她优美古老，是山的大教堂，山中还有其他更高，更壮观的山峰，但巴克的山峰是最精巧的。她的山脚盘延一公里，黑色的形体从地下隆起，上升成一个完美无缺的尖顶。在远处看，你可以看到一个女人的身体印在山上:她的腿由巨大的峡谷构成，她的头发是松树的浪花，在北部的山脊上呈扇形散开。她的姿势是威严的，一条腿大踏步有力地向前伸着。</p><p>我父亲叫她印第安公主。每年雪开始融化时，她都会面朝南出现，看着水牛返回山谷。他说，游牧的印第安人把她的出现，看作是春天到来的标志，预示着冰雪正在融化，冬天已经过去，是时候回家了。</p><p>所有我父亲的故事都是关于山和山谷，还有爱达荷州这块参差不齐的土地。他从未告诉我该怎么做，如果我离开这座山，越过海洋和大陆，在一个陌生的地方找到了自己，在这里我无法在地平线上看到印第安公主。他从未告诉过我，如何知道该什么时候回家。</p><p>除了我妹妹奥黛丽，她小时候摔伤了一个胳膊和一条腿。她被带去打了石膏。</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;我正站在谷仓旁的废弃红色火车上。风声大作，吹乱我的头发，将凉意送进领口。山边的风更大些，像是山峰在呼吸。往下的山谷则安静平和。与此同时，我家的农场跳起舞来：随着每一阵风吹来，巨大的针叶树缓慢摇摆，灌木丛跟着颤栗、弯腰。在我身后，缓缓向上的山坡绵延到山脚下。如果我抬起头，便可看见黑暗形态的印第安公主.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
    <category term="2020" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/2020/"/>
    
    <category term="翻" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%BF%BB/"/>
    
    <category term="生于教育" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%94%9F%E4%BA%8E%E6%95%99%E8%82%B2/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>信（一）</title>
    <link href="https://swy7.github.io/2018/10/25/%E6%9D%82/%E4%BF%A1%EF%BC%88%E4%B8%80%EF%BC%89/"/>
    <id>https://swy7.github.io/2018/10/25/%E6%9D%82/%E4%BF%A1%EF%BC%88%E4%B8%80%EF%BC%89/</id>
    <published>2018-10-25T01:37:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2021-05-09T21:21:40.524Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>亲爱的：德洛丽丝 </p><p>春雨夹杂着寒风阵阵吹来，夜晚行人匆匆的走着，不知有没有人和我是慢吞吞踱步在享受这雨，吐气出来还是有白雾升起，春意中凉意更多一些，德洛丽丝，我无比思念你。</p><span id="more"></span><p>我像是静止在人流中，眼光四散，甚至幻想着从人群中揪你出来，握住你的手，一遍遍的用拇指扫过你的手背，你可曾看到我眼中的光，我想我是看到你的了，那跳动的明亮的光，一层又一层的去除我对世界的质疑。</p><p>在散着黄光的雨街中走着，从没想过与你的日子似乎也是这种颜色，清澈透亮，我俩像是在时间的漩涡中跳舞，一圈一圈不知疲惫的转着，这一刻让我产生摆脱的感觉，生活的负重感，随着离心力一阵阵的退散，像梦一般，这种强烈拥有你的感觉，你能感觉到就好了。</p><p>​                                                                        ——  杰克</p><p>亲爱的：布朗</p><p>这里就不用多余的客套了，你我算是老友，在这里想让你帮个忙。</p><p>我有个朋友杰克，你应该见过，人还不错，上次在地铁和你有一面之缘，如果忘记了也没事，他巴不得别人忘记他，甚至想消失在人群中，真是怪人一个你说呢。人群中就只有显眼和普通两类人，怎么能消失的掉，我虽然读的书少，但也知道现在的时代个体与社会已经分不开了，没人能光不溜秋的窜进热带雨林中活下来。至于个体与社会的复杂关系，我这榆木脑袋是无法搞懂的。现在对于人生的意义或上述的这类问题，我的观点是不要再去多花时间去探讨这些问题了，着手去做事才是最主要的，或许有些问题要学会远离，才会找到答案。对于这一点我倒是很喜欢《树上的男爵》中的故事。</p><p>有点跑偏了，还是和你说说这位从小就认识的玩伴，我俩关系很好，就像《怪胎与书呆》的三个geek的关系，我不找他麻烦，他也不找我麻烦，感觉真要向友谊地久天长这句话发展了，可最近我越来越不懂杰克了。</p><p>杰克太消沉了。</p><p>杰克并没有自杀的念想，也没有像《荒原狼》提到的精神上自杀。和我谈过几次，他形容自己就像“in the middle of nowhere”，而且还是近视。我觉得他很迷茫，鼓励过几次，让他去做些事情，可他总是没有耐心，都半途而废。周而复始，这把我气的，直接上硬的，我用严厉的言语讽刺他，希望能激起他的斗志，可他总说感觉自己陷入时间的轮回中，无处可走，这类有的没的，我觉的他真是“游”的太远了，怎么可能脚不着地就想生活，真是自暴自弃的家伙，太令我失望了。</p><p>我真很关心他，希望你能找时间和他谈谈。</p><p>​                                                                                                                                             ——  麻桑</p><p>亲爱的：麻桑</p><p>最近一直没有答应，是由于我和杰克交谈了一段时间，现在才提起笔回应你。</p><p>约杰克出来过几次，对我的感觉是，挺帅的小伙，人也不错，但总觉得身上缺点什么。《龙珠》！嗯？看来这家伙缺气，卡卡罗特我感受到这孩子的气太弱了，当然这也是一种生活的方式。这孩子从未和任何人说过自己的内心话，从小到大。可能看到了我强大的战斗力从而相信我，或是我来自于遥远的贝吉塔行星与我倾诉也无关紧要，事实就是他和我开口了。好了，不开玩笑了，反正我也不知怎么的，我和他就谈了很久。</p><p>他说他很苦闷，时常感到矛盾，不追求成功，却越来越孤独，有时候负面情绪膨胀到胸口，简直就想开启自毁程序，把一切都砸个稀巴烂。</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;亲爱的：德洛丽丝 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;春雨夹杂着寒风阵阵吹来，夜晚行人匆匆的走着，不知有没有人和我是慢吞吞踱步在享受这雨，吐气出来还是有白雾升起，春意中凉意更多一些，德洛丽丝，我无比思念你。&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    
    
    
    
    <category term="2020" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/2020/"/>
    
    <category term="杂" scheme="https://swy7.github.io/tags/%E6%9D%82/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
