<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>swy7</title>
  
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="Swy7.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2020-05-10T03:13:42.271Z</updated>
  <id>Swy7.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>swy7</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Can we escape from information overload?</title>
    <link href="Swy7.github.io/2020/05/10/%E7%BF%BB/Can%20we%20escape%20from%20information%20overload/"/>
    <id>Swy7.github.io/2020/05/10/翻/Can we escape from information overload/</id>
    <published>2020-05-10T01:26:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-10T03:13:42.271Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We live in an age of infinite scrolling and endless interruptions. So what happens when you switch off the lights? Tom Lamont finds out </p><a id="more"></a><p>One day in December 2016 a 37-year-old British artist named Sam Winston equipped himself with a step-ladder, a pair of scissors, several rolls of black-out cloth and a huge supply of duct tape, and set about a project he had been considering for some time. Slight and bearded, with large grey-blue eyes, Winston had moved to London from Devon in the late 1990s. He supported himself through his 20s and 30s by teaching, doing illustrations for magazines and selling larger, freer-form artworks, many of them pencil-drawn, to collectors and museums. He had just collaborated on a children’s book with author Oliver Jeffers, and done his part to propel “Child of Books” up the bestseller lists. Grateful as he was for commercial success, Winston found he disliked corporate publishing. All the emails! He saw himself as a lead-smudged idealist, an artist-hermit at heart. He’d been troubled by nervous energy and stress since he was young, was an intermittent insomniac, had difficulty filtering noise and distractions in public spaces, and was someone who – like so many of us – increasingly relied on his phone and computer. So Winston decided to hole up for a few days. No screens. No sun. No visual stimulation of any kind. He was going to spend some time alone in the dark.</p><p>It took him hours, climbing up and down the ladder in his studio, to cover every last aperture and pinprick of inbound light. The studio, in a converted factory in east London, has large tenement windows and a sloped roof inlaid with skylights that were especially tricky to seal. By Winston’s conservative estimate he used 200 metres of duct tape before he was fully satisfied that here, at last, was darkness. He would sit in it, drawing with pencil and paper, doing yoga, snacking a bit, waiting to see if the dark had any sort of palliative effect.</p><p>The world in the 21st century is no more richly textured or exotic to touch than it used to be. It smells about the same and there are no new flavours. Not since the coming of factories, then aeroplanes, domestic appliances and motorways has there been a serious uptick in sound pollution. Yet the spill of information and distraction that comes at us by eye has grown and grown ceaselessly for two decades, without any sign of a halt or plateau. DM! Breaking-news! Inbox (1)! This is a time of the scrolling, bottomless visual, when bus stops and the curved walls of Tube platforms play video adverts and grandma’s face swims onto a smartphone to say hi. People watch Oscar-nominated movies while standing in queues, their devices held at waist height. A Netflix executive can quip, semi-seriously, that he covets the hours we sleep (hours in which we do not, currently, stream Netflix shows). Apple has put an extra screen on our wrists and Google retains quiet hope that we will eventually wear a screen inside our specs. Big news lands in 140 characters or less, ideally with a startling picture or piece of video, else it doesn’t register as big news.</p><p>Our brains tend to lean on the visual, heavily prioritising sight over the other four senses. Ever since we climbed on to two feet as a species, taking our noses farther from the aroma-rich savannah floor, we have been wired to be seeing creatures and for better or worse we usually experience the what’s-next-what’s-next of this world through our peepers. As an artist, Sam Winston was often on the lookout for topsy-turvy projects – weird, sidelong ways to unmoor familiar habits or nudge his work in new directions. He wanted to know what would happen, to him and to his work, if he hid away from the ocular blitz for a while.</p><p>Now, working and sleeping in his blacked-out studio, he began to notice new things. Without sunlight as a guide, the day’s rhythms came via aural clues he had been only dimly aware of before: the cessation of London’s air traffic overnight, or the sound of idling vehicles as they took fractionally longer to move off from traffic lights during rush hour. When he brewed cups of rooibos in a rote-remembered action at his tea station he noticed that he could hear the difference between hot and cold liquids as he poured them. He began to see, he later told me, “how intelligent our senses are. And how we just drown them in the tsunami.”</p><p>Winston found that he was productive in the dark, too, drawing until his pencils were nubs and creating a series of huge sketches – broad-stroked in places or crowded with overlapping sentences in his crabby handwriting – that would later become part of an exhibition at the Southbank Centre in London. Between drawing jags he had vivid daydreams, even hallucinations, “as if my brain was a digital radio left on search, constantly searching for an available channel”.</p><p>Winston’s older brother had died, suddenly, the year before, and bereavement was another prompt for him to hole away in the dark. He had expected to use his time under seal to have profound thoughts about love and loss, to feel gratitude towards his girlfriend, a fellow artist, and his parents back in Devon. Instead a very different figure stalked the darkened landscape of Winston’s mind – one who was suited, lardy and omnipresent in the news after his recent election as president of the United States. Winston considered himself only a moderate news junkie, bombarded but not an addict. Yet here was Donald Trump, cavorting around his studio. It was as if, Winston felt, the news was something he’d over-indulged in, even overdosed on, a damaging substance that only now, in cold-turkey conditions, could swirl up out of him and be evacuated.</p><p>Winston emerged from the blacked-out studio before his food stocks ran out, around lunchtime on a Saturday. He’d been in there for six or seven days. The sun hurt his eyes. For a long time Winston watched train after train go by on the tracks outside his studio, relishing the everyday sights he’d been starved of, and at the same time trying to settle his insides. What he presumed to be a sudden dump of daylight-induced hormones made him feel faint. The next time he retreated into the dark, Winston resolved, he would try to come out after sunset for a gentler transition. Intrigued by the experiment, and suspecting there were greater depths he could go to, he had already decided there would be a next time.</p><p>Through 2017 and 2018 he made plans. He Googled bits and pieces of research. A pioneering experiment on sensory deprivation had been done at the University of Manitoba in Canada in the 1950s, during which hundreds of people were asked to remain alone in a sealed dark room for as long as they could bear. About a third of the subjects quit within days. At most they were in there a fortnight. If he went into the dark again, Winston wondered, could he manage a month? He Googled some more, and went shopping online, ordering more black-out cloth, more duct tape.</p><p>Information overload was a term coined in the mid-1960s by Bertram Gross, an American social scientist. In 1970 a writer called Alvin Toffler, who was known at the time as a dependable futurist – someone who prognosticated for a living – popularised the idea of information overload as part of a set of bleak predictions about eventual human dependence on technology. (Good call, Alvin.) Information overload can occur in man or machine, wrote another set of academics in a 1977 study, “when the amount of input to a system exceeds its processing capacity”. Then came VHS, home computers, the internet, mobile phones, mobile-phones-with-the-internet – and waves of anxiety that we might be reaching the limits of our capacity.</p><p>A study in 2011 found that on a typical day Americans were taking in five times as much information as they had done 25 years earlier – and this was before most people had bought smartphones. In 2019 a study by academics in Germany, Ireland and Denmark identified that humans’ attention span is shrinking, probably because of digital intrusion, but was manifesting itself both “online and offline”.</p><p>By that time an organisation called the Information Overload Research Group had done a study which estimated that hundreds of billions of dollars were being shucked away from the American economy every year, in miscellaneous productivity costs, by an overload of data. The group had been co-founded in 2007 by a computer engineer-turned-consultant, Nathan Zeldes, who had once been asked by Intel, a computer-chip maker, to reduce the burden of email imposed on its workers. By the end of 2019 Zeldes was ready to sound a note of defeat. “I’d love to give you a magic potion that would restore your attention span to that of your grandparents,” he wrote in a blog, “but I can’t. After over a decade of smartphone use and social media, the harm is probably irreversible.” He advised people to take up a hobby.</p><p>In an age of overload it can feel as though technology has rather chanced its luck. Pushed too much, too far, bone-deep. Even before coronavirus spread across the world, parts of the culture had started to tack towards isolation and deprivation as desirable lifestyle signifiers, hot-this-year, as if some time spent alone and without a device was the new season’s outfit, the next Cronut, another twerk.</p><p>Before a pandemic limited the appeal of wallowing in someone else’s tepid water, flotation-tank centres were opening all over London. In the Czech Republic there are spas that sell clients a week in the dark in shuttered, serviced suites. “Social distancing is underrated,” Edward Snowden tweeted, deadpan, in March 2020: a corona-joke, but one that will have spoken to the tech bros of Silicon Valley, for whom retreats were the treat of choice.</p><p>Recently, I saw that a person called Celine in San Francisco had tweeted to her 2,500-odd followers about the difficulty of “trying to date SF guys in between their week-long meditation retreats, Tahoe weekends, month-long remote work sessions…” About 4,000 people tapped to endorse the sentiment, launching Celine onto an exponential number of strangers’ screens, including my own. The default sound for any new tweet is a whistle, somewhere between a neighbourly “yoo-hoo” and a dog-walker’s call to heel.</p><p>Hilda Burke, a British psychotherapist who has written about smartphone addiction, told me that part of the problem in this age of overload is the yoo-hooing insistence with which each new parcel of information seeks our attention. Speakers chime. Pixelated columns shuffle urgently or icons bounce, as if to signal that here is the fire. Our twitch response to urgency is triggered, in bad faith.</p><p>When Celine’s tweet whistled onto my phone one idle Friday I couldn’t understand why I found it mildly stressful to read. Was it that it made me feel old? That I already had enough to think about? Eventually I realised that, for me, every tweet is a bit stressful. Every trifling, whistling update that comes at us, Burke said, “is like a sheep dressed in wolf’s clothing. The body springs to attention, ready to run or fight, and for nothing that’s worth it. This is confusing.”</p><p>In Sam Winston’s case the epiphany moment came when he realised just how much he was enjoying his hangovers after a night out. He lolled on the sofa. He didn’t feel “targeted by Twitter, Instagram, Facebook, all these services with algorithms that are intentionally designed to be as sexy and juicy and distracting as possible, to fire my synapses as often as they could. What’s that truism? ‘Protect me from what I want.’” He realised that he had a weird urge to be on something like a cruise ship for a month: “To experience a clear stop to it.”</p><p>During the summer of 2018 Winston worked to secure a location for his planned month in the dark. An acquaintance agreed to lend him a one-room guesthouse in the Lake District, asking only that, once the property had been thoroughly blacked-out with cloth and tape, Winston sign a waiver taking the blame for any catastrophe. He bought cupboard stores, frozen pies, an apocalypse-supply of bottled water. He arranged for a group of trusted people to call in by phone and make the occasional visit to check that, as one friend put it, “he wasn’t going full Norman Bates in there”.</p><p>Winston decided on a few more ground rules. He would do four weeks, going in on Monday at the start of October and coming out on a Sunday at the end. This would amount to 672 hours in seclusion. He would take voice notes on a Dictaphone and record less literal impressions in a series of pencil drawings.</p><p>In keeping with the maverick spirit of the effort he did not look deeply into the health risks. He did a bit of reading about melatonin and serotonin, hormones that are produced in the brain by the pea-sized pineal gland and which help the body to regulate its sleep-wake cycle. Winston figured he’d end up rather starved of serotonin, which is usually secreted during daylight hours and helps us to feel alert, but that he’d get an absolute bonanza of melatonin, a soporific. He didn’t consult a doctor, though he did quiz a Specsavers employee during a routine appointment. She said she didn’t know what to tell him.</p><p>Winston couldn’t resist a final tweet before he locked himself away: “No reception. No screen time. Drawing in darkness. See you in Nov.” On the last day of September he took a sunset walk in the fields surrounding the property, staring at hills and cows and in general trying to enjoy this last conventional use of his eyeballs. Then he went indoors and went to bed, killing the lights for the next 28 days.</p><p>He could handle the pitch-black mornings, having tried a shorter version of this experiment before. So when Winston awoke and got over the momentary panic – that, no, he had not lost his vision overnight – it was easy and agreeable to drift back into a dark-drugged second sleep. When he did get out of bed, feeling his way to the kitchenette and the fridge, breakfast took longer than usual to prepare and consume. All this contributed to a certain time-slippage. Even in those first few days he imagined he was up and under way on some morning activity, drawing at his work table, or doing yoga stretches on the carpet, only to receive a check-in call from his girlfriend, who let him know he was a few hours behind. Without a precise sense of time he surrendered again to the vaguer, lulling rhythms of something-like-morning, something-like-afternoon, something-like-evening, something-like-night.</p><p>It was quieter in the country guesthouse than it had been in the city studio. Winston’s ears had to tune in to more distant aural clues. Before long he realised he could tell the difference between day and night from the density of traffic noise on an A-road half a mile away. He went through other transitional stages he had experienced before, such as that weird prominence of news and current events as his psyche cleared its titbits and cookies, “the accumulated songs, the little thought eddies, a kaleidoscope of stuff”, as Winston remarked in a Dictaphone note on day five. A day later he recorded another note: “I’ve discovered it doesn’t matter which way you walk in the dark, forward or backwards, it makes no difference. Either way you can’t see anything. Quite good, walking backwards.”</p><p>With his vision suppressed, his other four senses were getting a chance to step up and show their stuff. It has long been accepted that people who can’t see may experience other sensory gains. With advancements in brain-scanning technology in the 1990s and 2000s, academics began to test our anecdotal understanding with empirical research. Their findings suggested that non-visual sensory enhancement happens quickly in the dark. Even 30 or 45 minutes after the lights plink off, our fingertips thrill with greater responsiveness and we seem to become markedly better at determining the direction of travel of sound. Research in this area is ongoing, and it excites scientists who specialise in the senses because it suggests the brain is more adaptable – more “plastic” in their terminology – than was previously thought.</p><p>Charles Spence of Oxford University’s department of experimental psychology talks about brain plasticity as if he’s a property magnate. “When the body is plunged into darkness”, he told me, “this huge visual part of the brain is no longer doing the stuff it normally does. That’s a lot of spare real estate and what you find is that, surprisingly quickly, the real estate is retooled or repurposed.” The other senses simply take it over. That the non-visual senses should commandeer brain space so quickly – within an hour, according to some studies – excites specialists such as Spence because it suggests that we are using latent connections instead of growing new ones, which would take longer to form. By turning off the lights, in other words, we aren’t necessarily enhancing the other senses, we’re just more inclined to heed what these other senses are already saying.</p><p>As he entered his second week in the dark, Winston spent ages running his fingers over common objects, the edges of things, surfaces, entertained and distracted by the minute textural details he could discern. He had been drawing in the dark. Now, whenever he picked up a pencil, he was sure he could intuit the density of a pencil’s lead from its vibrations on paper as well as “the acoustics of it, its energy across the page”. Certain tactile experiences came with exciting visual impressions. Washing was especially thrilling – “showers were Alton Towers” – as every drop of water seemed to conjure a corresponding drop of colour in Winston’s mind. When his girlfriend called him from a London bus, he found that he relished the humdrum noises in the background, the sound of commuters, the beeps. “It was like having a whole tv mini-series to think about afterwards.”</p><p>The refining of his other senses led to compromises and frustrations too. Winston could no longer get to sleep on sheets that had been washed in supermarket detergent because he found the fragrance so strong it made him gag. Foods he’d always liked turned disagreeable, particularly processed ones. There was an unforgettable afternoon with a McCoy. Winston was convinced he could now track the progress of the crisp’s saturated fat down his oesophagus. One day, troubled by indigestion, his brain conjured a frightening image of himself with a distended, bloated stomach. He started to eat less after that. Exercising, crying, masturbating less. As Winston prickled with a richer sort of sensory awareness, these basic physical activities wound down because he found them too dramatic, too weird, too much. He had come into the dark to escape, but this didn’t feel like much of one.</p><p>By the start of the third week, soggy with melatonin, Winston was spending more and more time on the sofa. He sunk in to memories. Daydreamed. Hallucinated. He saw landscapes drift past, mostly coastlines, shimmering seas. His hallucinations could be workaday and he found that his mind itched to redraw the guesthouse around him, plastered beige walls there, tiled kitchenette there…Then, after something as prosaic as that, he would see a cloud-filled sky. A star field.</p><p>If the bodily effects of the retreat were strange (psychedelic showers, the snake-like digestion of a crisp), then these were foothill experiences compared with the mental effects. In the aftermath Winston would have trouble putting the experiences into words and we would have long conversations trying to map where exactly he went in his head, trying to differentiate between day-time hallucinations and night-time dreams, sometimes falling back on the Dictaphone notes Winston had recorded in the dark.</p><p>He was amazed at the obscurity and reach of the memories that came to the fore, “these weird little air bubbles from the past that went ‘pop’.” As with Trump, the people who turned up to join him – sometimes hallucinated, sometimes felt only as spectral presences – were rarely those he expected. When he was 17, Winston had been a bit crap toward his first girlfriend. He hadn’t thought about her in decades and now she strode back in (hiya!) to join him in the black-out. It took Winston four or five days, wringing his hands, picking back through long-ago instances of infelicity, laziness, casual teenaged callousness, to retrieve a useful memory: she’d once written him a letter he hadn’t answered. “She was the first person who ever wrote to me and said, ‘I love you.’ And I turned around and said, ‘Whatevs, I’m over, doing this with somebody else.’ I missed it at the time, the intimacy and the tenderness of the moment. So there I am, 20 years later, in the dark – realising how incredibly selfish I’d been.”</p><p>The spectral girlfriend shimmered away. Afterwards, Winston found himself revisiting and replaying all kinds of bygone squabbles and misunderstandings. Pleasant moments too. He thought about his girlfriend a lot. He wondered why he had never asked her to marry him. He found he could wallow, a little more inquisitively, a little more sympathetically, in overwhelming emotional events that had rushed by at the time.</p><p>This was not always a good thing. Winston thought a lot about his brother, Ben, who had died. “Just fell over. He was 40. He had a wife and a young daughter. He was in the middle of his life. It wasn’t fucking fair.” When someone dies on you like that, Winston said, “there’s a rational bit of you that knows they’re dead. And there’s this irrational bit where you feel a bit like a bloodhound. You’re sniffing around going ‘Sorry, where have they gone?’” In the dark, with no morning or afternoon, the real and the imagined had vaguer edges and Winston started sniffing around more deliberately. “I had some experiences that were pretty far out to sea. A part of me thought, you know, ‘I’m gonna go and find Ben.’” This didn’t happen. There was no spiritual encounter, no satisfying reunion for Winston. Instead, during his scarier reveries on the guesthouse sofa, he started to doubt what he called “the binary here and not-here of death”. Winston even wondered once or twice if he’d died himself. He worried he might be going mad.</p><p>“When you turn off perception by going into darkness,” Charles Spence told me, “mental imagery has nothing to compete with. It becomes the most intense thing there is. Hence you start to see hallucinations, people confusing reality with their mental imagery, the mental image for the real.” A friend of Winston, Martin Aylward, who’d tried a week-long dark retreat himself, warned how noisy the experience could be. “Even if you spend a little time with yourself,” Aylward said, “you’ll notice how a voice chatters away in your head – the blah-blah-blah of the inner monologue. In the dark that can start to be extremely loud, extremely tiresome. And relentless.”</p><p>There had been moments, listening to Winston’s tales from the dark, that I wondered if we might all follow his lead and spend our own month under seal. In a fluorescent world, especially in these tense, locked-down times, mightn’t darkness be a sort of readily available cure-all? A potent, inexhaustible form of bedroom pharma?</p><p>Winston went into the dark for a month in a bid to escape the digital bell-chimes, the bouncing icons, the bulletins and info-blasts – our exhausting daily scroll. “But when you go into the dark for a long time,” Winston admitted to me, recently, “you’re not going into a void. You’re going into yourself. And good luck finding blissful empty quiet there.” There was nothing to compete with the loud, incessant inner monologue or drown it out. I wondered, then, whether we’d created and refined all our sparkly informational distractions because on some level we knew the relentlessness of the subconscious had the real power to overload.</p><p>By the start of the fourth week Winston had started to lose track of how much sleep he was getting. He was having dreams of such dazzling, 3D intensity that even months later it was hard for him to call them dreams. One morning towards the end, Winston woke up and recorded a raspy, panicked Dictaphone note: “Day 19… There was a bizarre little event. The Queen came to visit, and I was naked, and she was here already.” Around this time a friend drove to the guesthouse to look in on Winston. He answered the door in a blindfold, looking pale and gaunt. Talking slowly, maybe at two-thirds speed, he said he hadn’t been expecting anyone until the afternoon. “But it’s 5pm,” the friend said.</p><p>The real world, the one with garishly delineated mornings and afternoons, was creeping back to claim him. His girlfriend was due to arrive at the guesthouse a couple of days before the end, to help Winston adjust to human company again and ease the outward transition. He recorded a voice note: “So this is day, I think, 26? 27? She arrives in a couple of hours. Everything’s sped up. Everything’s got quite rush-y. Like, shit, I need to wipe down the surfaces or make the bed. None of it big. But it [still feels like] coming out of hyperspace.”</p><p>On day 28, just before dusk, his girlfriend helped him out of the guesthouse, leading him in a blindfold to the garden. Winston was gently hysterical, cackling and clapping, kneeling to touch the ground under his feet, stroking the bark of a tree and muttering, “Who made this?” When he gingerly removed his blindfold and used his sight for the first time in 672 hours he had to bow his head against the minimal glare. He stared at the horizon for a long time, and later explained what was going through his head: “the whole system rebooting…Like you’re being born, but this time with an adult head on…I remember I felt really innocent. Like those astronauts who look back on Earth and wonder how a war could ever happen, how we could all get so confused. [There was] a sense of the impending loss of that. I knew that before long I’d be back on the Central line, thinking that some stranger was an idiot for standing in the wrong place in the carriage.”</p><p>Before he lost that thinning sense of innocence, Winston wanted to capitalise on his experience. He dragged his girlfriend off on a walk and proposed to her. She said yes. Over the month away he’d lost weight and his pallid, almost puce-coloured skin had turned a raw burnished pink in the outdoor breeze. As long as she’d known Winston his eyes had been an unremarkable blue-grey. Now, when he removed his blindfold, she gasped. She rushed to take a picture. His eyes, after 28 days without anything to feast on, had turned a vivid baby blue.</p><p>Shortly afterwards, Winston put the quirky photograph of his brightened eyes on Twitter, for his followers to see. He logged in, uploaded the JPEG, appended a pert little message and pressed send, digital chores that signalled as surely as anything that he was back in the world.</p><p>One afternoon in January this year I met Winston by Regent’s Canal in east London. He had just taught an art class nearby and was due back at his studio, where admin awaited him. More than a year had passed since the end of his monkish retreat and his eyes had returned to their regular blue-grey. Winston was carrying a large satchel, over-stuffed with cardboard tubes and when I asked what was in them he said it was his students’ work. That afternoon he had led a class in which he encouraged them to put on blindfolds to draw.</p><p>He had become an advocate for making art in the dark. Winston’s retreat had left him with conflicting feelings, but he was convinced of one thing: that a blast of darkness, taken in moderation, was a powerful creative tool. The boiled-down pitch he’d been making to other artists was that by depriving yourself of visual stimulus, the mind had to leave its comfortable grooves. Originality resulted. He was pleased with the large swirling pencil drawings that he’d made in the dark and had plans to exhibit them at the Barbican in London and the National Centre for Writing in Norwich. Winston had commissioned poets and novelists to undertake dark retreats, and been satisfied to hear from them that the freeing effects of dark-working carried over into other forms of creativity.</p><p>On his computer there were tons of emails that needed answering about the dual shows. Inbox (200), Inbox (300). One of the most time-consuming tasks, Winston admitted, had been his efforts to persuade curators in London and Norwich to construct enclosed black-out spaces, so that visitors could try immersion in the dark themselves. An hour or two at most, Winston suggested. Not 672.</p><p>He said he wouldn’t recommend what he’d done to any-one. A year on, Winston had finally found his bearings again but it took him months, maybe six, to get his equilibrium back. For a long time he couldn’t stop noticing every little inbound impression. In a city as loud and smelly as London that was too much to tolerate. After the retreat he often felt glum, almost bereaved, because, for all its terrors, the dark could be addictive. He pined for another immersion. This disturbed him.</p><p>Back at the studio we met his girlfriend. As usual, to record our conversations, I laid my iPhone on the table, beside a fail-safe iPad. Behind us, the studio computer flicked to a screensaver, hiding email software that teemed with to-dos. Unwilling to face these, Winston fooled about with a cardboard tube instead, using it as a loud hailer to pester his girlfriend. “Why haven’t we got married yet?” he boomed.</p><p>She smiled and said: “I don’t know,” throwing Winston an ambiguous look that I took to mean, “Because you’re the kind of person who might vanish on a black-out jag at any moment.” Winston sighed. Things had seemed simpler with the lights off. “I wanted to know, ‘How did we all get so confused?’ Because I couldn’t see the confusion. Now I can’t see the simplicity.”</p><p>He sat at the computer. Typed a bit. He was restless. Did I want to try it, Winston asked, the dark? The sun was setting outside the tenement windows. We could sneak in a couple of hours before I had to go home, he reckoned. Excited as a boy getting out his stickers, Winston grabbed two blindfolds from a hook and started shoving furniture to the walls. His girlfriend excused herself. I agreed to try and do some writing while Winston meditated and snoozed on the sofa nearby. The poet George Szirtes had been so uneasy about the coming dark, Winston recalled, that he needed his hand held. Don Paterson, another poet, had admitted that what truly terrified him was the prospect of his own uninterrupted company. “I’ll just be over here,” Winston said to me. There was a click and the lights went off.</p><p>From the sound of the sofa’s miniature rustlings, I tried to visualise the positions Winston shifted through. Then I listened to the creaks of the building’s heating system and the more distant trains. Taking up a pencil I started to make the scratchy beginnings on this story (what would eventually become paragraph three). After half an hour, surely no more, I heard Winston stir. He removed his blindfold and checked the time. Two hours had passed. With some reluctance, I pulled myself out of a middle-place of pale colours, crisp sound and slower, sedate thought. I said goodbye to Winston and headed for the nearby station. An electronic message board above the platform said the next train was 15 minutes away: unacceptable. I texted home to complain about this. The board rotated through station names, security warnings, bromides about respectful travel. A man beside me watched the new Scorsese on his upturned phone.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;We live in an age of infinite scrolling and endless interruptions. So what happens when you switch off the lights? Tom Lamont finds out &lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="翻" scheme="Swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%BF%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="短篇" scheme="Swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%9F%AD%E7%AF%87/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Why J. M. Barrie Created Peter Pan</title>
    <link href="Swy7.github.io/2020/05/10/%E7%BF%BB/Why%20J.%20M.%20Barrie%20Created%20Peter%20Pan%20-%20%E5%89%AF%E6%9C%AC/"/>
    <id>Swy7.github.io/2020/05/10/翻/Why J. M. Barrie Created Peter Pan - 副本/</id>
    <published>2020-05-10T01:25:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-10T03:14:46.946Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Almost a hundred years ago, at half past eight on the evening of December 27, 1904, the curtain went up at the Duke of York’s Theatre, in London, to reveal, among other things, a man dressed as a dog. The man was an actor named Arthur Lupino, suffering for his art in a shaggy costume, and the dog was called Nana. Most plays enjoy a fitful life, at best, but we can be fairly sure that this winter grown men will once again drop on all fours and work up a canine sweat, while grown women will crop their hair, pull on green tights, and turn into temporary boys. The play is “Peter Pan,” and, like its eponymous hero, it gives freakishly little sign of growing old.</p><a id="more"></a><p>The author was J. M. Barrie: Jimmy to some of his friends, and, in his later pomp, Sir James. He was short and slight, with bags under his eyes and a pale, protuberant brow, like a clever schoolboy who has stayed up late reading books under the bedclothes. He had a heavy mustache and a pipe smoker’s percussive cough. Of humble origins, he grew rich, yet his choice of overcoat remained several sizes too large, as if he were wearing a father’s hand-me-down. Both in face and in body—and, it became apparent, in the lineaments of his soul—Barrie seemed ill-suited to adult life, and those neat, child-friendly features sank all too readily into the caved-in sadness of old age.</p><p>Up to his death, in 1937, Barrie, as a result of his novels and plays, was one of the most famous men of his day; when Chaplin, on a trip to London in 1921, was asked whom he most wanted to meet, the answer was J. M. Barrie. Not even Barrie’s ardent admirers, however, would have described him as a matinée idol, and he would have been wryly flattered to find himself reincarnated, for the centenary of “Peter Pan,” in the beauteous person of Johnny Depp. A new film, entitled “Finding Neverland,” tells the story—or a decorated version of the story—of J. M. Barrie and the circumstances under which Peter Pan leaped into existence. Depp resembles Barrie in no way, except in his slenderness of form. We get a passable, soft stab at a Scottish burr but no mustache; we see more of the sweet side of Barrie than the insidious flip side; and the harshest coughing in the film comes not from Depp but from Kate Winslet, who plays Barrie’s friend Sylvia Llewellyn Davies.</p><p>Sylvia was one of a number of strong, rather Shakespearean female figures who ringed the life of Barrie—a dominance that began, unsurprisingly, with his mother. She was Margaret Ogilvy, a stonemason’s daughter who hailed from a particularly hard outcrop of the Presbyterian Church. James was born in 1860, the son of Margaret and a weaver named Alexander Barrie, in the Scottish town of Kirriemuir, and, until the age of six, he played in the shadow of his gifted and handsome older brother, David. Then, in the winter of 1867, David was killed; he was hit by a fellow ice-skater, fell, and cracked his skull. Margaret took to her bed under the onslaught of grief, and young James was dispatched to offer comfort:</p><blockquote><p>The room was dark, and when I heard the door shut and no sound come from the bed I was afraid, and I stood still. I suppose I was breathing hard, or perhaps I was crying, for after a time I heard a listless voice that had never been listless before say, “Is that you?” I think the tone hurt me, for I made no answer, and then the voice said more anxiously “Is that you?” again. I thought it was the dead boy she was speaking to, and I said in a little lonely voice, “No, it’s no’ him, it’s just me.” Then I heard a cry, and my mother turned in bed, and though it was dark I knew that she was holding out her arms.</p></blockquote><p>From here on, James worshipped his dead brother with a devotion that carried the taint of jealousy. Once, he even entered his mother’s presence wearing a suit of David’s clothes. The residue of the calamity, as it eventually seeped into Barrie’s art, was the conviction that a perfect child who dies on the eve of his fourteenth birthday will be spared the degradation of growing up, and that the death will be outshone by the thought of the perfection—so blindingly, perhaps, that the boy will seem scarcely to have passed away at all.</p><p>We think of Barrie as one of the chief explorers—or, in a gloomier light, invaders—of childhood. Yet the childhood that gripped him most tightly was not his own but that of other people; it is almost as if his own did not exist. The souls around him were like books, ripe for perusal, and he preferred their opening chapters. Hence “Margaret Ogilvy” (1896), which in part is a memoir of his mother’s youth. One of Barrie’s biographers, Denis Mackail, calls it “that distressingly human and inhuman book,” presumably because it demonstrates, even more than “Peter Pan,” the weird twinning of Barrie’s gifts—an almost telepathic self-spiriting into the emotions of others, and a professional shamelessness about baring them in public. Listen to his proud recital of Margaret Ogilvy’s deprivations: “She was eight when her mother’s death made her mistress of the house and mother to her little brother, and from that time she scrubbed and mended and baked and sewed.” At once we see that image skipping the generations, from mother to son, and from the son to the Wendy of “Peter Pan,” who was obliged, when she flew to Neverland and found a host of unclaimed children, to become a mother before her time.</p><p>The Barrie family—James was one of ten children, two of whom died in infancy—was ardently ambitious for its sons, the tool of that ambition was education, and Barrie duly studied at Dumfries Academy and at Edinburgh University. He emerged timid but industrious, and plowed a path into local and then national journalism. He moved to London, and, in 1887, produced his first novel, which bore the title “Better Dead.” Within a few years, thanks largely to some sharp, rosy fictions set in Scotland and to “The Little Minister,” a quaint tale of a minister who falls in love with a Gypsy, he had acquired not just a solid readership but a serious reputation; all of a sudden, we find him in correspondence with Thomas Hardy and Robert Louis Stevenson. He started writing for the theatre, kicking off with a parody of Ibsen, and indulging in the traditional sport of losing his heart to the leading ladies. His most acute biographer, Andrew Birkin—whose “J. M. Barrie and the Lost Boys” has been granted a timely reissue (Yale; $18.95)—digs up some astounding entries from Barrie’s private notebooks. Some are composed in the third person, as jottings toward a possible novel:</p><blockquote><p>—Greatest horror—dream I am married—wake up shrieking.<br>—Even while proposing, the thought of how it wd <em>read</em> go thro’ him.<br>—He never has contact with a woman—If he had this might have made him exult less in making women love him.</p></blockquote><p>In 1894, ignoring these self-cautions, Barrie married an actress named Mary Ansell, bestowing upon her, by way of a wedding present, a St. Bernard dog. The saga of Barrie is full of long-sufferers, the longest being Barrie himself, but nobody could follow its course and not spare a wealth of pity for Mary. Her husband loved many women, but the evidence suggests that the actual making of love lay outside his interests, or beyond his grasp. The creator of “Peter Pan” never had a child of his own. To us, the bewildering thing (and to Mary, surely the roughest insult) was that Barrie, far from burying his secret incapacities, dug them up like a pirate uncovering a treasure chest: “Grizel, I seem to be different from all other men; there seems to be some curse upon me… . You are the only woman I ever wanted to love, but apparently I can’t.” That comes from “Tommy and Grizel,” the tale of a devastated marriage which was published six years into Barrie’s own. At one point, the narrator says of Tommy, the fruitless husband, “He was a boy who could not grow up,” adding, of Grizel, “He gave her all his affection, but his passion, like an outlaw, had ever to hunt alone.” So where did the distinguished author like to hunt?</p><p>The answer is specific: Kensington Gardens, the broad, half-empty stretch of greenery next to Hyde Park. Here, in 1898, Barrie met a pair of boys, George and Jack Llewellyn Davies, aged five and four, who walked there with their nurse. They were amused by the small Scotsman with the enormous dog. Barrie talked with children, rather than at or down to them, and the meetings with George and Jack became drawn into the rhythm of their days. To our panicked eyes, such a relationship would be unthinkable—or, if thought about, nipped in the bud. We assume that a strange man, nearing forty, in a public place can offer only one thing to children still in knickerbockers, and that is harm. We would call the police, or, at least, call our children away. If we discovered the man to be a celebrity, we might call our lawyers, or, if we were feeling spiteful, the newspapers. And, if we were later to read what he wrote about our children, in an account so lightly ornamented as hardly to count as fiction, we might not be responsible for our actions:</p><blockquote><p>I returned to David, and asked him in a low voice whether he would give me a kiss. He shook his head about six times, and I was in despair. Then the smile came, and I knew that he was teasing me only. He now nodded his head about six times.<br>That was the prettiest of all his exploits.</p></blockquote><p>The tone of this, written in 1902, grates nastily on modern ears. Ever since “Lolita,” we have realized that one of the pleasures of the child-seeker is not merely to play games with the victim but to pretend that the victim is complicit in that game, or even pulling the strings; thus is the burden of guilt shifted smoothly away from the raptor. Did readers of 1902 feel nothing of the sort, or are we the guilty party, unable to conjure a time when playfulness was its own reward, rather than an alibi or a ruse? The passage comes from “The Little White Bird,” Barrie’s half-disguised novel about George Llewellyn Davies. In the book, George becomes David—note the name of Barrie’s dead brother—and is befriended by the bachelor narrator, who pretends to have a son of his own. This son, he then declares, has died (somewhere around here, the sheer weirdness of Barrie starts to multiply out of control), and he uses the nonexistent death to ingratiate himself further with David’s parents. He is especially pleased that David’s mother, Mary—note the name of Barrie’s wife—is “culpably obtuse to my sinister design,” the design being “to burrow under Mary’s influence with the boy, expose her to him in all his vagaries, take him utterly from her and make him mine.” Ladies and gentlemen of the jury, you may retire to consider your verdict.</p><p>Yet the stubborn fact remains: J. M. Barrie was innocent. He no more sought sex from children than he did from women. Andrew Birkin, who knows more about Barrie than anybody else (the last Llewellyn Davies boy, Nico, having died in 1980), has arrived at the balanced conclusion that the author of “Peter Pan” was “a lover of childhood, but was not in any sexual sense the paedophile that some claim him to have been.” His sinister design, it turns out, was not to corrupt boys with the murk of adult desire but to slough off any corruptions of his own, rejoin the unadulterated—the very word shows up the impurities in grownup life—and shrink once more, as best he could, into boyhood. This plan of Barrie’s may have been creepy and pathetic, but it was not a crime, and, as weaknesses go, it may be the most widespread in the world, haunting every harassed male who lies awake and tells himself how much simpler everything was as a kid.</p><p>At the heart of “The Little White Bird” is a story that the narrator slowly invents not only for David’s entertainment but with David’s help. It is about a boy named Peter Pan, who lives in Kensington Gardens. The first name is a direct allusion to the fact that George Llewellyn Davies now had another brother, Peter, born in 1897. There would be two more: Michael, born in 1900, and Nicholas (or Nico), born in 1903; a sisterless five in all, rather than the four of “Finding Neverland.” The film also opts for Peter Llewellyn Davies as the focus of Barrie’s attention—a not unnatural choice, given his name, but the wrong one, for it was really the whole gang of them whom Barrie loved. If he had a favorite, it was Michael, but, as the notorious preface to “Peter Pan”—dedicated “To the Five”—explains, “I always knew that I made Peter by rubbing the five of you violently together, as savages with two sticks produce a flame…. That is all he is, the spark I got from you.”</p><p>The course of the flame is a tricky one to trace, and what matters is that in Peter Pan Barrie achieved the rarest alchemy of all, the one that no writer can plan or predict: he invented a myth. The idea of Peter seems to have been flying around forever, a constant of humanity, and all that Barrie had to do was reach up and pluck the boy out of the air. After his first appearance, in “The Little White Bird,” Peter outgrew the nest; the passages about him were revised and republished, with illustrations of delicate grotesquerie by Arthur Rackham, under the title “Peter Pan in Kensington Gardens,” in 1906. In the meantime, the play, after its London début, was triumphantly staged in New York in the winter of 1905. The novel we now think of as “Peter Pan” is actually called “Peter and Wendy,” and it first saw the light in 1911. It is worth emphasizing that much of this material is close to unreadable—sometimes because it is sappy with sentiment but mostly because it is just too gnarled and knotted for current taste (increasing one’s reverence for Rackham, who saw its warpings at once), let alone for that of our children. What on earth will they make, for instance, of the opening pages of the novel, in which Mr. and Mrs. Darling, Wendy’s parents, are seen deciding whether they can afford to have more babies—literally adding up the doctors’ fees for the infant diseases (“measles one five, German measles half a guinea”) that they will be called upon to nurse?</p><p>Barrie would remonstrate severely on this point. He would claim that children cleave naturally to the misshapen and the morbid; like Roald Dahl, he admired the heartlessness and cunning of the young far more than he did their good behavior, and, for every mention of skipping fairies in “Peter Pan,” there will be some dashed-off sketch of alarming and sanguinary malice. Look between the cracks of the play, in the stage directions, and you will find his prose hardening and cooling into casual sadism, as in this line about Tootles, one of the pirate boys in Neverland:</p><blockquote><p>He has been in fewer adventures than any of them because the big things constantly happen while he has stepped round the corner; he will go off, for instance, in some quiet hour to gather firewood, and then when he returns the others will be sweeping up the blood.</p></blockquote><p>The most unfeeling child of all, needless to say, is Peter Pan himself. He flits through the play and the novels, and he has flitted through a century of stage productions and movies, and one result of those flittings is that we regard him as airy and innocuous. In truth, he is mean and green, a mini-monster of capering egotism; could there be any more dazzling proof of self-regard than a boy who first shows up in pursuit of his own shadow? In the early versions of the play, there is no Captain Hook, because there is no need for him; Peter supplies all the cruelty that is required. As “Peter Pan in Kensington Gardens” makes clear, our hero escaped from his parents as a baby and, after much prevarication, decided to forsake them for the unwithering plea-sure gardens of Kensington. He would fly back like a bird to watch his sleeping mother, but, once the decision was made, his way was barred—“When we reach the window it is Lock-out Time. The iron bars are up for life.” Such is Peter’s tragedy, but only because it was also his choice, and we should recall the terrifying title that Barrie appended to an early draft of the story: “The Boy Who Hated Mothers.”</p><p>And what of the real mother? Sylvia Llewellyn Davies first met Barrie at a dinner party in 1897; as the evening progressed, she realized that he was the man who wiggled his eyebrows at her children in the park. This revelation seems to have charmed rather than offended her; Barrie and she would be intimate friends for the rest of her life. Kate Winslet, who plays Sylvia in “Finding Neverland,” is ideal for the role, because she radiates that peculiar ease which starts to appear in photographs toward the end of the nineteenth century—no longer prim and straitened but open-faced, trusting, educated, and not without flickers of fire. In short, Sylvia (the daughter of a fast-witted literary clan, the du Mauriers) was altogether more modern than her husband, Arthur—scholar, lawyer, and stiff. Yet he, too, adored his boys, and it may be unfair of “Finding Neverland” to elide him, for streamlining purposes, from the scene; by the time that Johnny Depp meets Kate Winslet, she is already a widow, whereas Arthur was very much alive when Barrie first entered the consciousness—and, little by little, the home—of the Llewellyn Davies family. Soon, he was staying for tea, and then to wish the boys good night, and before long the Llewellyn Davieses were invited down to the Barries’ house in the country for idyllic vacations. He began as Mr. Barrie the author, and grew into Uncle Jim. It was all too much for Barrie’s wife, who, in the end, sought understandable consolation in the arms of another man; Barrie, in turn, sought a divorce, which was granted in 1909.</p><p>“Finding Neverland” is a weepie, and some viewers will mock it on that score, but it needs to be defended. First, because these days a good weepie is hard to find. And, second, because there is so much to weep about—far more, in fact, than you would gather from the film, which closes decorously after the death of Sylvia. (If you want a more accurate and leisurely testament, you could go online and order the DVD of “J. M. Barrie and the Lost Boys”—a wonderful TV drama, written by Andrew Birkin and running to four and a half hours, that the BBC produced in 1978, with Ian Holm providing the definitive Barrie.) From the moment that Barrie met George and Jack, and started to ponder the means by which they might be rendered immortal, the story becomes a dismal catalogue of mortality:</p><p>1907—Arthur Llewellyn Davies dies from cancer of the jaw.</p><p>1910—Sylvia dies of lung cancer. The five boys are orphaned; Barrie is made their guardian.</p><p>1915—George is killed in the First World War, fighting with his regiment in Flanders.</p><p>1921—Michael, an undergraduate at Oxford, is drowned while swimming with a friend. The two bodies, when recovered, are found clinging together.</p><p>All of this was enough to wreck Barrie, or, at least, to throw intolerable shadows over the remainder of his life. Few of his works, aside from “Peter Pan” and his desert-island comedy of class conflict, “The Admirable Crichton,” are remembered now, yet in 1922 he was invested with the Order of Merit, the grandest of British honors. He died in 1937, and we should be thankful that he didn’t live to be a hundred, and so to witness the terrible final act. On April 5, 1960, Peter Llewellyn Davies, by then an esteemed publisher, threw himself under a subway train in London. We should not presume to read a mind in torment, but we may note in passing that, if he had lived another month, he would have reached the centenary of Barrie’s birth and thus, one imagines, a fresh flurry of interest in “Peter Pan”—“that terrible masterpiece,” in the words of Peter Llewellyn Davies. His numerous comments on the genesis of the work, as quoted in Janet Dunbar’s 1970 biography of Barrie, are judicious, amused, and apparently unperturbed. But the effect of “Peter Pan” was like that of those iron bars on the hero’s family home; it is a kind of prison drama played onstage as a slice of festive cheer, and it locked the Llewellyn Davies boys into the garden of pre-puberty as surely as Pan himself is locked out from his mother’s embrace.</p><p>Does that make Barrie the bringer of mischance, after all? Peter “is never touched by any one in the play,” a stage direction in “Peter Pan” reads, and Barrie never touched his young charges—as Peter Llewellyn Davies confirmed—with anything more than affection. Once Arthur and Sylvia had died, Barrie, in loco parentis, fulfilled his duties with diligence and pride. But the damage, unwitting as it was, had been done long before, not by Barrie the middle-aged man but by Barrie the successful author; in making the Five the tinder for Peter Pan, he treated them as ideal spirits made flesh, and no child should be freighted with such an embarrassing burden. Their innocence was imperilled from the moment that it became prime-quality material for his elaborate public fantasies, and there may never have been a more desperate or acquisitive dedication than the one at the start of “Peter Pan in Kensington Gardens”: “To Sylvia and Arthur Llewellyn Davies and their boys (my boys).”</p><p>Barrie was a wounded creature, from his earliest youth, and his probing of that wound is what makes “Peter Pan” so enduringly painful to read. Toward the end of the novel, an immutable Peter drops in to find the adult Wendy, now a mother herself, as if he were the ghost of David Barrie, still cold from that skating accident, alighting beside Margaret Ogilvy. The tensions are bald and excruciating:</p><blockquote><p>He was a little boy, and she was grown up. She huddled by the fire not daring to move, helpless and guilty, a big woman.<br>“Hullo, Wendy,” he said, not noticing any difference, for he was thinking chiefly of himself; and in the dim light her white dress might have been the nightgown in which he had seen her first.<br>“Hullo, Peter,” she replied faintly, squeezing herself as small as possible. Something inside of her was crying, “Woman, woman, let go of me.”</p></blockquote><p>Is this really the stuff of classic children’s fiction? Do people still read “Peter Pan,” or has Peter shrunk to a brand by now, a chirping Disney figure wrenched from the unsettling landscapes where he originally appeared? If so, he demands restitution, for he sprang from the mind of an oddball, and he is not alone. Consider Lewis Carroll, Edward Lear, and J. M. Barrie: the stammerer with the camera, the wandering epileptic, and the coughing frequenter of playgrounds. The great dreamers of English children’s literature were not, as it happens, dreamy types at all but exacting, even pedantic, in the dramatizing of their fathomless unhappiness. If their characters are pricked by a helpless urge to travel—down a rabbit hole, to sea in a sieve, second star to the right and straight on till morning—it is because there is always something, a drab existence or a dreadful past, that begs to be fled. Open a page of “Harry Potter,” by contrast, and you know that it was written by a clever, funny woman of sound mind, with a keen commercial eye and a Barrie-like love of the fizzing narratives for which children naturally thirst; but there is nothing smarting beneath, no ominous beat of the heartsick. Harry will grow up, and we think it only proper that he should; but will he continue to taunt and haunt us, a hundred years from now, like the boy who never did?</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Almost a hundred years ago, at half past eight on the evening of December 27, 1904, the curtain went up at the Duke of York’s Theatre, in London, to reveal, among other things, a man dressed as a dog. The man was an actor named Arthur Lupino, suffering for his art in a shaggy costume, and the dog was called Nana. Most plays enjoy a fitful life, at best, but we can be fairly sure that this winter grown men will once again drop on all fours and work up a canine sweat, while grown women will crop their hair, pull on green tights, and turn into temporary boys. The play is “Peter Pan,” and, like its eponymous hero, it gives freakishly little sign of growing old.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="翻" scheme="Swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%BF%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="短篇" scheme="Swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%9F%AD%E7%AF%87/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>生于教育（一）</title>
    <link href="Swy7.github.io/2019/12/27/%E7%BF%BB/%E7%94%9F%E4%BA%8E%E6%95%99%E8%82%B2%EF%BC%88%E4%B8%80%EF%BC%89/"/>
    <id>Swy7.github.io/2019/12/27/翻/生于教育（一）/</id>
    <published>2019-12-27T11:21:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-12-29T12:24:23.682Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>我印象最深的记忆并不真实。而是一些我想象出来的事，这使得往后记起时像是发生过一样。这种记忆在我五到六岁之间形成，来自于父亲说的一个详细的故事，其中伴随着枪声与喊叫声，我和我的兄弟姐妹每个人变成了自己的电影角色。当我和家人一起蜷缩在厨房，关掉灯，躲避着房屋周围联邦人员，矿井的蟋蟀声，是我能听到的。一个女人伸手去拿水，月光照亮她的轮廓。枪声如同鞭声，她应声而倒。在我的记忆里，这个女人是我的母亲，怀中还抱有孩子。</p><a id="more"></a><p>这个孩子怎么都说不通，我是七个孩子中最小的，就像我说的，其实这些都没有发生过。</p><p>父亲讲这个故事后的一年，晚上全家聚在一起听他朗读圣经中的一节，关于以马内利的预言。他坐在芥末色沙发上，腿上放着一本打开的圣经。母亲坐在他的旁边。剩下的我们零散的坐在棕色的地毯上。</p><p>“他将会得到奶油和蜂蜜”，在搬运一天后的疲惫中，父亲拖着低沉，单调的语气读着。“这使得他弃恶择善。”</p><p>一阵沉重的沉默。我们静静地坐在那里。</p><p>父亲并不高，但足以震慑这个家。他的周围有一种神谕的庄严气氛。他的手又糙又厚，这是一生艰苦工作人的手，这手正紧抓着《圣经》。</p><p>他大声读着这一章两遍，三遍，四遍。每一次的重复他的声音变得越高。他的眼睛刚刚还因疲劳而肿起来，现在却睁得大大的，机警起来了。这里有一个神圣的教义，他说。他会向主询问。</p><p>第二天早上，爸爸把冰箱里的牛奶、酸奶和奶酪都清理了。当天晚上，他回家的时候，卡车里装满了50加仑的蜂蜜。</p><p>当我的兄弟把白桶搬进了地下室时，爸爸笑着说，“圣经没有说黄油还是蜂蜜，哪个是邪恶的，你们若问，主必告诉你们。”</p><p>当父亲对奶奶念诗，她当着他的面笑了。“我钱包里有些硬币，”她说。“你最好拿去。他们将是你所有的感觉。</p><p>奶奶有一张瘦削、棱角分明的脸，她那细长的脖子和手指上挂着一簇簇数不尽的银饰和绿松石做的人造印度首饰。因为她住在我们的山下，靠近公路，所以我们叫她山下奶奶。为了把奶奶和外婆区别开来，我们称外婆为镇上奶奶，因为外婆住在往南15英里的这个县唯一的一个镇上，在这里只有一个红绿灯和一家杂货店。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;我印象最深的记忆并不真实。而是一些我想象出来的事，这使得往后记起时像是发生过一样。这种记忆在我五到六岁之间形成，来自于父亲说的一个详细的故事，其中伴随着枪声与喊叫声，我和我的兄弟姐妹每个人变成了自己的电影角色。当我和家人一起蜷缩在厨房，关掉灯，躲避着房屋周围联邦人员，矿井的蟋蟀声，是我能听到的。一个女人伸手去拿水，月光照亮她的轮廓。枪声如同鞭声，她应声而倒。在我的记忆里，这个女人是我的母亲，怀中还抱有孩子。&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="翻" scheme="Swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%BF%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="生于教育" scheme="Swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%94%9F%E4%BA%8E%E6%95%99%E8%82%B2/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>生于教育（序）</title>
    <link href="Swy7.github.io/2019/12/27/%E7%BF%BB/%E7%94%9F%E4%BA%8E%E6%95%99%E8%82%B2%EF%BC%88%E5%BA%8F%EF%BC%89/"/>
    <id>Swy7.github.io/2019/12/27/翻/生于教育（序）/</id>
    <published>2019-12-27T03:11:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-10T03:11:52.552Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>我正站在谷仓旁的废弃红色火车上。风声大作，吹乱我的头发，将凉意送进领口。山边的风更大些，像是山峰在呼吸。往下的山谷则安静平和。与此同时，我家的农场跳起舞来：随着每一阵风吹来，巨大的针叶树缓慢摇摆，灌木丛跟着颤栗、弯腰。在我身后，缓缓向上的山坡绵延到山脚下。如果我抬起头，便可看见黑暗形态的印第安公主.</p><a id="more"></a><p>山坡上长满了野生小麦。若把针叶树与灌木丛看作独奏者，那这麦田便是芭蕾舞团，每个麦秆随着其他部分爆发出一阵阵的运动，在大风吹着金色的麦穗下，百万个芭蕾舞者此起彼伏地弯下腰。麦田凹陷的形状只存在片刻，像是人们看到风一样。</p><p>转向我家山坡上的房子，我看到不同的运动，高大的影子在气流中僵硬移动。我的兄弟们醒了，在测天气。我想象母亲在火炉边正翻着麦麸煎饼。父亲弓着背站在后门，系着钢头靴，把长满老茧的手穿进焊接手套里。下面的高速公路上，校车不停地驶过。</p><p>我只有7岁，但我明白，让我家与众不同是“我们不去上学”这个事实，而不是其他的事。</p><p>我爸担心政府会强迫我们去学校，但事实上并不会，因为政府根本不知道我们。七个孩子中有四个没有出生证明。因为在家里出生并未见过医生与护士，我们没有医疗档案。因为从未踏入进教室，我们没有学校档案。当我9岁时，我将得到一份延期的出生证明，但在此时，根据爱达荷州和联邦政府的说法，我是不存在。</p><p>当然我是存在的。我从小就为可憎的日子作准备，看着太阳下山，看着月亮如染血般下落。夏天，我把桃子装进瓶，冬天，则作食物供应。当这个世界走向尽头，我家依在，不受任何影响。</p><p>我学习于山的韵律，这种韵律的变化不是基本规律，而是一种循环。太阳在每天的早晨中升起，划过山谷，在山峰的背后落下。冬天的雪在春季融化。我们的生活是一个循环，一天的循环，一季的循环。我相信我家是这永恒模式中的一部分，在某种意义，我们是永恒的。但永恒只属于这座山。</p><p>我父亲曾经讲过一个关于这个山峰的故事。她优美古老，是山的大教堂，山中还有其他更高，更壮观的山峰，但巴克的山峰是最精巧的。她的山脚盘延一公里，黑色的形体从地下隆起，上升成一个完美无缺的尖顶。在远处看，你可以看到一个女人的身体印在山上:她的腿由巨大的峡谷构成，她的头发是松树的浪花，在北部的山脊上呈扇形散开。她的姿势是威严的，一条腿大踏步有力地向前伸着。</p><p>我父亲叫她印第安公主。每年雪开始融化时，她都会面朝南出现，看着水牛返回山谷。他说，游牧的印第安人把她的出现，看作是春天到来的标志，预示着冰雪正在融化，冬天已经过去，是时候回家了。</p><p>所有我父亲的故事都是关于山和山谷，还有爱达荷州这块参差不齐的土地。他从未告诉我该怎么做，如果我离开这座山，越过海洋和大陆，在一个陌生的地方找到了自己，在这里我无法在地平线上看到印第安公主。他从未告诉过我，如何知道该什么时候回家。</p><p>**除了我妹妹奥黛丽，她小时候摔伤了一个胳膊和一条腿。她被带去打了石膏。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;我正站在谷仓旁的废弃红色火车上。风声大作，吹乱我的头发，将凉意送进领口。山边的风更大些，像是山峰在呼吸。往下的山谷则安静平和。与此同时，我家的农场跳起舞来：随着每一阵风吹来，巨大的针叶树缓慢摇摆，灌木丛跟着颤栗、弯腰。在我身后，缓缓向上的山坡绵延到山脚下。如果我抬起头，便可看见黑暗形态的印第安公主.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="翻" scheme="Swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%BF%BB/"/>
    
      <category term="生于教育" scheme="Swy7.github.io/tags/%E7%94%9F%E4%BA%8E%E6%95%99%E8%82%B2/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>信（一）</title>
    <link href="Swy7.github.io/2018/10/25/%E6%9D%82/%E4%BF%A1%EF%BC%88%E4%B8%80%EF%BC%89/"/>
    <id>Swy7.github.io/2018/10/25/杂/信（一）/</id>
    <published>2018-10-25T01:37:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-05-17T03:56:37.688Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>亲爱的：德洛丽丝 </p><p>春雨夹杂着寒风阵阵吹来，夜晚行人匆匆的走着，不知有没有人和我是慢吞吞踱步在享受这雨，吐气出来还是有白雾升起，春意中凉意更多一些，德洛丽丝，我无比思念你。</p><a id="more"></a><p>我像是静止在人流中，眼光四散，甚至幻想着从人群中揪你出来，握住你的手，一遍遍的用拇指扫过你的手背，你可曾看到我眼中的光，我想我是看到你的了，那跳动的明亮的光，一层又一层的去除我对世界的质疑。</p><p>在散着黄光的雨街中走着，从没想过与你的日子似乎也是这种颜色，清澈透亮，我俩像是在时间的漩涡中跳舞，一圈一圈不知疲惫的转着，这一刻让我产生摆脱的感觉，生活的负重感，随着离心力一阵阵的退散，像梦一般，这种强烈拥有你的感觉，你能感觉到就好了。</p><p>​                                                                        ——  杰克</p><p>亲爱的：布朗</p><p>这里就不用多余的客套了，你我算是老友，在这里想让你帮个忙。</p><p>我有个朋友杰克，你应该见过，人还不错，上次在地铁和你有一面之缘，如果忘记了也没事，他巴不得别人忘记他，甚至想消失在人群中，真是怪人一个你说呢。人群中就只有显眼和普通两类人，怎么能消失的掉，我虽然读的书少，但也知道现在的时代个体与社会已经分不开了，没人能光不溜秋的窜进热带雨林中活下来。至于个体与社会的复杂关系，我这榆木脑袋是无法搞懂的。现在对于人生的意义或上述的这类问题，我的观点是不要再去多花时间去探讨这些问题了，着手去做事才是最主要的，或许有些问题要学会远离，才会找到答案。对于这一点我倒是很喜欢《树上的男爵》中的故事。</p><p>有点跑偏了，还是和你说说这位从小就认识的玩伴，我俩关系很好，就像《怪胎与书呆》的三个geek的关系，我不找他麻烦，他也不找我麻烦，感觉真要向友谊地久天长这句话发展了，可最近我越来越不懂杰克了。</p><p>杰克太消沉了。</p><p>杰克并没有自杀的念想，也没有像《荒原狼》提到的精神上自杀。和我谈过几次，他形容自己就像“in the middle of nowhere”，而且还是近视。我觉得他很迷茫，鼓励过几次，让他去做些事情，可他总是没有耐心，都半途而废。周而复始，这把我气的，直接上硬的，我用严厉的言语讽刺他，希望能激起他的斗志，可他总说感觉自己陷入时间的轮回中，无处可走，这类有的没的，我觉的他真是“游”的太远了，怎么可能脚不着地就想生活，真是自暴自弃的家伙，太令我失望了。</p><p>我真很关心他，希望你能找时间和他谈谈。</p><p>​                                                                                                                                             ——  麻桑</p><p>亲爱的：麻桑</p><p>最近一直没有答应，是由于我和杰克交谈了一段时间，现在才提起笔回应你。</p><p>约杰克出来过几次，对我的感觉是，挺帅的小伙，人也不错，但总觉得身上缺点什么。《龙珠》！嗯？看来这家伙缺气，卡卡罗特我感受到这孩子的气太弱了，当然这也是一种生活的方式。这孩子从未和任何人说过自己的内心话，从小到大。可能看到了我强大的战斗力从而相信我，或是我来自于遥远的贝吉塔行星与我倾诉也无关紧要，事实就是他和我开口了。好了，不开玩笑了，反正我也不知怎么的，我和他就谈了很久。</p><p>他说他很苦闷，时常感到矛盾，不追求成功，却越来越孤独，有时候负面情绪膨胀到胸口，简直就想开启自毁程序，把一切都砸个稀巴烂。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;亲爱的：德洛丽丝 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;春雨夹杂着寒风阵阵吹来，夜晚行人匆匆的走着，不知有没有人和我是慢吞吞踱步在享受这雨，吐气出来还是有白雾升起，春意中凉意更多一些，德洛丽丝，我无比思念你。&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="杂" scheme="Swy7.github.io/tags/%E6%9D%82/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
